<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erik.craddock.org/categories/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erik.craddock.org/categories/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of being a Parent</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was seventeen my father confessed, “Hey, I’ve never done this before. We are practicing on you.”. I think every parent on earth feels that way. We really have no idea what we are doing. Most of us are dealing with issues as they come by the seat of our pants. Even worse, the rules keep changing. And it doesn’t really matter how much experience or how many kids you have. The biggest mistake a parent can make is to expect what worked with one child to work on another. Being a parent is just hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up is the process of gradually taking more responsibility of your life. A child’s job is to fight for control of their lives until eventually they pull away. It’s like a game of tug of war with the kid at one end and the parent at the other. Whoever has more rope has more control but It’s a big rope. If, as a parent, you let go too soon your kid will fall backwards on their ass. That doesn’t stop most of them from trying. Too much control too soon is overwhelming. But parents can’t hold on forever. No one just magically becomes an adult at eighteen. The parent should give in slowly until eventually they feel comfortable letting go completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids rarely figure this out until they are grown. It has been difficult to explain to my oldest why I do what I do. I talk to him about the future. I try to make him understand that what he does now has a big effect on what he can expect later. To him the future happens in the next month or so. He still mostly lives his life as it happens. I am the roadblock that he has to get around. He knows that if he gets all A’s in school then he can play video games during the week. He knows that if he doesn’t do his chores that I am likely to get upset and punish him. He is starting to understand that he can get what he wants by giving me what I want. For my part, I try to only get in the way enough so that it is hard for him to do anything especially stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My youngest, on the other hand, lives a lot of his life in the clouds. He creates fantasy worlds in his head that he uses to test out situations that either scare or excite him. He is a bit more cautious and usually prefers to be alone. I encourage him to become the hero of those fantasy worlds. I try to teach him to be brave. We make an effort to get him involved in group activities so that he can get comfortable being around other kids. My wife and I have learned that we have to be careful about how hard we push him. Too much pressure and he shuts down. He retreats into of his imagination and we have to work hard to get him back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of being a parent is to teach children how to be adults. That responsibility trumps everything else while they are growing up.  Every kid is different. What works for one probably won’t work for another. One may try to jerk that rope out of your hands at every turn. Another may be content to let you lead them around forever. Either way can lead to trouble. Eventually our children must grow up to be adults that are capable of caring for themselves and their families. Hell, we may eventually need them to take care of us too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Fort Worth Ever Cross Your Mind?</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2015/10/does-fort-worth-ever-cross-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2015/10/does-fort-worth-ever-cross-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;As I fly over DFW airport, I can see downtown Fort Worth in the distance. I have 13 years worth of memories there that are surprisingly happy considering how eager I was to leave. I guess it is hard to fully appreciate something while you are experiencing it. The tendency, at least for me, is to move forward. I have been in pursuit of some ambitious goal ever since I was a boy. It is virtually impossible to look back while you are going full steam ahead. But the older I get the more I find myself reminiscing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I think that ambition is one of the things that separate the young from the old. Young men have a drive to succeed, usually out of necessity, that their elders can’t match. Sorry ladies but I only feel qualified to stereotype men, so don’t be offended if I leave you out. As a young man, I would try to brute force life until it either worked out for me or broke. I either got the knowledge, the job, the girl or there was a restraining order.  Thankfully I’ve matured a little bit over the years. I learned to rely less on bravado and more on experience and intelligence. Ironically most of that experience wouldn’t have been possible without youthful bravado.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Sometimes it feels like tradition herds us into a common routine of school, job, marriage, kids, retirement etc. I can remember feeling trapped as if my life had been planned without my input or consent. Now I realize that it takes a certain amount of order for freedom to even be possible. If you bulldoze your way into getting the things you want, you end up breaking them. It took getting married and having a family before I could even begin to comprehend this. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;We moved to Fort Worth in 2001. I wanted a job as a software developer. There wasn’t much of a market for that sort of thing in Oklahoma City at the time. Truth be known, I just needed a change of scenery and Fort Worth was as far as Linda would go. We did all of the things that grown ups are supposed to do. I began a career, we had kids and bought a house. We also made every mistake in the book. In short, we both grew up. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;My focus has shifted. Instead of trying to find my place in society, I now think a lot more about putting my boys in the best situation so that they can find theirs.  I no longer feel the need to conquer the world the way I did when I was 25. I enjoy spending time with my wife. We like to watch our boys play sports. I am quite happy with my job. My primary goal now is to be the best father I can be, which does seem ambitious at times. I learned a lot in Fort Worth. We stayed there a lot longer than we ever intended. However, I don’t regret it and I miss all of the close friends I made. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;My plane is now flying directly over Jerry World. I am reminded of a 4th of July that we spent watching a fireworks show in an empty parking lot across the street. There was another family there who understood English about as much as we understood Spanish. Our intention had been to find a park. Instead, we spent the night sitting in the back of my truck watching the show with new friends. We never saw that family again and we always prepared for our 4th of July outings better after that. But as I look back, I remember that night fondly. I feel the same about Fort Worth. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Binger Hill</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/12/history-of-binger-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/12/history-of-binger-hill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was raised to respect my last name. I was taught to be proud of who we are and where we came from. When I was a kid, I thought that I was a member of a secret society. There was a strong sense of family. Being a part of it meant that you would never be alone. We loved each other and still do. I believed that if you shared my blood line then you were a step above. You got any benefit of the doubt. We treated each other like royalty. This honor did not come without demands. I definitely felt that I had a lot to live up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, as a child, everything began on Binger hill. As far as I was concerned life on earth began there with my grandpa Van and grandma Lucille. They were Adam and Eve and the hill was our Eden. I’ve since learned that our history is much older and more distinguished. We have had many proud moments as well as some we’d rather forget. We can trace our family to back before the revolutionary war. Although I can’t confirm it, we even appear to have an ancestor who lived in the original Jamestown colony. It’s not a secret that I am very proud of my family. I have so many great memories. Most of them happened up on that hill. I couldn’t possibly tell them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate family didn’t move to Binger until after Grandma passed in 1987. I was thirteen. Before that we lived in Anadarko which is only about 20 miles away. Even then, I spent nearly every weekend running around Binger hill like the rest of the mob of children. And it was a mob of children. There were children of every age. My grandparents had nearly a litter of kids, who in turn had some of their own. Several of my aunts, uncles and cousins have called Binger hill their home. It seems like there have always been kids playing on those five acres. My Uncle Joe and my father Larry were the first two back in 1963. They were 10 and 12 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a young man, Grandpa Van was a farmer. He farmed land around what is now Chickasha lake. This is where the old homestead was located. All of their children were born there except Larry and Joe. Until 1945, he had a sharecropping arrangement with the owner of that land. On that year he leased some land about half a mile away and planted. Unfortunately, multiple years of bad crops convinced grandpa that it was time to walk away. The banker was ready to loan him enough money to try again another year. Grandpa was wary of taking a loan and decided against it. Instead he went to work for a businessman in Anadarko, Dee Higgins. They mostly did roofing jobs. They kept themselves busy tarring the roofs of buildings all over Anadarko. It was hard work but so was farming. It paid the bills, that is until he got sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1955, Grandpa was diagnosed with emphysema. The doctors said it was from years of smoking cigarettes and pipe tobacco. Grandma wasn’t convinced. She thought the culprit was the asphalt they used in the roofing tar. He never stopped working but it became harder and harder for him to breath. The manual labor was tough. Finally his body was just unable to perform as it had before. Up until that point, Grandma’s job was primarily raising kids. An occupation in which she was very experienced. She had already raised nine to adulthood with two more still at home. Unfortunately, this work would not pay the bills. Grandma was a take the bull by the horns type of gal. Without much of an education and no marketable skills to speak of, she took any job she could. Grandpa didn’t like the idea but sometimes you do what you got to do. Grandma began working as a bartender at the Mint bar. She later managed the Rock Castle both in downtown Anadarko, Ok. Times were hard and they didn’t have many options. But if anyone could turn things around with pure will and determination it was Grandma Lucille.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take her long to realize that the only person that made any money at a bar was the owner. She decided to give herself a promotion. She rented a building in Ft Cobb across the street from the movie theater and started her own bar. Grandma was a quick study. She spent a lot of time learning the business of owning and operating a bar. By 1962 she was ready to make a few changes. She began looking for a new location. This time her establishment would not be in city limits. In town she could only stay open until midnight. She knew that many of her customers weren’t quite ready to go home that early. She began looking for places outside of town, but not too far. The five acres a mile west of Binger was perfect. Despite Grandpa’s misgivings she secured a loan and bought the place. There would be no more landlords. There would be no more rent. She was free to do things however she saw fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1962, Van, Lucille, Larry and Joe Craddock all moved into a tiny apartment in Binger, Ok. It was located directly behind what is now the Binger Drive-thru. It wasn’t much but it was a place to sleep while they began turning the old house, that already stood on Binger hill, into a drinking establishment. Grandma bought the bar table and stools, a refrigerator and other various items from a tavern that was shutting its doors in a neighboring county. She was definitely the visionary. Grandpa did his part but he was skeptical. He gutted the old house and began rebuilding walls in more suitable locations. However, he was still not thrilled with the idea of Grandma running a bar. One day she asked him what they should call the place. He responded, “Just call it the midget bar. It’s so small that’s about the only people who’ll fit.” So of course she did. The tiny sign above the front door read, The Midget Bar. The work continued. The bar table was placed in the middle of what is now a kitchen. Tables for patrons sat in the front room where a recliner, two couches and a television now call home. Eventually, it was time to open the doors on the business that would sustain the family for the next 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad and Uncle Joe were not allowed anywhere near the Midget Bar during business hours. They weren’t so lucky when the sign was turned to closed. They swept floors, cleaned tables and re-stocked refrigerators. They emptied the trash, crushed beer cans as well as various other tasks. Eventually they moved their beds from the small apartment to the back room of the bar. That was as close as they got. According to dad, it was too close. Every night they would fall asleep to the music on the jukebox. They both learned to hate that jukebox. The names Ferlin Husky, Jim Reeves, George Jones, Buck Owens, Conway Twitty and Faron Young induce winces even now from both of them. Oh and I can’t leave out Patsy Cline or Wanda Jackson. Their dislike of country music was an equal opportunity. I guess hearing the same songs over and over again will do that to a person. Thankfully, their beds wouldn’t remain in the Midget Bar storage room for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just so happened that a team of men were in town constructing buildings. They specialized in garages. My uncle Onis was planning on going into business as a mechanic. So they decided to build a shop across the way from the bar. They put up a small building with four walls and roof. Before it was completed, Uncle Onis had decided on a different course. At the invitation of my Uncle Lonnie, he went to work as a telephone cable splicer. It was a good decision, they made a name for themselves. After that, cable splicing became the family business. In later years just having the last name Craddock would get you hired all over the country, experience be damned. In the meantime, there was an unfinished building across the way. Waste not, want not. It wouldn’t sit there unused for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandpa went back to work putting up walls in suitable locations. While he was at it he added a bathroom and a kitchen sink along the back wall. Dad likes to tell a story emphasizing grandma’s skill at project management. It’s unclear whether she developed these skills during her years of running her own businesses or if she was just naturally gifted. But according to dad, Grandma liked to visit the construction site and make suggestions for how Grandpa might accomplish his work. He would take it in stride and mostly answer with “yes dear” and such. Yes, he would move the plumbing for the sink over another foot. Yes, he could put the bedroom wall in the specific location she requested. Yes, he understood that despite what she had requested before that on second thought it might be better at a new specified location. Every once in awhile she’d push him just a little too far. He wouldn’t argue or get loud or even protest. He’d just look over at Dad and Uncle Joe and say “You boys wanna go fishing?” And that would be that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That house is still standing across the way from what used to be the Midget Bar. It is one of many that now sit on those five acres that Grandma purchased back in 1962. Her intention was to take care of her family in any way that she could. I’m sure that neither Grandma or Grandpa found the situation ideal. I wonder if either of them would have ever dreamed that this land at the top of Binger Hill would someday be considered home to so many.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Otis Ray?</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some things quite clearly belong in this world. They come to us in a variety of different packages. We have experienced them at some point with all of our senses. They are easy to identify. When you see them, even for the first time, it is familiar. The taste and smell is pleasant. You could swear that you’ve heard them before. It just feels right. That is how I perceive art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that good songs sound familiar is because they already exist. The musician does not create the song, he discovers it. This is accomplished by a process of elimination. Revise, Play, Destroy. Repeat this process until the noise gives way to music. There are an unlimited supply of songs out there just waiting to be discovered. They are rarely found with ease. There are no more free standing pools of songs for Jed Clampett to discover with a mere shotgun blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otis Ray was not discovered quickly or easily. We started over several times. We made every mistake in the book and nearly quit. Without a sense of accountability to each other, I am convinced that we would have quit. A few other things saved the song. It’s content has obvious sentimental value that we were reluctant to give up on. Also we told ourselves from the beginning that we were not in a rush, so there was less pressure. The biggest reason, in my opinion, was that we took a break in the middle to record an easier more lighthearted song. We came back to the Otis Ray project with some confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song began with Rodney writing verses about his father, JW Craddock. These were mostly his childhood memories. He planned on writing a song for his dad. He was a bit reluctant to show me the unfinished lyrics. I offered to help put them to music so he relented. I read them and knew immediately that this would be a great song. However, it needed changes. I was a bit nervous to make suggestions since it was so personal. For instance, initially all of the lyrics were written about his father. I suggested that the words be directed to him instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other lyrical contribution was the title. Initially the song was called “The Old Man”. The title didn’t sit with me well. I asked Rodney for any nicknames that his father had. He told me a story about a boxing match they had watched together years earlier. The bout was between one boxer named Odis and another named Otis Ray. The fight quickly turned into a comical back alley brawl as the fighters began trading low blows. From that point on, Uncle JW began calling Rodney Odis which of course resulted in him being dubbed Otis Ray. It stuck. Years later, they were still calling each other by the nicknames, nearly forgetting the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a collector of ideas. I keep lists. I have lists of short stories I want to write. As I have mentioned before I collect potential song titles. I have lists of books I want to write, products I want to create, businesses I want to start, etc. I also keep quick and dirty recordings of melodies, riffs and other musical ideas. The titles I give these recordings range from a sort of onomatopoeia like ‘blee blah duh’ to what instrument it was recorded with. The name I gave to the riff that became Otis Ray was ‘some acoustic new’. It barely resembles the song we ended up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the lyrics that Rodney gave me and I applied them to the music that I had previously recorded. I took my favorite two verses he wrote and transformed them into a pre-chorus and chorus. As usual, I recorded a demo with me playing the guitar and singing. After crossing my fingers, I sent them to Rodney. I wasn’t sure what to expect. It could have gone several ways. He could have been offended or worse apathetic. To my relief he loved it. Of course there were several changes that he wanted to make, mostly to the lyrics. He did make one major change to the way the chorus was structured. With his improvements, we had ourselves a song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, our first mistake was basing everything around a guitar riff. In theory one should be able to play with a metronome and everything would be in time. In practice, that doesn’t work very well. We had a completed song that sounded ok, but something just wasn’t right. I would focus on my parts and hear little mistakes here and there. I would re-record my parts and send them to Rodney. He would do the same. I kept telling myself that the problem was with the mix or some other technical issue that I was inexperienced with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I had begun recording another song, &lt;a href=&#34;http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/24/a-good-end-to-a-great-time-part1/&#34;&gt;Bad End to a Good Time&lt;/a&gt;. This was done during a period of time when the work on the Otis Ray project was in Rodney’s court. When I was working on Otis Ray, he would work on Bad End. It was becoming obvious that Otis Ray was going nowhere. It still just sounded wrong. For a time it appeared as if ole Otis Ray was destined for a life of receiving low blows in a back alley brawl. We ended up finishing Bad End first. There was a moment right after we pushed out the song that we nearly abandoned Otis Ray. Ironically, it was saved when we decided to scrap everything and start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney had been working on the project for a couple of weeks. He had recorded, erased and re-recorded every track he had originally created. It still didn’t sound right. He finally threw his hands up and gave me everything he had to see what I could do with it. I did the same, I re-recorded my parts but something was still off. I finally determined to get to the bottom of the problem. I began listening to tracks. The rhythm guitar and bass were good together but when I listened to them individually with a metronome they were off. It finally occurred to me that the issue was that every current track had been recorded along with the bass. The bass however had been recorded to match the original riff which had long been erased. Guitar riffs are rarely precise. In fact what made this particular riff good in the first place was it’s “looseness”. Riffs are meant to be played along with a backing track not vice versa. To top it off, I wasn’t even playing it the same anymore. With a sinking heart I realized that the we had to start over completely from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I recorded a rhythm guitar backing track first. I made sure that I had no timing issues. I sent it to Rodney and waited. What I received back a few days later completely restored my faith. Rodney had added vocals, a bass track and drums. Up until this point we didn’t have any drums at all. In fact it had been a source of worry for me. I knew we would never have a complete song with no drums. We knew a couple of drummers and even had one of them record drums for Bad End. The problem was that all of them were too busy. The music we were recording wasn’t a very high priority to any of them. That became less of an issue when Rodney discovered the Independence Free midi drum composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been much of a fan of computer generated drums. They always have this mechanical sound that isn’t acceptable to me. We were able to avoid this by keeping things simple. Rodney spent a lot of time tweaking the drums so that it gave us a good beat without being in your face. He told me about a feature that he used that is supposed to humanize the drums. I’m not exactly sure how it works but in my imagination it intentionally screws up every now and again. I got excited about this song for the first time since the beginning once I heard what Rodney had done with it. The drums in particular did the trick for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got busy with the rest of the guitar tracks. The more we recorded the less we used the original riff I had written. It began as the driving force of the song. By the time we were done it was only used for a measure at the beginning and end of the song. It’s funny how sometimes the very genesis of an idea can be the biggest hindrance in its completion. In the end we ended up with one bass track, one vocal track, two rhythm guitar tracks panned opposite of each other, a lead guitar track and a midi drum track. Rodney was responsible for the mix of the song. I couldn’t begin to explain the effects that were added to each track. I know that he balanced the volume envelope of each one and added compression where it made sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that was left was the video. Let me just say this about making videos, I hate it. Thankfully my partner in crime does not. The only credit I can take in the video production department is offering Rodney challenging material to work with. In my opinion, the video that he created for Otis Ray is the best to date. It is a kind of video / image collage of his father who is after all the subject of the song. I love that Rodney tries to add something new. I initially resisted the train scene while I was playing the lead part, but we showed it to several people who liked it. I finally concluded that I was not best suited for make video decisions. I only wish I could have given him better material to work with. I am going to get a green screen for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney videod his part in his backyard standing in front of the lake. He then added some kind of filter to the footage which turned out pretty good. All of the pictures were from Rodney’s own collection of family photos. The old videos were supplied by my father, Larry Craddock. It was footage of the 1992 Craddock Family Pitch tournament. Rodney is seen sitting next to his father in many of the shots. I think he was 18 or 19 years old at the time. If you look closely, I am in the very last shot standing in the back with a baseball cap on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have lots of old footage like the one used for this video. Our family is very close. Growing up, we lived next door to each other. Rodney and I grew up more like brothers than cousins. Uncle JW was like a second father to me and my father was the same for Rodney. Even though this song is without a doubt Rodney’s homage to his father. It isn’t hard for me to exchange those pictures into ones of my father as well. At the same time, I definitely learned my fair share of lessons from my Uncle JW. To me, ending the video with that unique laugh of his is perfect. He seemed perfectly comfortable at the center of attention amongst family. He jokingly called for everyone to clap for him. As you can see Uncle Jay, we are still clapping for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 3 year old Storm hit Montgomery, Tx</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The family and I made our way down to Montgomery, Texas a few weeks ago. We stayed with my cousin Rodney and his girlfriend Erin for nearly a week. Our goal was to convince them that they should never, ever for any reason have children. Not that there was any talk of kids. Ethan was only too eager to help prevent that conversation from ever happening, ever. Drew made a beeline to the back room where he holed away to play the XBox, rarely to be seen again. Linda had planned all sorts of fun stuff for us to do together. On the agenda was the NASA museum, the Houston Aquarium and Galveston beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got no sleep at all that first night. Erin kept me up all night goading me into arguments that I wanted no part of. To make it worse, she resorted to cheating to win these arguments using all sorts of nefarious psychology tricks that she learned from this book or that. Rodney and Linda just laughed at us. They didn’t sleep either though so the joke was on them too. Despite all of this, we got around and headed to the NASA museum that next morning. At first I was as eager as a teenager heading out on an adventure, sleep be damned. That lasted until Ethan came running into the room whooping and hollering while running in circles around the room. He desperately wanted to play with Erin’s dog Patches. Patches wasn’t too fond of children especially ones who insist on playing with his toys. He just wouldn’t leave the dog alone. My suggestion to just let him get bit and get it over with was ignored. The poor dog was exiled to the back room until the boy went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so our routine was established. We stayed up too late at night only to regret it the next morning as we drove through the depths of the city with headaches. I must have driven through Houston rush hour traffic a dozen times as my passengers gripped handles, seats or each other with white knuckles. Not the boys though, they kept themselves entertained as they always do, annoying each other. We all had a great time. I won’t bore you with a bunch of details about our tourist activities except for a little about the beach. I’m sure that all of you who care have already seen the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We timed our trip to the beach perfectly. There was a storm in the gulf that hadn’t yet made it to Galveston. This left us with perfect swimming weather, still in the 90’s but not burning hot. Linda and I got a kick out of watching the boys experience the beach for the first time. Drew stripped to his trunks and began his attempts at mastering the waves with a boogie board. Ethan in a rare moment of caution just stared as if trying to understand this strange body of water. He would wade into the water and then hightail it out of there as the waves crashed towards him. By the end of the day we were taking turns dragging him kicking and screaming back to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The storm hit that night and it rained all the next day. Rodney and I spent the entire day singing and playing music. We had left our dog Sugar with a kind neighbor who offered to feed and shelter her while we were away. Sugar isn’t so fond of the rain. Linda was worried about how she was handling it. I was pretty sure I knew exactly how she was handling it and so we wrote a song about it. I figured everyone needs a corny half blues toon about their dog. So that is how we spent our day. All in all it turned out pretty good. I arranged the tracks we had created once I was home and Rodney synced it up to the videos we recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to head home the next day. Both Linda and I were pretty sure that we had definitely worn out our welcome. Of course Rodney and Erin swore they were sad to see us go. They insisted that we should return soon. I’m sure they both let out a big sigh of relief as we drove away. Ethan held up to his part of the bargain that week. I think we just about convinced them that kids were just too much trouble. If Drew hadn’t been so well behaved all week, I think we could have sealed the deal. Linda, the kids and I don’t get to go on adventures like that very often. We sure picked a great place to go this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandma and the Rolltop Desk</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/08/grandma-and-the-rolltop-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/08/grandma-and-the-rolltop-desk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My hands slipped and the heavy desk slammed into my face. It’s free fall to the concrete was impeded only by this and a knee which is now bruised scarlet. I did manage to save the desk from harm. My face took the brunt of the damage. I stood there frowning as I looked at a split lip in the mirror and felt thankful. For one thing, I was physically capable of standing. I was also able to treat my own wounds and curse loudly as I had just proven. The desk was my grandmothers and she isn’t able to do any of those things. My parents and I spent the majority of last Saturday moving her furniture to storage. As I tried to decide whether or not to risk a little blood shaving over the wound, my grandmother was laid up in a rest home barely able to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, grandma had a stroke while undergoing surgery. She had developed an aneurysm which required immediate attention. During the procedure there was a blood clot or something to that effect and the unthinkable happened. When it was all over, she was rendered almost helpless. This woman who always had some kind of answer for everything could now only mutter few words like yes, no and ok. She lost the use of her right arm rendering her writing hand useless. Eventually she was able to walk around enough to get to a bathroom or head down the hall with difficulty. Her mind on the other hand seemed completely unmolested, at least at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandmother and I were never very close. Don’t get me wrong we love each other but neither of us has been very good at expressing it over the years. She is definitely not your prototypical grandmother and I was never in contention for grandson of the year. It has always been obvious to me that grandma had a wall, Pink Floyd style, between her and the rest of the world. I can only guess at the source of the heartache and pain that led to its construction. But as a result, she became a fighter. She has always been very independent refusing to put up with anyone’s crap. Grandma accomplished this by relying on as few people as possible. From my vantage, the seclusion seemed to suit her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t even begin to understand how frustrating it must be for her now. She has been reduced to three words and animated hand gestures to get her point across. She frequently loses her patience with the people who are trying to help her. The person she loses her patience with the most is my mother. I don’t think anyone could ask for a better daughter. No matter how inconvenient, abusive or heart wrenching the task might be, my mother has without fail been there. After the stroke, mom helped grandma procure a room at an assisted living facility. For those of you who don’t know it is more like a hotel than a rest home. In order to be able to stay there one must be able to get around fairly well and take care of themselves for the most part. There is a constant nursing presence just in case. She had a nice large room with plenty of space to entertain company for when we would visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom spends a lot of time there with her. If grandma needs something and the nurse can’t guess what it is, grandma points to a sign stuck to the wall. The sign reads “CALL MY DAUGHTER” and it lists mom’s phone number. Mom has a kind of sixth sense when it comes to anticipating grandma’s requests. Somehow she knows, or is able to find out with a quick trial and error process. Grandma will make a series of unintelligible sounds and mom will ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom: “Are you in pain?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma: “No, No, No”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom: “Are you hungry?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma: “No!, No!, No!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom: “Do you want to go shopping?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma: “OK!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom: “Do you need new shoes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma with a big smile: “YEAH, YEAH!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see these types of exchanges every time I am around them. If it takes very many times for mom to determine what she wants the final “YES” comes out in an exasperated tone. Grandma then looks over at me and gives me a wink as if to say “See, I’m still all here in my head.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all hoped that grandma would improve. We hoped that she would get more strength in her body and regain the ability to speak. The doctors seemed to think it was plausible. At first she would try to talk. It would come out like “doh doh doh doh”. I think that she actually thought that she was saying something. Afterwards she would look at you as if she expected an answer. I would be forced to confess that I didn’t understand her. She eventually realized that she wasn’t getting through to us. After awhile she gave up on that and would just answer yes or no to questions we would pose to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse, grandma started having issues getting around. She would fall and hurt herself. She got to where she needed help getting to the bathroom. Technically, the nurses weren’t supposed to make a habit of helping in this manner. However, they had told grandma that if she called they would come and help her. Well, grandma being grandma would get impatient if it took them very long to respond. This would inevitably lead to grandma tripping over something and injuring herself. She finally fell and broke her arm. Grandma was in a lot of pain, the arm seemed to be broken pretty badly. At first there was talk of surgery but it was ultimately decided that surgery was too big of a risk. They put it in a sling and prescribed pain medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma wasn’t able to stay in her assisted living room. She is currently temporarily staying at the actual rest home next door where she has nurses around the clock. We put her furniture in storage while we wait for her to recover enough to move back to her old room. To the surprise of no one, mom has already begun negotiating a new arrangement which will allow grandma as much comfort and independence as is safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about grandma a lot in the last few days. I feel guilty for not going to see her more often. I regret not having spent more time talking to her when she was still able. I admit I am a little bitter that she didn’t make more of an effort but the road runs both ways. The past is the past and people can only give what they have. In the meantime, I will try to follow my mom’s example and be there when I am needed. If it means I suffer a busted lip every once in awhile, I guess its worth it in the end. As for busted lips, I have decided to risk a little blood and shave the mustache. Even though the beard might hide the wound on my mouth, it also stops me from applying the medicine that is needed to prevent an infection. It&amp;#8217;s funny how that works out isn&amp;#8217;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Rushmore – Our Great American RV Adventure</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/10/our-great-american-rv-adventure-mount-rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/10/our-great-american-rv-adventure-mount-rushmore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days in Yellowstone, it was time to head home. We decided to take a different route back in order to see more of the American west. We exited Yellowstone via the east entrance and took highway 16 to Cody, Wy. We continued on highway 16 with a little trepidation through the Bighorn mountains. We had read reports of sharp curves and steep roads that might tax the breaks. Losing your breaks on a 10% decline is the last thing you want in a 35 foot RV. However, after surviving dirt roads at the top of the Grand Tetons we felt we could handle anything and it turned out to be a non issue. At Greybull we took highway 14 over to I90 and entered Sheridan, Wy the home of the world famous Peter D&amp;#8217;s RV Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before reaching Sheridan, we browsed around the internet looking for a good place to spend the night. Peter D&amp;#8217;s was highly recommend by all visitors. We couldn&amp;#8217;t find a bad review of the place. Sure enough the RV park was ideal. It was easy to access, quiet and extremely clean. It was almost too clean, at least once an employee waited for me to finish using the restroom so that he could clean it. Peter D himself was a very friendly old man that seemed to exist solely to help his customers. This park became the model that we would compare all other locations with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the next day making our way to the Black hills of South Dakota. We made a brief stop in Deadwood where we had buffalo burgers for lunch. We also managed to spend a few minutes at the Mt Moriah cemetary where Wild Bill Hickock and Calamity Jane are buried. Deadwood is a neat place with a lot of history. Had we decided to stay longer, we could have seen more cowboy shootouts and several museums depicting life in the wild west. That being said, our goal was Mount Rushmore and with a little luck we could be there before nightfall. We pulled into the Rafter J-Bar ranch with plenty of time to park, grab a bite to eat and unload the Serento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Rushmore is the mountain near Keystone, South Dakota where Gutzon Borglum sculpted the larger than life faces of four U.S. Presidents, George Washington, Thomas Jefferson, Theodore Roosevelt and Abraham Lincoln. Every night a patriotic presentation is made honoring America. At the beginning night has not yet fallen and the presidents faces are visible in the background of an outdoor amphitheater. The presentation consists of raising the flag, a speech from a presenter along with several videos that are projected onto a screen on the main platform. The night grows darker as the show goes on. By the end the presidents faces are no longer visible in the dark of night. At the culmination of the performance, huge flood lights are powered on illuminating Mount Rushmore in glorious fashion. It was quite amazing. As the entire crowd was speechless in appreciation, Ethan broke the silence and yelled &amp;#8220;OOOH SCARY&amp;#8221;. Everyone in the crowd laughed as Linda and I blushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left early the next morning. For the first time during our entire trip, we didn&amp;#8217;t have any reservations or anything in particular planned other than driving. From Mount Rushmore to my sisters house in Wichita, Ks was about a 12 hour drive. After some convincing dad and I talked our wives into letting us just drive it straight through. This would not only break, but shatter our rule of not spending more than 6 to 8 hours on the road in one day. They ultimately agreed because everyone was ready to be home and Stephanie was really missing her oldest child. We drove all day and despite stopping pretty frequently to stretch our legs we were well on our way to making our destination in closer to 10 hours than 12. Or at least that is what we thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the arrangements were complete. We had found an RV park in Wichita. Stephanie was going to meet us there and pick up Dylan. It was just a matter of time before we would be asleep and then making our way back to Oklahoma. We were probably 30 minutes north of Wichita when I heard a loud BANG and the RV started fishtailing back and forth. Dad&amp;#8217;s eyes bulged nearly out of their sockets. He grabbed the wheel with both hands and fought the inevitable flip that I was convinced was next.  He managed to wrangle the vehicle to a stop on the side of the highway. We had blown a single rear tire, it was the inside one on the right. Other than my near fatal heart attack, there were no injuries. Both boys were wide eyed but neither panicked. I don&amp;#8217;t think Ethan even woke up and Linda and mom were more concerned about the kids than anything else. Thankfully it ended up being just one more memorable event in a vacation of many, even if this one wasn&amp;#8217;t as welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for our early arrival in Wichita. An inspection of the damage resulted in finding a very flat tire along with severed cables and a damaged mud flap. We of course had a spare tire but after careful consideration, we decided to take the recommendation of the owners manual. We called a professionals to actually change out the tire. It took about an hour for him to find us but he was a real nice guy and handled the work like a pro. By the end of another hour we were finally ready to leave. Despite the late hour, Stephanie still came to get Dylan but we promised to drop by the next morning before we left. Finally after a very long day, it was time to get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or at least that is what we had hoped. We quickly found out that the air conditioner was no longer functional at all! While the RV was twisting and turning on the road apparently the mud flap had been caught up over the tire and it completely destroyed some wiring that was secured at the top of the wheel base. I won&amp;#8217;t even mention what I think of the person who made that design decision. These wires turned out to be power to the air conditioner. So after a very long day spent almost entirely on the road and a heart stopping flat tire, we capped off the night by drowning in sweat and praying for some way to fall  asleep. We did finally sleep and I for one slept well once I finally managed to keep my eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we woke up early and all of us were eager to get home. We hugged and kissed the three girls at a short stopover at Stephanie&amp;#8217;s house before we began the 3 hour journey back to Anadarko. Linda and I were definitely ready to continue the rest of the way back to Fort Worth. As far as vacations go, this one could definitely be classified as epic. Many people have many different ideas on what the ideal vacation should be. Some people want to experience places that they ordinarily would not see. Others just need a break from the monotony of their lives. Some want to let their hair down and have a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, a vacation is a microcosm of life that acts as a sort of testing ground. You begin a journey with a group you care about. Despite how carefully you might plan your adventure, it never turns out how you expect. A good portion of the journey is spent attempting to overcome hurdles while still achieving your goals. If you complete your journey with your group intact and a smile on your face, you are a success. I must say that our vacation to Yellowstone National park was a huge success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone (part 2) – Our Great American RV Adventure</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/10/our-great-american-rv-adventure-yellowstone-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/10/our-great-american-rv-adventure-yellowstone-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After travelling through five states in four days, we were finally at our destination, Yellowstone National Park. By this time we had a well established morning routine. At around 6AM, dad would come tip toeing  through the RV attempting to exit without waking the boys (especially Ethan). I would get up and follow him out. We had a coffee pot pre-prepared the night before ready to be brewed. By the time it was ready, mom would join us also in need of caffeine.  Eventually Ethan would wake up and of course it was unthinkable that anyone should be asleep while he was not. After converting the hideaway bed back into a couch and reassembling the table, we would all have breakfast. On this day in particular, there was no moaning or slow footing. Everyone was ready to finally begin our exploration of the park. Ethan again reminded us of his intense desire to see a bear as a flurry of destination requests came from the older two boys. We packed up in the Serento and made our way into the park. This scene replayed itself every morning for the next two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yellowstone National park is huge. It encompasses 2,219,789 acres. That would be nearly 3,470 square miles. Seeing the entire park is virtually impossible as most of it is undeveloped and untouched by humans. We decided early on to avoid guided tours and instead drive around the park looking for interesting sites on our own. We did this in an effort to see as much as we could in a short amount of time. There are two primary roads that loop around the park. The Grand Loop circles the northern part of the park. The Grand loop passes by Norris geyser, Mammoth Hot Springs, Roosevelt Lodge and the Canyon Village center. The other loop is much longer but it hugs the northern edge of Yellowstone Lake. It also passes next to Old Faithful and the Old Faithful lodge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that became evident pretty quickly is that Yellowstone is a very strange place. Steam spewing out of the rocks everywhere, boiling water next to creeks and bubbling puddles of mud are not normal. Not to mention water geysers everywhere you turned around. It didn&amp;#8217;t take long for me to put two and two together. All of the oddities that make Yellowstone interesting are made possible by seismic activity. The whole park is sitting on top of one huge super volcano. Apparently, it is one of the largest volcanoes on earth. Scientists have discovered that it erupts approximately every 600,000 years and the last eruption occurred about 640,000 years ago.  If this sounds a bit disturbing don&amp;#8217;t worry about it too much and definitely don&amp;#8217;t cancel your Yellowstone vacation plans. That is unless you live on another continent. If Yellowstone erupts and you live in North America you are in as much or more danger than if you were in the park. The ash alone would cover the ground as far east as Iowa, the sun would not be visible for several years and most of us wouldn&amp;#8217;t survive anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that it&amp;#8217;s important to point out that our primary goal was to see a bear. Any wildlife was  a welcome sight, however nothing compared with spotting bears. Ever since seeing the life sized stuffed bear in the gift shop at the Cave of the Winds, Ethan could think of nothing but bears. As we made our way through dense forests, hiked along dirt paths or drove up winding mountain roads he chanted about bears. The boy was obsessed. Thankfully there were lots of really cool things to see as we hunted for bears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way we viewed boiling springs, boiling puddles, steam rising out of rocks and water spewing out of the ground. Raised planks of wood were laid out over the ground with sporadic signs warning us of the dangers of getting too close to just about anything. The ground around springs and geysers were an assortment of colors. The whole area looked like someone had painted it with crazy designs. It was hard to believe it was real. There were ponds filled with boiling hot water. These ponds had streams with boiling water reaching out for larger creeks. At one point we saw boiling streams that flowed out into a small canyon with a creek at the bottom forming a boiling waterfall. It seemed everything boiled including our temperament a few times after having spent so much time in close quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early on we made our way to the most famous geyser at Yellowstone, Old Faithful. It was a very popular location indeed. For some reason I was unprepared for the huge concrete parking lot and shopping mall that surrounded the geyser. There had to be a thousand people all visiting the complex which contained the Old Faithful Inn and restaurant, along with a gift shop, an ice cream parlor, cafeteria, museums among other places to visit. Old Faithful erupts approximately every 90 minutes. The interval used to be about every hour but has increased over time due to earth quakes. We all crowded up near the geyser with all of the other tourists and waited with video cameras alert waiting for it to spew water and steam into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ethan mumbled alternatively something about bears and wanting down, I spent the time people watching. There were all sorts of tourists from all over the country. There were mothers, fathers, grand parents and children of every nationality. Boy scouts marched along with their troops. Families scuttled by speaking languages I didn&amp;#8217;t understand. However, as much as I like to think that I am unique, I have to admit that there wasn&amp;#8217;t much that distinguished us from every one else. We were all rubberneckers gawking at an anomaly of nature that could turn deadly on us at all at any moment. As I looked at the beautiful scenery, I could only describe it as majestic. It was hard for me to justify the fact that I was destroying part of it by just being there. It&amp;#8217;s as if in order to gain the perspective necessary to appreciate the beauty of something we must destroy part of that beauty. I wonder how many other things in life this applies to. Old Faithful finally erupted and like the other tourists we took pictures and videos of each other standing in front of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention that Ethan had become obsessed with bears? Thank god for the Grizzly and Wolf Discovery Center in West Yellowstone, Mt. After failing to see hide nor hair of a wild animal our first day, we decided to visit the museum. It was the home of half a dozen grizzly bears and a small pack of wolves. The curators of the museum are nice enough to take in the animals who take to human company to easily. Once a bear gets a taste of picnic baskets they can never go back. Bears and humans in close proximity is never a good thing and can lead to the death of one or the other or both. We walked through the museum and saw several stuffed bears. Of course Ethan was attracted and terrified at the same time. Afterwards we went out back and saw at least 4 or 5 full grown wolves lounging in the sun. The main attraction were the bears. Before they were let out, several kids accompanied by rangers strategically placed large pieces of meat out. After everyone was safely back outside, the bears were let out and we were all able to see them feed.  The grizzly bears were huge. I can&amp;#8217;t imagine what would happen to my bowels if I were to see one up close and unpinned. Unfortunately seeing live bears only increased Ethan&amp;#8217;s interest in them and if anything we heard more about bears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a good portion of our time just driving around the park. If we came upon something that looked interesting than we stopped. We tried not to get in a big hurry. One of the coolest things we saw were waterfalls. We saw several of them. Some were plainly visible from the main road. Others we had to hike a ways to see. While visiting one of these waterfalls we met a neat couple. Adam and Christy Coppola are a young couple who are riding their bikes across the United States visiting every state on the way in one year. I was a bit embarrassed complaining about a 200 yard hike to the waterfall after hearing about a 11,000 mile bike ride.  That sounds like an awesome adventure to me. I&amp;#8217;ve been following them on their adventure ever since at &lt;a href=&#34;http://giveabike.com&#34;&gt;giveabike.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anytime we saw anything that resembled a road that separated us from the main road, we took it. We saw some of the best scenery this way. As we drove down one of them we came upon a mini traffic jam and sure enough there was a bear! There were several people all huddled together behind a car a little ways down the road. They were all taking pictures of a wild bear. After evaluating the other tourists, I was convinced that I could outrun them all. This gave me the courage to join the huddle and start taking pictures too. If the bear decided to attack, I figured I didn&amp;#8217;t have to outrun the bear just the other tourists. Finally the cars in front of us decided to move on, so I scurried back to the Serento. After all this time Ethan would finally get to see a bear, except HE WAS ASLEEP. Typically we count it a blessing when the boy is asleep, this time we woke him up. He was so excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our primary mission accomplished, it was time to pack up and prepare for our 1400 mile trek back home. We decided to take a route through South Dakota and Nebraska on our way home. This would take us through the Black Mountains and Mount Rushmore but first we had to cross the Bighorns and the steepest road we would travel yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering Yellowstone – Our Great American RV Adventure</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/09/our-great-american-rv-adventure-yellowstone-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/09/our-great-american-rv-adventure-yellowstone-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Driving through Wyoming is like touring a spaghetti western movie. At any moment I expected traditionally dressed Arapaho to come riding out on horseback. Dylan and Drew peered out the window, one of them exclaimed &amp;#8220;this looks like Red Dead Redemption&amp;#8221;. This truly was a perfect picture of how I have always envisioned the Old West high plains. This describes most of the terrain of Wyoming, that is until one reaches the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We entered Yellowstone National Park from the southern entrance which took us first through Grand Teton National Park. This was our first real experience driving through the mountains in an RV. From where I was sitting, the RV looked too wide to co-exist on the road with other cars. Every time we passed another motor home I was sure there would be a collision with one of us rolling down the mountain. At one point on the drive in there was construction on the road. So here we are in a 35 foot long RV. It seemed as wide as two lanes. We were towing an SUV while driving on a dirt road on the side of a mountain at somewhere around 8000 feet above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have been terrified. Instead, I couldn&amp;#8217;t take my eyes off of the scenery. It was absolutely amazing. Imagine looking down on an untouched forest that stands next to a lake as big as an ocean with a snow peaked mountain range off in the distance hovering like an apparition.  We had just spent our longest day on the road yet. We were all exhausted from being in a vehicle for too long. However, the mountains seemed to revive us. Suddenly instead of dreaming of showers and feet on the ground, we started thinking about grizzly bears and Old Faithful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did drive right past the road to Old Faithful that first day. We saw the historic Inn to our left but we decided to use good sense and save sight seeing for the next day. We pushed on until we finally arrived at our destination, West Yellowstone, Montana. Unfortunately the RV park where we had reservations was the worst we would have the entire trip. It was crowded with the lots packed closley together. It was not as long as advertised and we had to remove the tow dolly and push it up against the side of the RV so that it wouldn&amp;#8217;t hang out in the road. To make things worse the bathrooms weren&amp;#8217;t very nice and the employees at the front desk were not friendly. It was a good thing that we didn&amp;#8217;t intend on spending too much time there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West Yellowstone, Mt is a neat little tourist town that sits right on the west entrance of the park on the Montana / Wyoming border. There were dozens of little gift shops, restaurants and museums that were all within walking distance of our RV park. That first night Linda, Dylan, Drew and I took a stroll to the general store to pick up some groceries and to get our first glimpse of the town.  For a town whose sole purpose is to cater to tourists, the residents were stand-offish to tourists. I can imagine that a steady stream of strangers who constantly expect you to answer questions about the park could get a bit annoying. I was more interested in how they dealt with the weather. I managed to strike up a conversation with the couple who ran the general store. The gentleman, who lives in the town year around, told me that it got 40 below this last winter. The woman, who I assumed was his wife, informed me that he spent the winter there alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like a kid that night. I was too excited to sleep. In my dreams, herds of buffalo stampeded across the plains with wolves chasing them. Just as wolf was about to catch one it was snatched up by a grizzly bear. We would spend the next two days trying to take in as much of the park as we could. This would be juggled with trying to keep Ethan alive and the rest of us sane.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colorado Springs – Our Great American RV Adventure</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/our-great-american-rv-adventure-colorado-springs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/our-great-american-rv-adventure-colorado-springs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The weather in Oklahoma and Texas leading up to our trip had been blistering hot. It was not at all uncommon for the temperature to reach 110 degrees. When we heard that it would almost certainly rain before we reached Colorado Springs most everyone rejoiced. However, when I looked over at dad he had no expression on his face at all. I asked &amp;#8220;Do you think rain will be an issue?&amp;#8221;. He quietly replied that he had never driven the RV in the elements but was more worried about the wind than the rain. Now that he mentioned it, the trees we passed did seem to be getting whipped around quite a bit. Dad put on a show of confidence but admitted later that he expected a gust to all but topple us over at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived at our destination, a little late but all in one piece. Most of our passengers were none the wiser of any cause for concern. The Garden of the Gods RV park was like a little city. It was pretty nice but a bit crowded. The people were nice though and the bathrooms clean. We slept well after a long day of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cave of the Winds was the day&amp;#8217;s destination. This was our first confirmation that bringing a vehicle along with us was a necessity. There was no way we could have traversed the winding road up the mountain to the Cave&amp;#8217;s entrance in the RV. A gift shop was built around the mouth of the cave. As we waited for our tour to begin, we browsed around the gift shop. At the back of the shop was an obviously fake stuffed bear standing on it&amp;#8217;s hind legs. The bear stood over seven foot tall but did not look menacing at all. Ethan&amp;#8217;s eyes were transfixed on the huge teddy bear. He couldn&amp;#8217;t take his eyes off of it but would shriek in terror if I took him any where near it. This was the genesis of an obsession that would linger for the rest of the trip. From that moment on the words &amp;#8220;want to see bear&amp;#8221; were as likely to be heard as anything. On this particular day Ethan was on a tear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally entered the cave and met our tour guide. He was a nice enough fellow but spoke in a tone that hinted he had given this tour at least a billion times. As he was informing us about stalactites and such at our first stop a young girl bent over and vomited on the floor. During the silence while the young girl was being helped out of the cave, Ethan informed us all quite loudly &amp;#8220;I POOTED&amp;#8221;. Linda&amp;#8217;s face turned two different shades of red. To our relief his diaper did not need changing however that wasn&amp;#8217;t the end of his chatter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just journeying through the cave was a blast. We were guided along narrow passages, up winding stairs or crouching under jagged rocks. We were introduced to all sorts of rock formations. Some of the rooms had names such as the Temple of Silence or Silent Splendor. I don&amp;#8217;t think Ethan stopped talking through the entire tour. It was all we could do to not laugh at him. Large exclamations of &amp;#8220;OOOHH&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;SCARY&amp;#8221; had the whole tour chuckling.  All but the tour guide, I think he felt slighted that people laughed at the two year old instead of his corny jokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exiting the cave, Dylan and Drew convinced dad and I to join them on a contraption that hung over the side of the mountain called the Wind Walker. Mom, Linda and Ethan opted to take pictures from the safety of the ground. The Wind Walker is a sort of obstacle course consisting of planks and ropes that connect a series of platforms. It is like a real life game of chutes and ladders at about 7000 feet above sea level hanging over a 400 foot deep canyon. Before being allowed entrance, one must first be fitted with a full body harness that is equipped with safety ropes that are attached to the course. There is nothing like following a ten year old across a narrow board that extends out twenty feet while peering down a chasm of rock. Despite the safety equipment, I was quite convinced that our trip would be coming to a tragic end at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving the Pike&amp;#8217;s Peak area, we returned back to the RV. We packed up and prepared for the next leg of our trip which would take us into Wyoming. By nightfall we would be in Glendo, Wyoming, if we ever managed to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dodge City – Our Great American RV Adventure</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/our-great-american-rv-adventure-dodge-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/our-great-american-rv-adventure-dodge-city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day one of our trip to see Yellowstone had finally arrived. We could not have been more excited. Linda, Drew, Ethan and I arrived at my parents house in Anadarko, Ok on Sunday just in time for lunch. Dad and I began pre-departure inspections and were immediately faced with a dead main battery. We were able to get it started with a jump and after some fiddling determined that everything was fine. Next we climbed on top of the vehicle in the blistering heat and cleaned out the air conditioning system filters. Everything checked out great. The only thing left to do was attach the tow dolly and hook up mom&amp;#8217;s Kia Serento. This would allow us to pull out early the next morning and head to Wichita. Not everything works out as you plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad pulled the RV up as close to the road as he could as I pulled the tow dolly up to the rear. I hooked up the dolly and dad drove the Serento up on it. Now it was time to secure the vehicle with tow dolly straps, except our straps were too small. We loosened them as much as possible but it wasn&amp;#8217;t enough. I began calling everywhere I could think that might have larger straps. Half the places I called were closed on a Sunday afternoon. Although it would mess up our time, we decided that we would just have to wait until after businesses opened up the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning at about 8 AM, dad and I headed over to McDuffy&amp;#8217;s Auto Parts and found straps long and strong enough to secure the Serento to the dolly. We were on the road by 9:30 AM and in Wichita to pick up Dylan by 2 PM. After visiting with my sister Stephanie for a bit we got on the road and headed to Dodge City, KS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodge City, KS was founded in 1872 and was a major shipping point for cattle in the old west. With the cattle came the cowboys who were mostly young, single men seeking adventure. It wasn&amp;#8217;t long before Dodge City also became one of the wildest places in the old west. Several famous lawmen such as Wyatt Earp and Bat Masterson did their time fighting crime in Dodge City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were in town we visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://boothill.org/&#34;&gt;Boot Hill Museum&lt;/a&gt; which has a historically accurate replica of the old Front street. The street now doubles as gift shops and a museum. Despite their earlier claims of only liking modern guns, Dylan and Drew were overwhelmed by the glass encased gun collection on display. They posed in front of the windows in mock duels and were as excited as I saw them all week. The museum featured many antique items from Dodge City&amp;#8217;s glory days. Out back, at the top of a hill was the old cemetery which included several old graves. Many of the graves with simple wooden gravestones had epitaphs such as &amp;#8220;Edward Hurley, shot Jan 17, 1873. He drank too much and loved unwisely&amp;#8221;. Another one read &amp;#8220;A buffalo hunter named McGill who amused himself by shooting into every house he passed. He won&amp;#8217;t pass this way again. Died March 1873&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had a wonderful time on Front street. In addition to the museum, there was also an antique shop, an authentic saloon and even an ice cream parlor. We sat inside the saloon drinking sarsaparilla while watching can-can dancers as we waited for the main attraction&amp;#8230; the old west gun fight show. The gunfighters would have a showdown at high noon obviously. Before that could occur, the boys would need to be deputized just in case anything happened to the sheriff. The sheriff lined them up and explained to them their duties. He made them swear their allegiances as well as several other important oaths such as &amp;#8220;cleaning their rooms&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;listening to their parents&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was finally time for the gun fight to began. Cowboys swaggered, bad guys behaved slyly and guns flared. Watching the kids with mouth agape was almost as much fun as watching the show. Even Ethan quit squirming and attempting to jump in mud puddles during the performance. After the gun fight was over, the boys took a group picture with all of the performers and bought souvenirs from the gift shop. We were still hearing about cowboys for days. I noticed more than one duel in the next few days as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After retiring back to the Gunsmoke RV park, we got a good nights sleep before moving on. With Dodge City in our rear view mirrors we headed west on highway 50 until we reached I25 and headed north to our next destination, Colorado Springs, CO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Great American RV Adventure – Preparation</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/the-great-american-rv-adventure-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/08/the-great-american-rv-adventure-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The terrain of the United States is a complete wonder to me. The aesthetic difference of the east coast from the west and everything in between is like night and day. It varies so much that it is hard to believe that it is all part of the same country. I believe it to be true that we are in part products of our environment. My upbringing in a small peanut and cotton farming community has vastly shaped my view of the world. I can only assume that this is true of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the last ten days visiting a small section of the country. I have returned amazed that we have even as much in common as we do. I found myself asking over and over again &amp;#8220;Could I be happy here with&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; (insert unique geographical attribute). When I met people I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but try to imagine them living in Caddo county. Sometimes it was more plausible than others. It didn&amp;#8217;t take much effort in Kansas.  However, the people who spent the winter in West Yellowstone, Mt might have found Binger a bit stifling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea to visit Yellowstone National park was my father&amp;#8217;s.  He had fond memories of visiting the park when he was a boy. His oldest brother lived in Washington at the time and two other brothers were temporarily staying in the northwest with friends. My grandparents decided to take the opportunity to both visit their son and return their other boys home. At the age of seven, this was a grand adventure for my dad and he never forgot it. It didn&amp;#8217;t take much for him to convince me to come along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a month shy of ten years old, my son Drew is at the perfect age for this sort of gig. However, no young man can fully enjoy an epic adventure such as this without a running buddy. Thankfully, his cousin Dylan was more than happy to accept the challenge of conquering the road. Conquest was the last thing on Linda and Mom&amp;#8217;s mind. They were excited to see the different destinations, but roughing it was out of the question. Our youngest adventurer, Ethan aged two, was game for anything as long as there were plenty of new experiences and/or things to destroy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cross country RV adventure was the perfect solution. It allowed us to gain access to remote locations at a somewhat reasonable price. All of this could happen without giving up many of the amenities that we were accustomed to. Dad began planning the trip and we were set to leave June 3rd which was the second week that the park fully reopened after the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intention was to leave early Saturday, pick up Dylan and spend our first night in Dodge City, KS. The next day we would take in a couple of sites and continue on to Colorado Springs, CO. During our two planned days in the Rockies, we would scale Pikes Peak and maybe do some white water rafting. Next we would spend two days on the road and finally land at Yellowstone National Park. After four days of watching bear and buffalo and gawking over mud bubbles and geysers we would head home. The drive home would be a straight shot only stopping for bathrooms, food and sleep. These plans were doomed for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before embarking on a trip across country mom and dad thought it wise to make a couple of shorter test runs to get a better idea of what to expect. The first realization was that without full hookups the RV was pretty much just a fancy tent. There are holding tanks for drinking water or refuse but those quickly become empty or full with much use. There are ways of getting around these issues but most of them are more expensive than paying for full hookups. Speaking of expensive, the RV also has a gas powered generator for electrical equipment. I don&amp;#8217;t think I need to remind anyone of how expensive gas is these days.  It didn&amp;#8217;t take much to decide to follow the full hookups. This led to the next realization. RV parks in popular destinations during vacation periods fill up quickly. To ensure full hookups we would need to make reservations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we knew it, the time for our vacation had arrived. I had taken off work for two weeks and we were all excited to hit the road. There was only one snag, it was still snowing in Wyoming and many of the roads to Yellowstone were still closed. There was only one reasonable thing to do&amp;#8230; put chains on the tires of the RV and go anyway. After this idea was quickly vetoed, we decided that it would be best to reschedule our trip to the end of July. We were all a bit disappointed but it was the best decision and we were all glad of it later. The thought of hot rod Larry driving a 35 foot RV through the snow covered mountains still makes me a bit nauseous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delay allowed us to reassess some of our vacation destinations. For instance, a train ride over Pike&amp;#8217;s Peak might be a blast for adults, the children by all accounts would find it extremely boring. We decided on the more kid friendly Cave of the Winds. Also after much consultation from more experienced travelers, it was decided that we should limit the number of driving hours to six. This along with a desire to visit Mount Rushmore on our way home limited our time in Colorado springs to half a day instead of two. Keeping this all in mind, mom took the lead on making reservations at RV parks while dad focused on readying the vehicle for its upcoming journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open House</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/03/open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/03/open-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bluebonnet Elementary school treated the family of its students to an Open House Thursday evening. It was highly anticipated at our house and Drew seemed excited to show us what he had been working on at school. I was already somewhat aware of what I would be seeing as I had been helping him with one of his projects off an on for the prior week. It&amp;#8217;s always fun to go to the school and see what the kids have been working on. Linda and I were excited to go, had I known the future I might have chosen to stay home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drew had been asked to write a paper about someone famous and had been given a list of adequately famous people from which he was allowed to choose. To my disappointment, he chose our illustrious President. Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong I&amp;#8217;m not a President Obama hater or anything of the sort but when he told me of his decision the first thought I had was &amp;#8220;gosh couldn&amp;#8217;t you have picked someone more interesting?&amp;#8221;. What&amp;#8217;s worse is that every question that he asked conjured up some kind of smart ass response that I had to suppress and then answer seriously. For example, &amp;#8220;What is President Obama known for?&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;What is President Obama&amp;#8217;s contribution to the world?&amp;#8221; to which I thought with humor &amp;#8220;being a Muslim that is hell bent on destroying America&amp;#8221;. Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong I don&amp;#8217;t actually think that for a second but I get the feeling that most of my Texan neighbors do but oh my God wouldn&amp;#8217;t it be funny if Drew put that in his paper. I must admit I really had to think hard to conjure up a suitable answer to those questions. It made me wonder what the Nobel people were thinking. Anyway, when it was all said and done Drew was able to write a positive report on Mr. Obama and Open House night was primed to be a success or so we thought the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started out like any other day. I crawled out of bed and found Drew asleep in his room. I woke him up with the normal threat of bodily harm if he went back to sleep. I then went about the process of keeping the momma&amp;#8217;s boy Ethan distracted and out of Linda&amp;#8217;s hair so that she could get ready for work. With a cup of coffee in hand, I alternated between preventing property damage in the living room by Ethan and reminding Drew of my deep love of spanking children if given the chance.  Linda was feeling better after having been sick for several days. This would be her first day back to work in almost a week. She seemed ready to escape our house to the peace of a dozen 3 and 4 year olds for which she is charged with readying for Headstart and Kindergarten. Finally they all left for school and I found myself wonderfully alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the day writing code and answering support calls, nothing new. This continued until about 2:30 PM. I was on the phone discussing some feature requests with a customer when my cell began ringing, it was Linda. I sent her a text to let her know I was on the phone. Her reply changed the rest of my day from typical to exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linda sent me a text that said &amp;#8220;Please come get me, I almost fainted at work&amp;#8221;. I apologized to the customer, replied to Linda that I was on my way and headed out the door. My first thought was &amp;#8220;how do I get both cars back home since she can&amp;#8217;t drive?&amp;#8221;. Well, my brother who is in the process of moving hadn&amp;#8217;t quite moved yet, so I gave him a call and asked for assistance. I then received a call from one of my old clients whose email was down. So I had to call dad, who hosts his email, and let him know. Still on the phone as I drive up to the school, I see Ethan running around the playground. Dad fixed the problem so I hung up the phone and looked at my wife who was white as a ghost. I thought for a moment that I should take her to the hospital but she assured me that she just needed rest. Little did I know that it wouldn&amp;#8217;t be long before I would need some rest myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after having to chase Ethan around the playground for a minute I gathered him up along with his and Linda&amp;#8217;s bags and headed home. Along the way I had to call the old client back to let him know the server was back up and then I dropped Linda off at home. Ethan and I now needed to go retrieve Nathan so that he could drive my truck back home. With that accomplished we all arrived back at my house. I checked on Linda who was laying in bed still fully clothed. She had gotten sick in the bathroom while I was away. I urged her to get some rest. Drew had returned home from school and was now charged with watching his little brother while I drove Nathan back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;#8217;m drivin back home once again, it occurred to me that we still had the Open House to attend that night. I couldn&amp;#8217;t possibly skip it, Drew would be so disappointed. It was going to be bad enough that Linda couldn&amp;#8217;t go and I was determined not to let her go no matter her protests. The logistics of feeding, dressing, preparing and transporting the kids was now a real concern. These were all tasks typically undertaken by Linda. If anything I was usually another soul that needed to be handled and now I would have to do the handling. I accepted my new responsibilities without complaint nor any apparent fear, I&amp;#8217;m a good liar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things went sour almost immediately, I had sent Drew outside to play with his friends to get him out of my hair until it was closer to departure time. As I walked past Ethan I got a nasty whiff of something rotten in his diaper. I reminded him of his recent status change as a big boy and that big boys pooh poohed in the potty. As he looked at me indifferently, I removed his diaper and sat him on the toilet. At right about the same time, my phone started ringing. It was from Paul who was having email problems. I offered to let him handle my current problem while I handled his issue. He declined opting instead to wait for me to call him back when I was finished. I returned to find Ethan with a handful of poop which he was using to paint grotesque pictures on the toilet. I cleaned him up and got him dressed and ready for Open House which was fast approaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next chore was to feed the kids and try to keep them from disturbing their mother&amp;#8217;s sleep. We had about an hour before we had to be at the school. This seemed like the perfect time to abolish my Ronald McDonald ban which pleased everyone. Ethan was very excited once he saw the playground and it was nearly impossible to get him to eat although I did manage to stuff a chicken nugget and a few french fries down him before playground fever over took him irrevocably. Drew took it upon himself to play mother hen and both of them were out of my hair long enough for me to eat. While I sat there eating and watching the kids I started talking to another parent who was in the same boat as me. He told me about his kids, their mother and his job, I listened with as much interest as I could muster. After a few minutes a young black woman left with her daughter. Once she exited the room the first fellow looked at me with true astonishment and said &amp;#8220;She was pretty hot for a black girl, you don&amp;#8217;t see that every day.&amp;#8221; I was a little taken back but managed to smile and change the subject. It did get me to thinking though, do I just look like the kind of guy who is a racist? Was I wearing some kind of secret symbol proclaiming my allegiance to some kind of racist white mans order? I checked myself over for swastikas and found nothing. I guess I should have said something but I didn&amp;#8217;t. I found reasons not to speak to him anymore thankfully it was time to go so I gathered up the kiddos and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Open House time and even though Drew was disappointed that mom couldn&amp;#8217;t come with us we decided that if mom couldn&amp;#8217;t go to the Open House, we&amp;#8217;d bring the Open House to her. We determined to take lots of pictures and do our best to minimize her unhappiness at not being able to attend. We entered the school with Drew in the lead and Ethan and I hand in hand following him. The first place he wanted to show us was the school library. Both the librarian and I were impressed that the library was his favorite room in the school. As became routine, we took pictures and moved on to the next destination which was the art room. What also became routine was Ethan&amp;#8217;s reluctance to hold my hand in the hall. We established a kind of pattern which began with him walking next to me holding my hand. This would soon give way to me picking him up after he would plant himself on the floor refusing to get up. The little bugger is starting to get heavy so after awhile I would put him up on my shoulders. At first he enjoyed being on my shoulders but eventually he would complain that he wanted down. He has a tendency to complain loudly and his preferred method of complaint is via the ear splitting scream at the top of his lungs. This would prompt a bargain of my letting him down in return for him holding my hand which would start the process all over again. This happened over and over again as we made our way through the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the art room, Drew found a piece of art that he created which I believe is an owl with an eye patch. Look here&amp;#8230;. smile&amp;#8230;. flash&amp;#8230; move on to the next attraction before Ethan destroys the room. Next it was time to visit Mrs. Lankford classroom. She is Drew&amp;#8217;s very nice teacher who has somehow put up with him all year without &amp;#8220;signing his folder&amp;#8221; even one time which is definitely a scholastic first for Drew. Now it was time to evaluate several projects Drew has been working on including the dedication to Mr. Obama. I was even given a quiz which I gave up on after about the one hundredth &amp;#8220;no Ethan, stop Ethan&amp;#8221;. I did manage to take pictures though. Drew&amp;#8217;s work looked very good and his classroom was nice. Based on the many exclamations of &amp;#8220;HI DREEW!!!!&amp;#8221; I heard, I think his popularity with his classmates has also been a success. Drew and I left Mrs Lankford&amp;#8217;s in good spirits but Ethan was done and I do mean done. Refusing to cut Drew&amp;#8217;s day short, we soldiered on to the next display which was in the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we entered the gym, we were greeted by the sound of jump ropes skipping across the floor followed by cheers or cries of sympathy. Drew quickly found a jump rope and began showing us how it was done. I was quite impressed I think his record while we stood there was nearly 20 successful rope jumps. He wanted me to try but I begged off due to the now inconsolable two year old in my arms. We didn&amp;#8217;t linger there long. Next we visited the cafeteria where the 4th graders were playing a concert with xylophones and bongos. I was able bribe Ethan to be quiet by giving him juice while we listened. It was very impressive. I hope Drew can play with them next year. Before Drew would accept departure for home, he insisted that we visit his past teachers from 1st and 2nd grade Mrs. Ogle and Mrs. Parker. Afterwards we headed back to the car. I was so relieved to be going home. How wrong I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called Linda to let her know that we were heading home and as an afterthought I said &amp;#8220;Have you eaten? Would you like me to pick you up something?&amp;#8221;. Had I known then, I would have kept my mouth shut. She just wanted something quick a burger or something. Would I please drop by Wendy&amp;#8217;s? &amp;#8220;Sure&amp;#8221; I replied, why not. Well I now know why not. As we drove down the road we noticed the traffic was a little heavy. I attributed it to a neighborhood full of parents who had just attended an Open House. The first issue was an ill timed freight train that set us back at least 15 minutes. Then as we pulled up to Wendy&amp;#8217;s it was depressing to see that we were the 10th car in line at the drive through. This is all made worse by a little boy in the back who is intent on testing the max volume at which he can scream. I held my composure by remembering a sick wife waiting at home who was not only feeling ill but no doubt starving at this point. Drew on the other hand noticed nothing except the current hi-jinx of Harry Potter and crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our order was handed to us and we waited in a 20 car line at the red light which came and went three times before we were allowed to pass, we finally headed home. The rest of the night was hazy but it involved rocking the little guy to sleep and then hitting the sack myself. I would like to note that Linda loved the pictures and was in better shape when we returned. All in all, it was a wonderful day that I won&amp;#8217;t forget anytime soon. Apparently we are sometimes made to suffer a bit to help us commit to memory why life with those that we love is worth living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reluctant Prisoner</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/02/the-reluctant-prisoner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/02/the-reluctant-prisoner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The terms of surrender of private property and personal liberty were never fully agreed upon by all parties. Linda and I, henceforth known as &amp;#8220;The parents&amp;#8221;, have spent the better part of two years trying to ensure that the life, limb and property of a certain mister Ethan Craddock  remain unmolested, much to his annoyance. He seems to consider himself a prisoner, the reluctant prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago an incident occurred that made us painfully aware of the drastic measures which needed to take place. I won&amp;#8217;t go into all the details but while one of us was away and the other was in the restroom for mere moments, the little guy made his way out the front door and down the street. Apparently, one of Drew&amp;#8217;s friends had knocked on the door and Drew unlocked the dead bolt and opened the door to inform them that he couldn&amp;#8217;t play at the moment. This was just the break that Ethan was looking for and he bolted out the front door as soon as Drew turned his back. He made it half way down the block only to have his escape thwarted by our next door neighbor who returned him home and was later nominated for sainthood. The entire incident could not have lasted longer than five minutes but the thoughts of &amp;#8220;what if&amp;#8221; rattled us both and opened our eyes to what we could expect for the next sixteen or more years. Eighteen month old boys have no place in the front yard without supervision and we became determined to ensure this prohibition. We decided at that moment to make our home &amp;#8220;Ethan Proof&amp;#8221; a commitment not taken lightly and surely not easily accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan of action was threefold education, elevation and physical barricades. First we informed the child that all doors in the house were to be classified as a solid &amp;#8220;NO! NO!&amp;#8221;. Violation of the Don&amp;#8217;t Open Doors policy was dealt with by force or more commonly known as involuntarily sticking ones nose in the corner. Drew was also reminded and quizzed incessantly about the foolhardiness of opening the front door outside the supervision of an adult no matter whose voice was on the other side. Next all valuable, sharp or otherwise unsafe items were placed on shelves that were higher than 4 feet. Climbing on furniture was strictly forbidden with special attention being placed upon accessing desirable items by pushing chairs up next to their shelf locations. Finally we placed physical barriers in front of all exterior doors as well as deadbolts out of reach to toddlers. I also re-prioritized my intention to read the manual to our alarm system which had a nifty little feature which sounded a loud beep every time an outside door was opened. This feature which was deemed too annoying during the alarm installation four years ago had become a must have four years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure the neighborhood excursion of our toddler was not the first time that we had considered denying access to certain areas of the house. Months ago we had purchased what was advertised as baby proof door knobs. These devices were designed to fit around the door handle so that one had to squeeze the handle before it was possible to turn the knob and gain access to a room. We learned pretty quickly that these managed to only lengthen the amount of time that it took him to get in. Typically this was enough time for us to catch him but on more than one occasion we would find that he was in the bathroom attached to the master bedroom usually in the closet hiding. This went from being mildly annoying and kind of cute to being intolerable when once instead of heading to the closet he went  into the shower and tried to put a razor in his mouth. This incident led to a visit to the Home Depot to purchase a new door handle that could be locked from the inside and unlocked from the outside with a key or the equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far our precautions have worked to perfection. We are not as worried about him leaving the house or cutting himself with a razor or some other dangerous instrument. In fact our biggest challenge at the moment is keeping a stoic countenance in the face of hilarious queries, observations and other activity that is best not encouraged. Currently the biggest threat to his well being is an older brother that tends to play a little too rough or possibly the dog might finally snap and take revenge for the last year of prodding and tail pulling. That said it would be foolish for us to let our guard down too much. As a reminder that he has not given up on his dream of penetrating the security of mom and dad&amp;#8217;s room, a couple of days ago I found him with the key to the door trying desperately to open it. We keep the key on top of the thermostat which is down the hall from our room. He must have been watching us grab it and unlock the door to our room for weeks before he made his move. Although I didn&amp;#8217;t witness it, I am pretty sure that he took one of his toys and threw it at the thermostat until the key fell to the floor. When I found him he was on his tippy toes trying to put the key in the hole as his toy lay suspiciously on the floor directly under the thermostat. He was extremely upset and was not shy about it as I took the key from him and carried him away to the living room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, I anticipate a constant game of cat and mouse between the two of us for the foreseeable future. Any advice from any of you more experienced personal liberty violators would be welcome. I would appreciate hearing of your adventures in child rearing in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Days Survived</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/02/snow-days-survived/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/02/snow-days-survived/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a full week of sitting at home due to snow days, life returned to some semblance or normalcy today. At this time last week the sleet was already beating down on my roof. I always work from the home office on Tuesdays but it was pretty apparent that none of us would be leaving the house the next day. This proved to be true for the rest of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did venture out on Thursday mostly due to cabin fever. I drug Drew along with me to Best Buy and Walmart. Yes, its true, I broke my promise to never set foot in Best Buy again. My mouse had went out and I wasn&amp;#8217;t satisfied with the selection at Walmart. Also it was too dangerous to trek around the city with the roads being as they were, so I bit my tongue and went to the Best Buy right down the street from me. I guess I wasn&amp;#8217;t the only one wanting to get out of the house as Walmart was absolutely packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending another day sitting behind a desk in the Fort Worth club with headphones on to drown out the office noise, I wonder again why I am not allowed to work from home full time. In a conversation with my boss today, she mentioned how she got so much more done from home this last week than she is used to. I&amp;#8217;ve also heard that ExxonMobil isn&amp;#8217;t real fond of renting space for employees to work. So why don&amp;#8217;t we kill two birds with one stone. I&amp;#8217;ll just save myself the angst and stop complaining and be happy with the two days I&amp;#8217;m semi illegally enjoying at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>