<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Review on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>/categories/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Review on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Things Done – GTD</title>
      <link>/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>[Lists are how we track what we need to do] (/2013/07/29/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/) but this alone is not enough. Despite an abundance of technology available to help us keep track of tasks, many of us still keep these lists in our heads. We do this for a variety of reasons. They all have a common root. We don’t trust our system. We don’t actually believe that the list is the full list. We know that things have either been forgotten to be put on the list or were not important enough to track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of Getting Things Done – Lists</title>
      <link>/2013/07/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/</guid>
      <description>Getting Things Done is a task management system created by David Allen. Its purpose is to establish a framework for tracking tasks so that all necessary resources are available when and where they are needed. A primary focus is to ensure that the system can be trusted as the one source of anything that needs to be done. This is an overview of the system from my own point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfecting Sound Forever – Summary</title>
      <link>/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Edison invented the phonograph in 1877 in an effort to accurately record sound. He aimed to create a device that could document what was heard much the same way a photograph documented what was seen. It didn’t take long until it became apparent that the primary draw of the phonograph was not to document sound but to be entertained by it.
By the early 1900s, the phonograph was beginning to show up in private homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People’s History of the United States by Howard Zinn – Book Review</title>
      <link>/2011/04/book-review-the-peoples-history-of-the-united-states-by-howard-zinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/book-review-the-peoples-history-of-the-united-states-by-howard-zinn/</guid>
      <description>A theme is established at the beginning of the People’s History of the United States. It begins with Christopher Columbus enslaving, kidnapping and slaughtering the native Americans. It is continued with the African slave trade. It is represented by the protest of war after war, in countless labor strikes and the struggle of many different minority groups for equal consideration. Howard Zinn’s The People’s History is the repetitive recounting of the rich few subjugating the weak majority in the name of democracy, capitalism and freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poke the Box (Seth Godin) – Book Review</title>
      <link>/2011/03/book-review-poke-the-box-seth-godin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/book-review-poke-the-box-seth-godin/</guid>
      <description>[1][Poke the Box][1] is the first book published by the [Domino Project][2]. The book nor the publishing company is easily categorized. A little bit about the Domino Project. What I am reading is that the Domino Project is going to make it easier and faster to produce, promote and distribute books. This is being accomplished by a partnership with Amazon. It is not exactly clear to me how this is different than any other publisher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
