<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Review on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Review on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Things Done – GTD</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/07/29/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/&#34;&gt;Lists are how we track what we need to do&lt;/a&gt; but this alone is not enough. Despite an abundance of technology available to help us keep track of tasks, many of us still keep these lists in our heads. We do this for a variety of reasons. They all have a common root. We don’t trust our system. We don’t actually believe that the list is the full list. We know that things have either been forgotten to be put on the list or were not important enough to track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we can’t trust our system, we do what comes natural. We attempt to remember. We deal with issues as they come. The squeaky wheel gets the grease. That is until there is another louder squeak. This inevitably leads to stress and poor performance. The true genius of GTD are the procedures that help us manage lists. The integrity of our lists are what make the system trustworthy. To achieve this GTD is broken up into five different categories, Collect, Process, Organize, Review and Do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Collect
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It is essential that every thought, idea, request or demand that you have or receive be collected in a place that can be reviewed later. It is not necessary that you act on these items immediately but don’t be in a situation where you are forced to remember them. Always have a notepad and pen, a mobile computer or a voice recorder with you at all times. If you fail to collect tasks as they come you will lose faith in your system. If you are relying on your memory anyway, you will stop bothering with the system.  All of your tasks and notes should be deposited into a central Inbox so that you can process them at a later time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Process
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Most of us have way more to do than we could ever keep track of in our brains. It doesn’t really help to have a huge lists of tasks stored elsewhere either. At some point we need to organize the tasks into sections so that they are easier to manage. Traditionally this is done only when we are at our wits end. We throw up our hands and say “I’ve got to get organized.” We then stack the papers that are strewn about into neat piles and throw away anything not immediately identifiable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With GTD this is a daily process. The instinct is to leave anything that we’re not ready to deal with in the inbox whether its an email or a physical piece of paper. Before you know it your inbox is unmanageable and the scenario above is triggered. With GTD this is how tasks get into our lists. Each task begins its life in the inbox. At least once a day, the inbox is emptied by either transferring its contents to a list, the trash or to be archived as reference material.  We accomplish this one task at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each task in the inbox item is put through a series of questions. It is very important to process one item at a time. An item should never be returned to the inbox. Don’t pick and choose which ones to process. Take them as they come. Processing starts with a question. Is the item actionable? Can something be done about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  No
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  If the answer is no, then there is one of three choices.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    If it is trash, throw it away.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    If the required action can not be taken until some time in the future, then add it to your calendar.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    Some things are purely valuable as information. This information might be handy in the future but there is no immediate action that needs to be taken. We file these away in a bookmark, reference folder or archive the email.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Yes
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  If there is action to be taken, then determine if it is a single task or a project. Add projects to your projects lists.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to determine the next action. What is the next thing to do to further or finish the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the next action will take less than 2 minutes then just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise it needs to be added to a list. Are you the best person to perform this task? If so add the task to your Next Actions list. Otherwise, delegate the task to the person that is. Add the task to your waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Organize
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Keeping everything in its proper place establishes an order that gives us faith in the system. Lists are the proper places for a task. New unprocessed items belong in the Inbox. The name to identify multistep tasks are stored in the Project list. Tasks that are ready to be worked on are stored in the Next Actions list. Unfinished tasks that have been delegated are kept in the Waiting list. Projects or tasks that you may want to do in the future are stored in the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tasks don’t neatly fit into any of these lists. Some tasks can not be accomplished until some other condition is met first. It might be that a project can not be started until some other project is completed. On the other hand some tasks can not begin until a certain date or time. For these types of projects we have two different tools to ensure that when the time comes we are ready. These tools are the tickler file and the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickler file is essentially a reminder to deal with a task. You will be reminded of this task either during your weekly review or by checking your calendar. Here is an example. If you are a musician and you might think of a clever new trick you want to use in your next video. Since you are currently focusing on recording the song, it is not the appropriate time to act on it. You are not exactly sure when you will begin working on the video. The answer is to make a note of the idea and add it to the tickler file for the music video project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another method of ensuring that nothing falls through the cracks is your calendar. Anything that needs to be done on a specific date or at a specific time should be entered onto your calendar. It is recommend to use an online calendar with a good reminder system. Some tasks can not be completed until a certain date. For example, the tickets for the concert that you want to attend may not go on sale until a date in the future. Add a reminder to your calendar to purchase tickets on the correct date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  One of the most import aspects of the GTD system is also the most overlooked. Spending the time to refresh your memory on everything you have is the best way to ensure that none of it slips between the cracks. A review of everything in your system should be accomplished at least once a week. Some things will never be addressed until you have a review. Your tickler file and Maybe / Someday lists in particular are dependant on the review process. If you fail to review your system at least once a week, you will find that you stop using the parts of the system which require it. Your weekly review should consist of five different tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Next Action List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Look over each task. How long has the task been in the Next Actions List? Do you actually intend to do it? Be honest. Sometimes we have good intentions but when push comes to shove, it just isn’t going to happen. If you are not going to do it, then trash it. Things change. Has something happened since you added the task to your next actions list that prevents or discourages you from doing this work. Maybe now is no longer the right time. If you intend to work on the project but not right now, move it to the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common reason for a task lingering on the Next Actions List is confusion over what the task actually is. Typically this happens when your task is actually a project. Ask yourself what the next action actually is and update the task accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Project List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The review process is the time to evaluate the status of each of your projects. How many tasks are left to be completed? How far along in the process are you? It is not until after the review process that you can be confident that a project is completed. As with the Next Action List review, this is the time to ask yourself the hard questions. If no progress has been made on a project since your last review, it may be time to either trash it or move it to the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Maybe / Someday List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Of all of our lists, the Maybe / Someday list is the most dependant on the review process. This is where we store the ideas that we don’t want to forget about. Many of the projects that we are working on now will have some kind of impact on our future projects. While reading our Someday list, it may become obvious that a current project could be tweaked to include a listed idea. Update your project list or next actions as necessary and remove it from the Maybe / Someday list.  It is also possible that one of our current projects may nullify the need of a listed project. In this case remove it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we have ideas that seem brilliant as we are having them. We may decide to put them on the back burner. Later on, we wonder what in the world we were thinking. We no longer have any interest in the project. These should obviously be deleted. On the other hand, when one project is completed it is time to begin another. Our Maybe / Someday list is the obvious place to look for more work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another benefit to the review process. During this period, you will almost surely have new ideas. One project will remind you of another project that you want to undertake at some point. Occasionally, an idea from one project combines with an idea from another. When this happens a new idea is born, one that you may have never thought of otherwise. Although, you must be careful not to let your list get too big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer your list of ideas, the less likely you will be to review them. When a project has spent too long in your Maybe / Someday list, it could be time to remove it. This is obviously a judgement call. At a certain point you need to be honest with yourself. If five years have gone by and you still haven’t planted that garden in the backyard, you might need to consider that you may never do it. The finality of removing an idea from your Maybe / Someday list can be hard. It will clear up time and effort for projects that you will actually work on. This is true even if it is only during the review cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Waiting List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Almost certainly at some point, you will find yourself waiting for someone to finish a task before you can move on or complete a project. You may have a varying amount of influence over that person. You may have direct authority over some people. You may be able to directly set their priorities. You may have no authority at all over others. Your options will range from a kind word of encouragement all the way to dropping the project. At the very least, you’re waiting list is a good place to keep yourself reminded of who is holding up progress.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Calendar / Tickler File
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  You’re calendar and tickler files are like your own personal crystal ball. You can get a pretty good idea of what your future holds by looking at what you have planned. The amount of progress that  you’ve made since your last review will help you determine what you can expect. It may be necessary to change an appointment or modify a deadline.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tickler file is essentially a reminder with no specific date, time or task association. Without the review process a tickler file is useless. It might make sense to check the tickler file every day to keep this information as a constant reminder. The tickler file must be checked at least once a week to retain its value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-8217-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s Next&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparation is a waste of time unless it is followed by the actual work. In a future article I will write about [using goals][1]. I will also offer some tips on actually doing the tasks that have been planned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of Getting Things Done – Lists</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/07/29/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/07/29/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Getting Things Done is a task management system created by David Allen. Its purpose is to establish a framework for tracking tasks so that all necessary resources are available when and where they are needed. A primary focus is to ensure that the system can be trusted as the one source of anything that needs to be done. This is an overview of the system from my own point of view. This overview is derived from the knowledge I gained from reading the book and implementing it in my life. I highly recommend that you purchase and read the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-Free-Productivity/dp/B007J5D4QQ/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1471890232&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=getting+things+done&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done: The Art of Stress-Free Productivity&lt;/a&gt;. It is the definitive source for the processes and procedures of Mr. Allen’s system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gettings Things Done is typically referred to by its acronym, GTD. It is not a software application, nor is it contained in a physical binder or notebook. It isn’t even a product for sale. It is philosophy with a set of recommended procedures for simplifying the process of implementing a trusted project management system. Many companies and individuals have created tools to accommodate the GTD System. They come in the form of software or paper products designed to help implement the system. But all that is truly needed is paper, a writing utensil, a calendar and a method of binding multiple pieces of paper together such as a paper clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Lists
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  At its core GTD is a collection of lists. There are four types; Projects, Next Actions, Waiting and Maybe/Someday lists. A list might be comprised of lines written on a piece of paper or full pages bound together. For example your waiting list might either have five items you’re waiting on or five pages with an individual item on each page. Each list has a specific purpose.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Project:
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  A project is the name given to a list of associated tasks. To qualify as a project the list of tasks when completed should result in a related outcome. If any desired outcome requires that more than one action is taken, it is considered a project.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Similar tasks in certain situations could be considered a task or a project. For example “Email Cable company tech support” might be a project with multiple tasks such as; “search for company website” and “find email address on company website”. On the other hand if the other information is on hand the task might be “Email phone company technical support at email@company.com”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Next Action:
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  A next action is a single task that is the next thing that needs to be done to bring a project one step closer to completion. A next action should be clear and concise. If a task hangs around in your next actions list for too long, it’s probably because it is not actually the next action. If you are not quite sure how to do your next action, there is probably another step you are not listing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Not correctly identifying the next action is where projects typically get stuck. If your next action is “Fix the bicycle”, it would not be surprising to feel a certain amount of hesitation at performing this task. The reason is that it is difficult to determine the details. How long will it take? What tools do I need? Do I even have the tools? This is of course because “fix the bike” is not actually the next action. A better next action might be “determine what is wrong with the bike”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Waiting
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Some projects require work or input from other people, who don’t always respond immediately. It is very easy to lose track of a project while it is sitting in someone else’s inbox. That is why we have the waiting list. Keeping a task in a waiting folder accomplishes two things. It keeps a relic of the project in a place where we won’t forget about it. It quickly gives us the status of the project.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; It is not always people that we wait on. Sometimes a task is better left undone until a specific date. Maybe you have written an application that targets the next version of Microsoft Windows that is soon to be released. You would want to wait for Microsoft to release before releasing your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Maybe / Someday
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It is important to stay focused. You will never accomplish anything if you begin a large new project every day. At the same time, you don’t want to disregard an idea simply because you don’t have time for it at the moment. These types of projects should be kept in a maybe list. But be careful. You do not want to let your someday list get too big. If you are not able or inclined to review it then the list might as well not exist.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maybe list is also valuable for keeping track of things that you aren’t ready for yet. For example you might keep a list of books you want to read. Or you might keep a list of gift ideas.  Song titles, a storyline, partial poem lyrics, a business strategy, a marketing angle,  this is the place to store all of your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;Whats Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a logical way of storing the things we want to do in a list is not enough. Next I&amp;#8217;ll &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/&#34;&gt;describe the processes&lt;/a&gt; that are necessary to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfecting Sound Forever – Summary</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/04/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/04/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Edison invented the phonograph in 1877 in an effort to accurately record sound. He aimed to create a device that could document what was heard much the same way a photograph documented what was seen. It didn’t take long until it became apparent that the primary draw of the phonograph was not to document sound but to be entertained by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the early 1900s, the phonograph was beginning to show up in private homes. People wanted to listen to music. Edison’s phonograph found that it had a real competitor in the Victrola. The phonograph with its cylinders had superior sound quality to the Victrola discs. Victrola discs were cheaper and could hold more music. Cheaper and easier to use won out over high fidelity beginning a confrontation that would repeat itself over and over again through the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book Perfecting Sound Forever is essentially a history of these confrontations. It explains the different methods used to record sound by the technology which made them possible. Beginning with the already mentioned competition between the Edison Phonograph and the Victrola and continuing with live recordings of American musicians such as Ledbelly for the library of congress. We read over and over again about the opposition between those looking to perfectly record a performance and those looking to record the perfect performance that never actually occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major topic is the evolution of the recording studio. As the technology has advanced the tendency has been to improve the flexibility of the recording process sometimes at the expense of the audio quality. Recording equipment has evolved from the first two track recorders all the way up to 24 track dat tapes to finally fully digital software such as Pro Tools. It has changed from the mechanical ear of the phonograph to becoming a kind of instrument in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edison would roll over in his grave if he had seen what his invention had become. We no longer even aspire to accurately record sound. Today an artist at his computer is capable of creating music that couldn’t have even been dreamed of 100 years ago. The funny thing is that we are closer to being able to achieve the pristine world of only capturing the music that he dreamed about now than ever before. Ironically we have come to understand that the noise that surrounds music is the very thing that makes it sound authentic. In a world where computer software allows anyone to create a perfect sound, the recordings that are heard forever are the ones with an imperfect human touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People’s History of the United States by Howard Zinn – Book Review</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/04/19/book-review-the-peoples-history-of-the-united-states-by-howard-zinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/04/19/book-review-the-peoples-history-of-the-united-states-by-howard-zinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A theme is established at the beginning of the People&amp;#8217;s History of the United States. It begins with Christopher Columbus enslaving, kidnapping and slaughtering the native Americans. It is continued with the African slave trade. It is represented by the protest of war after war, in countless labor strikes and the struggle of many different minority groups for equal consideration. Howard Zinn&amp;#8217;s The People&amp;#8217;s History is the repetitive recounting of the rich few subjugating the weak majority in the name of democracy, capitalism and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Mr. Zinn, this book was written to look at the history of the United States not from the point of view of presidents, senators and founding fathers but instead from the eyes of native Americans, slaves, share croppers, the working class and women of all walks of life. I believe that he accomplished this goal. However, either by necessity or biased opinion it is also critical of America beyond any point of redemption. It is hard for me to imagine how the wrongs described in this book could be righted and still call the results America for there wasn&amp;#8217;t much said about America that was positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am completely in agreement with him when he says that there is no such thing as pure history. All history is told through the eyes and prejudices of the historian. This is carried out by the choices of inclusion and omission. This is a feature of not only every history book but every piece of written word. History is a weapon whether its aims are to instill patriotism or to incite riots. It&amp;#8217;s funny how depending on ones station in life the connotation of either may be negative or positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over and over again I read chronicles of people fighting oppression against all odds and paying the ultimate price. Depressingly, most of it was seemingly for naught. Most of the people who fought injustice did not live to see the results of their work. I learned that justice is not something that begins at the ballot box, nor the house of representatives, nor any court of law. The abolishment of slavery, the right to vote, education for all, child labor laws, the minimum wage and hundreds of other privileges that we consider our birthright were not initiated by any of those institutions.  They were achieved by ordinary people protesting over a prolonged period of time. It took people willing to give up their own freedom and often their lives in hopes of improving the lives of those that would come after them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll not try to recount the contents of this book as I don&amp;#8217;t feel that I am capable but I will say that reading this book was emotionally draining. I felt a wide range of emotions as I read: pride, outrage, pity, denial but ultimately shame. I was forced to admit to myself that no matter what Mr. Zinn&amp;#8217;s intentions for writing it, I believed almost all of it to be true. I also recognized my complicity in the state of the world that I live in and my unwillingness to take any action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now live in a world where 1% of the population of our country owns 90% of the wealth. The rich expect the rest of us to subsidize their extravagant lives and most of us are not only willing servants but outspoken apologists for our masters. Some like myself are well taken care of. With such a lifestyle its hard to complain, it is likewise hard live with myself as people starve all over the world. Yes, history is a weapon and it has been used to teach me that I am a true blue, apple pie American and I deserve prosperity more than the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poke the Box (Seth Godin) – Book Review</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/03/18/book-review-poke-the-box-seth-godin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/03/18/book-review-poke-the-box-seth-godin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[1][Poke the Box][1] is the first book published by the [Domino Project][2]. The book nor the publishing company is easily categorized. A little bit about the Domino Project. What I am reading is that the Domino Project is going to make it easier and faster to produce, promote and distribute books. This is being accomplished by a partnership with Amazon. It is not exactly clear to me how this is different than any other publisher. Granted I am not an expert in the publishing industry but the books still have to be written, edited, produced and then distributed don&amp;#8217; they? Doesn&amp;#8217;t every publisher already follow this model? I am very impressed with the ideas of Seth Godin and have faith that this project is highly innovative and am pretty sure that it&amp;#8217;s me that just doesn&amp;#8217;t get it.  Hopefully someone out there can explain the difference to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poke the Box is a manifesto on initiative. The ideas in this book are mostly common sense practices that nobody seems to have the sense to make common. Mr Godin urges us to move past fear of failure, ridicule or whatever else may be holding us back and not only start something but finish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like past books such as Linchpin, he makes the case that it is becoming increasingly impossible to succeed by attempting to do things faster and cheaper. Instead he encourages us to stand out, be unique and to take risks. His claim is that the world has evolved to the point to where not risking failure is actually a bigger risk than to attempt something that has never been done. This can never be accomplished without, to use his term, shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shipping is the act of distributing whatever product that you have created to the customer. Many of us are walking, talking idea factories. Most those ideas exposure to the world is primarily the &amp;#8220;what if&amp;#8221; conversations held over lunch or some other social situation. The book suggests that these ideas don&amp;#8217;t make it past the lunchroom conversations because the person with the idea is waiting for someone to give them permission to take the next step. Once they have permission, procrastination or supposed realism prevents them from actually taking a chance. People seem to require support from ,investors, employers or some other authority figure in the form of money, marching orders or encouragement  before they will take action. Ironically, inaction is more likely to cause the very results that they intended to avoid in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially the entire book is a manifesto expressly giving the reader the permission to not only begin but to also finish and ship the ideas that they feel passionately about. As a person who exists with a constant barrage of noise constantly flowing through his head, the idea of focusing on an idea to completion is both obviously logical and terrifying at the same time. I am the textbook example of the ambitious individual who has started a million projects and finished none of them. This book, even though it may not have been the intent, has caused me to understand that my behavior is a permanent trap. It will not be until I choose and focus that I will be able to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poke the Box is a short book that should probably be shorter. The primary point, which is that starting on something only has meaning by finishing it, is made early and often. This does not take away from its value in the least. The repetition is unnecessary to most but I must admit that reading the last page was disappointing as I didn&amp;#8217;t want it to end. I believe that if everyone took these ideas to heart the world would be a much different place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>