<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erik.craddock.org/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erik.craddock.org/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s All A Cliche</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2013/02/its-all-a-cliche/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2013/02/its-all-a-cliche/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;embed-youtube&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center; display: block;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share another song that Rodney Craddock and I have recorded. It is called It&amp;#8217;s all a cliche. My dad, Larry Craddock, is once again playing lead guitar. This time, my mom, Samie Craddock,has  also made a huge contribution. She wrote the lyrics. I received an email from her seemingly out of the blue last November. It included a poem that she had written one day while she was in a particularly cynical mood. That poem became the lyrics for the song it’s all a cliche. Along with the lyrics, mom sent me instructions to make any changes we deemed necessary. She also encouraged me to take full credit, which I obviously refused to do. We did make changes but very few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her original idea was to create a poem comprised of the opposites of overused phrases. For example instead of “two wrongs don’t make a right”, she would say instead “two wrongs make a right”. It was a great idea but in my opinion, the poem was inconsistent. Some of the phrases expressed the opposite while others did not. I invoked my right to make changes by including only the overused version of each phrase. The end product is very similar to mom’s original lyrics but not exact. We did reorder a couple of the verses and changed two lines completely. I only mention these changes to keep the record straight. Any lyrical inconsistencies are almost certainly my fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think she expected us to put them to music with a more country flavor. After all, everything we have done up to this point has leaned in that direction. Both Rodney and I were ready for something different. We wanted to do something a bit more rock and roll. I had a tune in my head that I thought would fit. I first played it for mom and then for Rodney. They both liked it. To be honest, I wasn’t so sure but their approval was enough. I’ve gone back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny how these things work. Mom may have written most of the lyrics. I may have written most of the music. But Rodney has been this songs champion. When I wanted to scrap the music and go with something different he convinced me not to. He was right, this seems to happen to me every time. At some point in every project, I think to myself “this sucks, I’m no good” blah blah blah. I’m learning to tune it out. I’m running on the assumption that it’s better to do something than nothing. I tell myself that everything is a learning process and the best way to improve is by making mistakes. So you might as well get busy making mistakes. When I have had doubts it is usually Rodney who encourages me to keep on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this song Rodney handled the main vocals, bass and digital drums. I recorded both rhythm guitar tracks and helped out a bit with background vocals. For the lead guitar part, we recruited Dad. I wanted to get someone else’s take on the song and you can never go wrong getting Dad to play. The song is sort of split in two. There is an intro, two verses and a chorus. This format repeats after a pause. Initially, we asked Dad to record a solo during the repeat of the introduction (if that makes any sense). We also asked him to solo at the end over the chorus music. After some trial and error we decided we liked hearing a solo over the chorus music much more than the intro. We ended up adding another frame after the chorus and leaving the second intro with rhythm guitar only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of situations are kind of stressful as they are happening. You always worry about offending someone or starting a fight. An “I don’t like a solo there” can easily be heard as “Your solo sucks and so do you”. You have to run on the assumption that the guys you are working with aren’t jerks. Thankfully we all trust each other. It’s pretty easy to takes statements in their best light instead of their worst. The arguments and criticism are both the toughest and the most memorable parts of the process. They are also the difference between an average recording and a great one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far the toughest part of this song for me has been the video. Rodney usually handles most of it. This time I tried to lend more of a hand. Unfortunately, in doing so I only caused more work. This song is about living life on autopilot and getting caught up in the flow of everyday life. I can’t help but think of white collar America and my corporate day job. I’m the one who suggested that we dress up in suit and ties for the video. I drove to downtown Fort Worth and recorded backdrop videos of busy streets, parking garages and the fronts of impressive looking buildings. I also took some video of us driving down the road. Don’t worry, Linda handled the driving duty while I operated the camera. I’m sure people thought i was crazy with a camcorder held out the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, Rodney and I would be playing while wearing suit and tie in front of the green screen. We had other plans for Dad. We had him dress up like a hobo and play his part with an open guitar case in front of him. The idea was that we would put him on the street as if he were playing for change. To my shock he didn’t protest. We each submitted our performance to Rodney and he got busy making the video. He worked his tail off and created the video that we had both signed off on. I didn’t like it at all. He must have been ready to kill me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t really the video that I didn’t like. As usual, Rodney did a great job especially with the quality of material he was given. It was the costumes. It sounded like fun during the planning process but it was nearly impossible to implement on our budget of practically nothing. I thought that all three of us looked silly and the reason for our costumes wasn’t very obvious. Of course it could have just been me being insecure again. Rodney wasn’t able to talk me down this time. Truthfully, he didn’t try very hard. Either he agreed with me or I had already worn him down with other complaints. Regardless, we each videoed ourselves again but this time we nixxed the costumes. The video that Rodney created is pretty much the same except it now had the new footage of us playing replacing the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been over two months since we have shared any music. It’s not that we haven’t been playing but for one reason or another, we haven’t been ready to release it. In my opinion, each recording that we do sounds better than the last. After every project I have learned a little more about recording, engineering and mixing songs. I hope you all enjoy listening to this song as much as I did recording it. Please let me know what you think. If you like it, I’d really appreciate it if you shared it with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erik Craddock&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Otis Ray?</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some things quite clearly belong in this world. They come to us in a variety of different packages. We have experienced them at some point with all of our senses. They are easy to identify. When you see them, even for the first time, it is familiar. The taste and smell is pleasant. You could swear that you’ve heard them before. It just feels right. That is how I perceive art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that good songs sound familiar is because they already exist. The musician does not create the song, he discovers it. This is accomplished by a process of elimination. Revise, Play, Destroy. Repeat this process until the noise gives way to music. There are an unlimited supply of songs out there just waiting to be discovered. They are rarely found with ease. There are no more free standing pools of songs for Jed Clampett to discover with a mere shotgun blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otis Ray was not discovered quickly or easily. We started over several times. We made every mistake in the book and nearly quit. Without a sense of accountability to each other, I am convinced that we would have quit. A few other things saved the song. It’s content has obvious sentimental value that we were reluctant to give up on. Also we told ourselves from the beginning that we were not in a rush, so there was less pressure. The biggest reason, in my opinion, was that we took a break in the middle to record an easier more lighthearted song. We came back to the Otis Ray project with some confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song began with Rodney writing verses about his father, JW Craddock. These were mostly his childhood memories. He planned on writing a song for his dad. He was a bit reluctant to show me the unfinished lyrics. I offered to help put them to music so he relented. I read them and knew immediately that this would be a great song. However, it needed changes. I was a bit nervous to make suggestions since it was so personal. For instance, initially all of the lyrics were written about his father. I suggested that the words be directed to him instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other lyrical contribution was the title. Initially the song was called “The Old Man”. The title didn’t sit with me well. I asked Rodney for any nicknames that his father had. He told me a story about a boxing match they had watched together years earlier. The bout was between one boxer named Odis and another named Otis Ray. The fight quickly turned into a comical back alley brawl as the fighters began trading low blows. From that point on, Uncle JW began calling Rodney Odis which of course resulted in him being dubbed Otis Ray. It stuck. Years later, they were still calling each other by the nicknames, nearly forgetting the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a collector of ideas. I keep lists. I have lists of short stories I want to write. As I have mentioned before I collect potential song titles. I have lists of books I want to write, products I want to create, businesses I want to start, etc. I also keep quick and dirty recordings of melodies, riffs and other musical ideas. The titles I give these recordings range from a sort of onomatopoeia like ‘blee blah duh’ to what instrument it was recorded with. The name I gave to the riff that became Otis Ray was ‘some acoustic new’. It barely resembles the song we ended up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the lyrics that Rodney gave me and I applied them to the music that I had previously recorded. I took my favorite two verses he wrote and transformed them into a pre-chorus and chorus. As usual, I recorded a demo with me playing the guitar and singing. After crossing my fingers, I sent them to Rodney. I wasn’t sure what to expect. It could have gone several ways. He could have been offended or worse apathetic. To my relief he loved it. Of course there were several changes that he wanted to make, mostly to the lyrics. He did make one major change to the way the chorus was structured. With his improvements, we had ourselves a song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, our first mistake was basing everything around a guitar riff. In theory one should be able to play with a metronome and everything would be in time. In practice, that doesn’t work very well. We had a completed song that sounded ok, but something just wasn’t right. I would focus on my parts and hear little mistakes here and there. I would re-record my parts and send them to Rodney. He would do the same. I kept telling myself that the problem was with the mix or some other technical issue that I was inexperienced with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I had begun recording another song, &lt;a title=&#34;A Good End to a Great Time (part one)&#34; href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/24/a-good-end-to-a-great-time-part1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bad End to a Good Time&lt;/a&gt;. This was done during a period of time when the work on the Otis Ray project was in Rodney’s court. When I was working on Otis Ray, he would work on Bad End. It was becoming obvious that Otis Ray was going nowhere. It still just sounded wrong. For a time it appeared as if ole Otis Ray was destined for a life of receiving low blows in a back alley brawl. We ended up finishing Bad End first. There was a moment right after we pushed out the song that we nearly abandoned Otis Ray. Ironically, it was saved when we decided to scrap everything and start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney had been working on the project for a couple of weeks. He had recorded, erased and re-recorded every track he had originally created. It still didn’t sound right. He finally threw his hands up and gave me everything he had to see what I could do with it. I did the same, I re-recorded my parts but something was still off. I finally determined to get to the bottom of the problem. I began listening to tracks. The rhythm guitar and bass were good together but when I listened to them individually with a metronome they were off. It finally occurred to me that the issue was that every current track had been recorded along with the bass. The bass however had been recorded to match the original riff which had long been erased. Guitar riffs are rarely precise. In fact what made this particular riff good in the first place was it’s “looseness”. Riffs are meant to be played along with a backing track not vice versa. To top it off, I wasn’t even playing it the same anymore. With a sinking heart I realized that the we had to start over completely from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I recorded a rhythm guitar backing track first. I made sure that I had no timing issues. I sent it to Rodney and waited. What I received back a few days later completely restored my faith. Rodney had added vocals, a bass track and drums. Up until this point we didn’t have any drums at all. In fact it had been a source of worry for me. I knew we would never have a complete song with no drums. We knew a couple of drummers and even had one of them record drums for Bad End. The problem was that all of them were too busy. The music we were recording wasn’t a very high priority to any of them. That became less of an issue when Rodney discovered the Independence Free midi drum composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been much of a fan of computer generated drums. They always have this mechanical sound that isn’t acceptable to me. We were able to avoid this by keeping things simple. Rodney spent a lot of time tweaking the drums so that it gave us a good beat without being in your face. He told me about a feature that he used that is supposed to humanize the drums. I’m not exactly sure how it works but in my imagination it intentionally screws up every now and again. I got excited about this song for the first time since the beginning once I heard what Rodney had done with it. The drums in particular did the trick for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got busy with the rest of the guitar tracks. The more we recorded the less we used the original riff I had written. It began as the driving force of the song. By the time we were done it was only used for a measure at the beginning and end of the song. It’s funny how sometimes the very genesis of an idea can be the biggest hindrance in its completion. In the end we ended up with one bass track, one vocal track, two rhythm guitar tracks panned opposite of each other, a lead guitar track and a midi drum track. Rodney was responsible for the mix of the song. I couldn’t begin to explain the effects that were added to each track. I know that he balanced the volume envelope of each one and added compression where it made sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that was left was the video. Let me just say this about making videos, I hate it. Thankfully my partner in crime does not. The only credit I can take in the video production department is offering Rodney challenging material to work with. In my opinion, the video that he created for Otis Ray is the best to date. It is a kind of video / image collage of his father who is after all the subject of the song. I love that Rodney tries to add something new. I initially resisted the train scene while I was playing the lead part, but we showed it to several people who liked it. I finally concluded that I was not best suited for make video decisions. I only wish I could have given him better material to work with. I am going to get a green screen for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney videod his part in his backyard standing in front of the lake. He then added some kind of filter to the footage which turned out pretty good. All of the pictures were from Rodney’s own collection of family photos. The old videos were supplied by my father, Larry Craddock. It was footage of the 1992 Craddock Family Pitch tournament. Rodney is seen sitting next to his father in many of the shots. I think he was 18 or 19 years old at the time. If you look closely, I am in the very last shot standing in the back with a baseball cap on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have lots of old footage like the one used for this video. Our family is very close. Growing up, we lived next door to each other. Rodney and I grew up more like brothers than cousins. Uncle JW was like a second father to me and my father was the same for Rodney. Even though this song is without a doubt Rodney’s homage to his father. It isn’t hard for me to exchange those pictures into ones of my father as well. At the same time, I definitely learned my fair share of lessons from my Uncle JW. To me, ending the video with that unique laugh of his is perfect. He seemed perfectly comfortable at the center of attention amongst family. He jokingly called for everyone to clap for him. As you can see Uncle Jay, we are still clapping for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bad End to a Good Time</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/a-bad-end-to-a-good-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/a-bad-end-to-a-good-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rodney Craddock and I have been recording music together almost constantly since I &lt;a title=&#34;A 3 year old Storm hit Montgomery, Tx&#34; href=&#34;http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;visited his place&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago. While I was there, we threw our first song together in pretty much one day. We wrote the song and recorded all of his parts while I was at his house. We turned on the video camera. We recorded as we played and Rodney used that footage to create a video. After I got home, I finished things up. The result was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5-mEgWeH-w&amp;feature=plcp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a little tune about my dog Sugar’s lack of fondness for bad weather&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had such a great time that we began working on another song. This time Rodney had some lyrics that he had thrown together. He shared them with me and I made a few suggestions. The next thing I knew we had written the most country song ever. Due to the subject matter, which I can’t disclose yet, it had to be that way. Country isn’t really my thing but here was this song that was as country as it gets. And somehow I wrote the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, every time I picked up my guitar it wouldn’t make a sound that didn’t twang. I decided that I would get even. The ball was in his court in the recording process and I was left with nothing to do. I started writing what I hoped would be a country cliche song. I must admit that I got the idea from Mick Jagger. I might not have moves like Jagger but I was hoping to write a song like his. My inspiration was the song Dear Doctor on Beggar’s Banquet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, my song only had a couple of verses. They could be sang on top of the Rolling Stone’s song exactly. This would never do. My never ending twang box came to the rescue. I began playing and ended up with the primary riff. I tweaked the first two verses and wrote the third. Next on the agenda was a chorus. The first thing that came to mind were the first two lines. Since the first line was about living it up, it only seemed natural that something needed to come down. But it still felt like there was something missing. Every good country song needs a catchy title right? Well, it so happens that I’m always on the lookout for a good song title. I keep a list of them. I’m constantly jotting down lines from things that I hear or think about. In fact I just copied down the title “Never Ending Twang Box”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the title “Bad End to a Good Time” from a conversation that I had with my father. We were talking about my nephew Brody. He had recently either broken his pinkie or his collar bone. Both injuries happened pretty close together. Poor kid couldn’t use his left arm or his right hand for a little bit there. It must have been his pinkie because that was the first of his playground injuries. Mr. Brody is a little super star at baseball. He plays first base and he and his team ain’t foolin around. They win most every game they play. Dad was telling me how much Brody loved to play ball. I said something like “man, that sucks, I bet he was disappointed.”. Dad responded with “yeah it was a bad end to a good time”. Ding, ding, ding, I wrote it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title sat in a list until the day I started working on the chorus for this song. Everything just kind of fell in place. I plugged in a microphone and pressed record. Typically, I record a little demo so that whoever I am working with can get the gist of the song. I don’t consider myself a singer at all but I have to give the tune to them somehow. So I started up a Reaper project and began. I recorded two acoustic guitar tracks that were nearly identical except for slight deviations here and there. I panned one to the left and the other two the right. No effects on either track. I then began laying down a vocal track. I didn’t intend for us to keep any of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first vocal track was horrible. It was too awful for me to even give out as a demo. So I recorded it probably 10 more times. I wasn’t happy with any of them. I took the best take of each phrase for the entire song and used that as a track. It was still pretty bad. In the process, I noticed that if I played two of the best takes on top of each other it obscured some of the badness. So I created two new tracks which were both a kind of a ‘best of’ from the nearly ten recordings that I made. I must admit that it didn’t sound too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction to the demo I had recorded was to play it for Rodney. I had written it in the first place to amuse him. I had even added some extra twang in my voice for the demo. Problem was that he was super focused on that other song. He didn’t want to get distracted so he told me he’d listen to it later. Despite the fact that the song was a joke, it was kind of growing on me. I had to admit that I liked it. I wanted to play it for someone so I sent it to my parents. My mom really liked it to my surprise. I was worried that she wouldn’t approve of the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to finish recording the music. I had a friend come over and record a drum track. He was having computer issues so we made an even trade. He recorded my drum track and I fixed his computer. A win win for everyone. When the ball was back in my court for the other song, Rodney was ready to work on Bad End to a Good time. He recorded a bass track and a temporary backup vocal track. Wait, backup vocals? I was totally against using my demo vocals. They were horrible. He didn’t agree. He thought mine were good. We eventually settled on using a lead vocal part from both of us. He would sing the first line of every verse and I would sing the last line. We both sang the middle two lines and the chorus. I recorded harmony vocals throughout the rest of the song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tweaked levels and frequencies and put effects on nearly all of the tracks. I also normalized and added compression to all of the vocal tracks. There was only one thing missing, a slide guitar. Dad sent me several different slide tracks but none of them matched what I heard in my head exactly. I didn’t want to tell him what to play but at the same time I had a vision. In the end I took the four different slide tracks he sent me and I cut and pasted the audio until I had the performance I wanted. The hardest part was deciding what to use. There was so much slide goodness in there that it was tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next came the video. Lord I hate videos and the feeling is mutual. I always look like an idiot on film. I haven’t been very focused on videos. My point of view is that the music is what is important not the video. I do recognize that everyone listens to music directly off of Youtube. In order to upload to Youtube there has to be a video of some kind. So typically we have always just turned the video camera on while recording the tracks. It is a kind of kill two birds with one stone approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a problem this time. I hadn’t recorded video for either the guitar or vocal parts since I didn’t intend on them being the final take. This meant that I didn’t have any video of me. So I grabbed the guitar turned on the song and played along with it all Milli Vanilli style. I made sure that I played the guitar parts without screwing up through the entire song and I sang during my parts. Rodney does the video so I sent it over to him. I didn’t even bother watching it, lest I lost my nerve. I gotta admit I think I look stupid in the video but you live and learn. I’ll do better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad was smart and sent video of his actual performances. He even used a green screen. Rodney recorded his parts and put the video together. He is getting better and better at doing them. With some better footage to work with who knows what he could do. I think next time we are going to focus more on the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had a great time working on this song. Every part of the collaboration was done remotely. None of us were in the same room together at any point of the process except for the drum track. My friend Scott recorded that in one take on my son’s drum kit. We used a digital audio workstation software package called Reaper. We shared the project and wave files over Google Drive and discussed our plans with a combination of audio, text and video chat software. I spent many hours fiddling and tweaking the mix. I still have a long way to go but I learned a lot about recording music on this project. I hope you all enjoy the song. If you have any comments or criticisms I would love to hear them. The critical comments are especially helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-634&#34; title=&#34;erik&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://erik.craddock.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/erik-150x150.jpg&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.caradoc.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/erik.jpg&#34;&gt;http://erikvancraddock.caradoc.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/erik.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it possible to sell sound?</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept of property can get complicated. We have plenty of laws regulating it. In fact, the idea of private property is at the heart of our way of living. It seems fair that if you work hard creating something, then you should own it. That isn&amp;#8217;t always possible, and some things cannot be owned at all. Or at the very least, it would be silly to consider owning them, for example a cloud, rain or air. What about sound? Does one own the sounds he makes? Can you sell sound? When you speak, you create sound. A few people actually put a lot of time, energy and thought into what they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you own sound waves? Can you forbid someone from repeating your words? Can you sell your spoken words? Can you demand compensation for those who have heard your words?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is mostly yes, if those sounds have been recorded. This logic kind of falls apart in a live setting. If you give a speech, you do not own the sounds you make. You can&amp;#8217;t forbid anyone from uttering the same words. You can not even charge anyone for hearing the sound. You can only restrict access to the location you speak from so that only authorized ears are in range to hear. In a sense you are restricted by physical property for what you can and can not charge. Instead of a sound being stored on a cassette, disk or thumb drive forever, it is stored in a geographic area or inside of a building for only a moment. Therefore you can not charge for those sounds. You can only charge for access to the sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also cannot make someone pay to hear sound in a public place. How silly would it be if you walked down a public street singing a song and demanded that everyone who heard pay? But what if it was a song you worked very hard to create? What if your performance was the best that had ever been heard? Doesn’t matter right? Now what if someone recorded your performance on the public street, can you charge them now? It is ridiculous to think that someone could charge for something that was knowingly released to the public. In this sense public is not a designation. It is a description. If something is reasonably accessible by all people, then it is public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never had to consider these issues before. We have never directly paid for sound. Instead, as I mentioned, we buy access or we purchase containers that sounds are stored in. Records, 8 tracks, tapes and CD’s are all physical items that are inherently scarce and therefore have a value. You are free to sell the item you own for whatever price you can get. The radio however is a different thing entirely. If a song is broadcasted publicly over a radio frequency then whoever is able to hear it should be able to do whatever they want with it. This would be no different than recording someone playing a song on a street corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is no different than the radio. The radio is no different than someone speaking in public. Only the scope of the broadcast is different. Some of these network are password protected. Some radio frequencies are encrypted. This does not make the networks or radio frequencies private. The raw Internet or Radio network is still accessible to anyone in range. It simply means that the tools necessary to make sense of them are protected. As an example think of this in terms of the person speaking in public. It would be as if he spoke in a another language to protect his words. He might offer a class in that language to grant access to the meaning but the words themselves are free to be consumed by anyone in range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is made up of private servers all over the world. On their own the data on these servers is private. However once it becomes part of a public network then that machine is accessible by any machine on that network. The data that is shared between machines is public. The Internet is not the machines themselves but instead it is all of the connected networks. Each individual server is privately owned and its files are private. They can and should be secured. However if a private file is released on a public network can we reasonably expect it to stay private? The accessible data on the network is public in the same way that the radio is public. The radio signal is useless without a receiver but it is nonetheless available to all in range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything becomes confused when we consider digital items. Digital items are pieces of data. The data itself is in demand, people want it. But here is the real question. What exactly is data? Can I pick a piece of data up in my hands? What does it look like? Data is an abstraction. It does not physically exist, it is only a concept, an idea. Data is like sound, it only has meaning when processed through the brain. You may be able to speak in an unfamiliar language but you can not prevent people from hearing the sounds unless they are out of range. I can understand paying for a device which makes it possible to access data, like a radio receiver. I can understand paying for the method of making sense of data. I can even understand the rate of payment being based on the amount of data I access. But if you broadcast data over a public network, then it has become public property. If I have a password, can decrypt the security, or understand the secret language then I should be able to use it as I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think that we are missing the point entirely. What exactly is the point of granting or denying access to all of this data? When it comes to music, do we want the container or the music it contains? In the days of physical media, the tape, CD, etc., offered a service. Without the physical item it was impossible to hear the music. With digital files, all the music in the world is instantly available but denied to the listener who doesn’t pay. As I said, data is a concept. It is impossible to make it partially available to the public. Once it is out there, the only way to secure access is to threaten violence, incarceration or fines. Would we punish someone for understanding words spoken in public because they didn’t learn the language from an authorized source?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it could be argued that the Internet is not a public forum since one has to pay to access it. I would disagree, you have to pay for a newspaper. You don’t pay for the news mind you, you pay for the actual paper. You pay to access information, not for the information itself. The government recognizes the newspaper as a public forum for public notices. If a band is authorized to play a song in a public location they can not charge admission. The preferred method of compensating the band would be a donation. This allows each person to judge the value and give the band the data they need to determine whether it was worth their while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using force or threats to demand payment for a public resource is extortion. It doesn’t matter that you made the resource public. The legality of your action doesn’t change the definition of extortion. The Internet is attractive because it is used by the public. Publishing your song or any other information on the Internet and then demanding payment is no different than singing in a public park and demanding payment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfecting Sound Forever – Summary</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Edison invented the phonograph in 1877 in an effort to accurately record sound. He aimed to create a device that could document what was heard much the same way a photograph documented what was seen. It didn’t take long until it became apparent that the primary draw of the phonograph was not to document sound but to be entertained by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the early 1900s, the phonograph was beginning to show up in private homes. People wanted to listen to music. Edison’s phonograph found that it had a real competitor in the Victrola. The phonograph with its cylinders had superior sound quality to the Victrola discs. Victrola discs were cheaper and could hold more music. Cheaper and easier to use won out over high fidelity beginning a confrontation that would repeat itself over and over again through the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book Perfecting Sound Forever is essentially a history of these confrontations. It explains the different methods used to record sound by the technology which made them possible. Beginning with the already mentioned competition between the Edison Phonograph and the Victrola and continuing with live recordings of American musicians such as Ledbelly for the library of congress. We read over and over again about the opposition between those looking to perfectly record a performance and those looking to record the perfect performance that never actually occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major topic is the evolution of the recording studio. As the technology has advanced the tendency has been to improve the flexibility of the recording process sometimes at the expense of the audio quality. Recording equipment has evolved from the first two track recorders all the way up to 24 track dat tapes to finally fully digital software such as Pro Tools. It has changed from the mechanical ear of the phonograph to becoming a kind of instrument in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edison would roll over in his grave if he had seen what his invention had become. We no longer even aspire to accurately record sound. Today an artist at his computer is capable of creating music that couldn’t have even been dreamed of 100 years ago. The funny thing is that we are closer to being able to achieve the pristine world of only capturing the music that he dreamed about now than ever before. Ironically we have come to understand that the noise that surrounds music is the very thing that makes it sound authentic. In a world where computer software allows anyone to create a perfect sound, the recordings that are heard forever are the ones with an imperfect human touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of Music Appreciation</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was young, the music that I was allowed to listen to was strictly limited by my parents. Any music purchases must first go through an approval process. The cover art was the first obstacle. My mother would look over the tape cover with a suspicious eye. Anything with pictures of demons, drugs,  or violence was out. Anything that might otherwise suggest the devil’s handiwork would quickly get put back on the shelf. The same held true for any slight suggestion of sexuality. It’s not hard to imagine how many titles were restricted for this rock n roll fan in the early 80’s. Next, the song titles were scrutinized. The same rules applied as with the cover art; no drugs, sex, demons or violence. It was harder for her to check the lyrics. That is until that damnable woman Tipper Gore convinced the record labels to put a big black label on the album that said “EXPLICIT LYRICS”. Those two words were the purchasing death nail of many albums I desired. On rare occasion, I was able to sneak something through that wasn’t entirely squeaky clean. Once I was finally permitted to purchase an album it became a treasured possession. By the time I was a teenager with a job, I bought whatever I wanted and learned to hide my treasures. When this became the norm, the approval process was turned on its head. I actively sought out many of those Explicit Lyrics labeled albums. My album collection became a representation of me and how I viewed myself, instead of the idealized version of me that my mother wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Music Appreciation as a hobby
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have changed alot since then. I can remember hanging out with my friends with the express intention of listening to an album. Listening to music was the thing we did together. We would dissect each album. I knew what equipment was used, how the guitars were tuned and the backstory of the lyrics usually. We liked to compare the musicians from this or that band. We knew the names of each album and all of the songs. To this day I remember the lyrics to most of the songs on those albums and can name the band, track, album and release year after hearing the first measure. I don’t think we were the exception to the rule. Nearly everyone listened to music that way. It doesn’t seem to happen any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the line music has become the soundtrack for whatever else we are doing. It gives us something to sing along with while we’re in the car. It plays softly while we are at work.  Music has degenerated into our last defense against boredom. It is no longer something we do but instead it is background noise that guards against silence. Silence makes people uncomfortable. They nearly always find something to say instead of allowing it. Music is a nice convenient way of drowning out the possibility of having those forced conversations. Have you ever been in the car with someone who turned the music up so loud that you had to scream to talk to them? My favorite trick is headphones. I listen to music or books all day while wearing headphones. People are hesitant to talk to you while you are wearing them. Nothing says, “Please don’t disturb” quite like a good pair of headphones. The over the ear variety are even more effective. Somehow music has gone from connecting me to other people to helping me avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It’s hard to hold a digital file
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did listening to music go from being the main event to a mere sideshow act? I think that there are several reasons. One of the big ones is that there is now nothing physical to cherish. There is nothing to touch. Every album feels the same to my fingers, exactly like my mobile phone. It is all ones and zeroes floating inside a mini computer. Before when I bought an album, I physically possessed it. It was mine and which ones I owned said something about me. I could only have so many with me at any one time. The albums I kept on hand defined me, especially while in my car. If I wanted to play music for a friend, I had to choose carefully what albums to bring. What I listened to was a representation of my musical tastes. My music collection was tangible proof of that. I can now keep as many albums as I want. There is no space limitation and no penalty for having even the worst music on my digital player.  I may never listen to an album ever again and still have it on hand &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; without even a slight inconvenience. This seems like a good thing at first, but in reality it has trivialized the process of owning music. Many of us don’t even bother owning it anymore, instead we subscribe to music services which allow us to listen to what we want, when we want. It is much easier to take it for granted when it is so quick and simple to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Singles discourage innovation
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This constant access to music has lead to the habit of listening to singles instead of albums. We  now only listen to the equivalent of mix tapes, a personal greatest hits collection. The only problem is that this music is usually curated for us. We listen to what a computer algorithm tells us we will like. At best our friends suggest songs that they liked which the computer suggested to them. Albums in the past were meant to be listened to straight through. The single was essentially a gift we received via the radio to help us decide if we wanted to hear the entire album. You didn’t know which was your favorite song on an album until you listened to them all. The single got you through the door, the album helped you decide if you would stay or ever return again. Some albums ended up in our car and some ended up at the used record store. But now people mostly want to listen to singles. This requires that every song is available for individual purchase. It means that every song has to stand on its own. Musicians are in the business of selling music. No matter how much artistic integrity they have, ultimately they need to pay the bills like the rest of us. How many songs are now scrapped that don’t have an obvious market? Can you imagine if all of the tracks on Pink Floyd’s The Wall had to stand on their own? Even though the cost of creating a fully realized song is much lower, the time commitment is still substantial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  There is too much music
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor is competition. The cost of doing business has reached the point where anyone can start a band, record music and market it to the world for very little money. Of course these things alone do not guarantee success. It does guarantee that anyone can throw in their hat and try. This is another thing that seems like a good thing but has a negative impact on how we listen to music. In the past, it was so expensive to record that a band needed someone to fund their recording sessions. Record labels would invest in bands who obviously filled a market. Even though this process probably stifled creativity in general, it ensured for the most part that the music would be decent. Of course this depends on your tastes but the point is that there was less out and out bad music. The gatekeepers are now falling to the wayside. More and more musicians are picking themselves instead of waiting to be chosen by a record label. This has caused an entirely new problem, there is too much music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many bands, it is almost impossible to be heard. You have to really stand out to find any kind of mass audience. Signing with a major record label is still the best way to ensure that you will find an audience but ironically record labels want to sign bands who already have an audience. The latest strategy is for a band to give their music away to remove any kind of reason for fans to pass them by. This has created a race to the bottom, turning singles into nothing more than advertisements. The strategy seems to be to gain enough of a following so that record labels will want to sign you. The result has been that fans are given the impression that they are doing the band a favor by listening to their music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The Music Industry is dead, long live the music industry
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the problems that I have pointed out are the direct result of technological changes that we consider innovations. How do we determine if a change was a positive one? In my opinion, to be deemed positive it has to improve the fans experience. The truth is that technology is almost always used to make things easier. Sometimes getting something easy just makes us lazy. I am not suggesting that we turn back time and go back to physical media. In order to succeed, bands will need to overcome these issues. In order to do this we must realize that the game has completely changed. I’ve read that the era of super bands like the Beatles is over and that the success of the future is only making a living. I don’t believe it. Mega successful bands will always exist as long as they connect listeners with music that moves them. The fan must respect and maybe even envy the musician. These people have the almost magical ability to manipulate our emotions with their creations. It’s hard to respect someone when you feel like you are doing them a favor by granting them your attention. It’s hard to cherish a possession that doesn’t actually exist. It’s even harder to pay for what is out there for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe that the problems I’ve mentioned are fixable. More than likely music will never again be primarily sold enmass in physical packages. I wouldn’t be surprised if musical compositions ceased to be sold at all. Music will become more accessible, not less. The idea of the personal music collection will be explained in history books next to the section on cassette tapes. People will continue to listen to mostly to curated music in the background.  The music industry as we know it has already died, we just don’t realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The successful band of the future will involve its audience in every way imaginable. The fans contribution to the project will cloud the line separating the band from its audience. By combining social networking, crowdsourcing and crowdfunding, musicians will join with their fans to produce music that is meant to be enjoyed by those who created it. This band will give their fans more than a souvenir, it will give them a voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/music-appreciation-decline.jpg&#34;&gt;http://erikvancraddock.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/music-appreciation-decline.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 3 year old Storm hit Montgomery, Tx</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The family and I made our way down to Montgomery, Texas a few weeks ago. We stayed with my cousin Rodney and his girlfriend Erin for nearly a week. Our goal was to convince them that they should never, ever for any reason have children. Not that there was any talk of kids. Ethan was only too eager to help prevent that conversation from ever happening, ever. Drew made a beeline to the back room where he holed away to play the XBox, rarely to be seen again. Linda had planned all sorts of fun stuff for us to do together. On the agenda was the NASA museum, the Houston Aquarium and Galveston beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got no sleep at all that first night. Erin kept me up all night goading me into arguments that I wanted no part of. To make it worse, she resorted to cheating to win these arguments using all sorts of nefarious psychology tricks that she learned from this book or that. Rodney and Linda just laughed at us. They didn’t sleep either though so the joke was on them too. Despite all of this, we got around and headed to the NASA museum that next morning. At first I was as eager as a teenager heading out on an adventure, sleep be damned. That lasted until Ethan came running into the room whooping and hollering while running in circles around the room. He desperately wanted to play with Erin’s dog Patches. Patches wasn’t too fond of children especially ones who insist on playing with his toys. He just wouldn’t leave the dog alone. My suggestion to just let him get bit and get it over with was ignored. The poor dog was exiled to the back room until the boy went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so our routine was established. We stayed up too late at night only to regret it the next morning as we drove through the depths of the city with headaches. I must have driven through Houston rush hour traffic a dozen times as my passengers gripped handles, seats or each other with white knuckles. Not the boys though, they kept themselves entertained as they always do, annoying each other. We all had a great time. I won’t bore you with a bunch of details about our tourist activities except for a little about the beach. I’m sure that all of you who care have already seen the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We timed our trip to the beach perfectly. There was a storm in the gulf that hadn’t yet made it to Galveston. This left us with perfect swimming weather, still in the 90’s but not burning hot. Linda and I got a kick out of watching the boys experience the beach for the first time. Drew stripped to his trunks and began his attempts at mastering the waves with a boogie board. Ethan in a rare moment of caution just stared as if trying to understand this strange body of water. He would wade into the water and then hightail it out of there as the waves crashed towards him. By the end of the day we were taking turns dragging him kicking and screaming back to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The storm hit that night and it rained all the next day. Rodney and I spent the entire day singing and playing music. We had left our dog Sugar with a kind neighbor who offered to feed and shelter her while we were away. Sugar isn’t so fond of the rain. Linda was worried about how she was handling it. I was pretty sure I knew exactly how she was handling it and so we wrote a song about it. I figured everyone needs a corny half blues toon about their dog. So that is how we spent our day. All in all it turned out pretty good. I arranged the tracks we had created once I was home and Rodney synced it up to the videos we recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to head home the next day. Both Linda and I were pretty sure that we had definitely worn out our welcome. Of course Rodney and Erin swore they were sad to see us go. They insisted that we should return soon. I’m sure they both let out a big sigh of relief as we drove away. Ethan held up to his part of the bargain that week. I think we just about convinced them that kids were just too much trouble. If Drew hadn’t been so well behaved all week, I think we could have sealed the deal. Linda, the kids and I don’t get to go on adventures like that very often. We sure picked a great place to go this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili, beer and music at the Lanier’s</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/05/chili-beer-and-music-at-the-laniers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/05/chili-beer-and-music-at-the-laniers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent last Saturday night drinking beer, eating chili and writing music at the home of Nathan and Misti Lanier. Linda and I had been looking forward to a night with adults away from the kids for some time. Unfortunately Linda was inflicted with a sinus infection and ended up staying with her parents along with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m never sure what to expect from a songwriting session. They can go in a lot of different directions. Sometimes you get so caught up playing that you lose the whole day just jamming while never quite finding that perfect hook. Other times you come in with a catchy riff that never seems to fit quite right. There are plenty of potential pitfalls so you learn to appreciate the ones that go off without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything went off without a hitch Saturday. I had spent the last week recording everything that came to mind. I had riffs, melodies and even songs that inspired me. I knew that Nathan and Misti had been working on lyrics and I was just hoping to make any kind of contribution. To my surprise they liked the first riff I played for them. It ended up being the basis of the song we worked on. We didn’t even bother with anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misti is an excellent songwriter. She has a notebook full of beautiful lyrics and each has a melody that goes along with it in her head. She tells me that it is always a bit strange to hear her lyrics put to a different tune. Nathan and I pushed that to its limit this time. Misti isn’t the biggest fan of loud guitars and rock music. When I first played the guitar riff to them, it was on an acoustic guitar and had a kind of bluesy feel. By the time Nathan was done with it, we were full on rocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since everyone agreed last week that I get to decide which song we record, there is a good chance it will be this one. This video was taken sometime either late Saturday night or early Sunday morning. Watch it and let me know what you think. Does the song have potential?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Embanded meeting will be on Thursday at 6pm this week. Our intention is to have it on Tuesdays but neither Erin nor Dad can make it tonight so we’ve postponed it.  Thanks again to Nathan and Misti for putting up with my long winded slurred speeches and outlandish opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My History with Music</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/04/my-history-with-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2012/04/my-history-with-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My History with Music nearly ended twenty years ago when I decided to throw my lot in with the working folks. After high school I decided that college was a waste of not only my time but my parents money. I knew for a fact that I would shrug off class and spend all of my time in more lively pursuits. I figured I could do that without the pretense of school. As ridiculous as it sounds, I thought I was being responsible. Not going to college turned out to be one of the smartest decisions I made as a teenager. I followed it up with one of my worst, I joined the Air Force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  In the beginning
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things I ever did was ask my dad for a guitar. This might not seem like a big deal but it took all the courage I could muster. In my family, playing music was like breathing, everyone could do it, but my dad was the best. I grew up listening to my uncles and cousins. Family gatherings quickly turned into concerts. Those not playing cards were serenading those that were. Most everyone could play the guitar or the piano. No one seemed to think twice about singing a little ditty. This all seemed completely normal to me but playing the guitar was another matter entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad was the electric guitar gunslinger of our family. He was the rocker. While my uncles were playing songs by Hank Williams, dad was trying to mimic Johnny Winter or Jimi Hendrix. It seemed inconceivable that I would ever be able to muster even half his skill. I  feared becoming a  watered down version of my father. So the act of requesting a guitar was akin to a declaration of war. In my mind, we would eventually face off in a guitar duel for the ages and I would emerge victorious. But first I would need to learn some open chords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received that first guitar when I was fifteen. A cheap pearl white Peavey Patriot, it quickly became my best friend. At first I took lessons at a music shop in Oklahoma City. My Uncle Dan would come by once a week and take my cousin Rodney and me. I can remember my first lesson vividly. Rodney went first as I waited in the hall. I picked around on the Peavey while picturing myself on stage. Finally, it was my turn. The instructor&amp;#8217;s name was Robert.  My memory is probably full of creative inventions but I remember that he looked like a member of an 80’s hair band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Learning to Play
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still picture Robert with long black permed hair wearing leather pants and a white laced half unbuttoned shirt. I was sure that he was a rock star philanthropist giving back to aspiring musicians. Rodney and I were convinced that he would take us under his wing. We believed that he would impart upon us the secrets of rock-n-roll super stardom. That first day we didn’t do too much rocking, mostly he taught me the basic notes on a guitar fret. I did learn my first open chord, G. With an encouraging word and a reminder that I should be able to strum the notes clearly when I returned, I was dismissed. And it began. After that first lesson I knew I had found my calling. There was no doubt in my mind that this is what I would do for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was obsessed. All I wanted to do was play my guitar, and I played constantly. It could not have been pleasant. My mother must have been horrified but she never complained that I remember. She rarely asked me to stop, usually only when she was talking to me and I was staring through her instead of listening. I never tired of playing my guitar, but it didn’t take long for me to tire of my rock god guitar instructor. He had strange habits, for instance he would mouth “three four, three four” to help me keep time as I played. I’m not sure what happened to one and two but obviously they were unnecessary to wordlessly keeping time. On top of that, one of the first things he taught me to play was Sweet Georgia Brown which shattered my heavy metal impression of him. He finally resorted to just asking me what I wanted to learn to play.  After the 3rd lessons of that, I decided to go it on my own. Except I was never alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The Band
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney and I had been inseparable since we were children. From the moment we started taking guitar lessons together, there was no doubt that a band would follow. We spent much time critiquing music and arguing the merits of the different musical acts of the time. We were soon joined by my brother Pete on the drums. Dad bought Pete a cheap five piece kit that he used to drive everyone insane. If my guitar playing was annoying, Pete’s drumming was maddening He played at one volume LOUD! I can imagine everyone on the hill wincing as we began practicing together. We all lived on a 5 acre patch of land at the top of Binger hill. Only family members lived there but there were a lot of us. I have good memories of that hill, many of playing music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fourth member was my cousin John on the bass. I’m not sure that he really wanted to play the bass. But he was four years our younger and willing to do whatever was necessary to be included in the ranks of the ‘older kids’. This definitely had its advantages. Need someone to test the home made zip line stretching down into the canyon floor? Not sure how bad being shot by a bb gun will hurt? Need a bass player to complete your garage band? Well, John Paul was our guy. He was about 12 years old at the time and not very big for his age. That bass guitar was bigger than he was. He took it seriously though and learned quickly. We all learned quickly. Before long playing for ourselves was not enough. We needed an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid there was a teenage nightclub that my mom allowed me to attend. It was an old church located out in the country that had been converted into Teen Town. It was the sole exception to the “NEVER LEAVE TOWN” rule that had been insisted upon by my parents for Friday and Saturday nights. This place was the perfect alibi for a teenage troublemaker. It was easy to slip in and out of with no one being the wiser. Since there were always a million kids there, it was difficult to keep track of us all. It was primarily frequented by every young girl in the county who liked to dance. Every young girl in the county just so happened to be our target market. It seemed they all liked to dance. It was the perfect venue for our fledgling little band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris, the owner of Teen Town, knew my parents since he had purchased computer equipment from their computer sales and repair business. When I approached him about allowing our band to play at Teen Town, he was all for it. He even offered to let me use his acoustic guitar for the ballads we intended to play. The solid black, hand made Alverez with a cutaway and built in electric pickups was beautiful. I was in love. I convinced him to trade the guitar along with an amplifier for a Tandy 1000 computer and printer that I received for my 16th birthday. At the time the computer and printer retailed for more than the guitar and amp, but I still own that guitar. I doubt Chris still owns the computer. From that moment on, the Alverez was my most prized possession. I’m sure that every girlfriend I ever had was a bit envious of it. I even took my Senior picture with that guitar. Thankfully my wife has learned to co-exist with my most prized possession. It is practically a member of the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were very excited about playing in front of a live audience. We began practicing every spare second we could muster. To further cater to our intended audience, we named our band “Yours Truly”.  Yes, we have been teased about the name for the last 20 years but it seemed like a good idea at the time. Everything was coming along nicely until the unthinkable happened. Rodney got himself grounded. I don’t remember the details but I remember that I panicked. John Paul came to the rescue. He had been taking guitar lessons from a kid who went to school in a nearby town. John couldn’t say enough about how awesome his teacher played the guitar. He suggested we recruit him. My only reply was “How do we get to his house?”, and off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan was never technically a member of the band. He did not want to answer to Yours Truly. I had seen him cruising around Binger in his IROC-Z but we had never spoken. With that long hair and reputation for rocking out on the guitar, he wasn’t your typical Caddo County country boy, or so I assumed. We first met when John and I made the trek out in the country to his house. I knocked on the door of his house and politely introduced myself to his mother. After asking for him, I was directed to a pond next to their house where he was busy fishing. He may not have looked like a country boy but he acted like one. I’m still not sure why he agreed to play with us. We were very obviously a bunch of novices. I think he just wanted to play in front of a crowd. Rodney’s punishment only lasted that one day but we were still very happy to have Nathan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  [mudslide:picasa,0,evcraddock,5735773265361272513]
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The Gig
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally our big day arrived. Everyone but Pete who had a “I’m good with whatever happens.” attitude seemed nervous. I always envied him that but I’ve had little success copying it. At one end of the building was a small raised platform, where a pulpit must have once sat. As we setup our equipment, kids danced to pop music. I always associate Teen Town with the boy band New Edition. I looked out at the audience and with a pit in my stomach. I realized that my social standing could drastically change. I looked over at Nathan and Rodney and could see that they both were thinking the same thing. When I looked over at John Paul, he just had a big smile on his face. He didn’t care either way. He was excited to play music with and for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After what seemed like an eternity, it was time to begin. Our opening song was “Shook me all night long” by AC/DC. Maybe I was wrong about Pete not being nervous because he set the tempo like a sprint. Not a long song to begin with, it was over in no time. After that we settled down. To Nathan’s horror we had chosen almost all songs by the popular hair bands of the time. We played songs by Poison, Warrant, Great White and others. We had a good time. For a first gig things went pretty well. People applauded after each song, boys and girls danced together on the slow ones, and there was no heckling that I remember. I was later disappointed to realize that my social standing changed little, if at all. None of the girls I knew showed any more interest in me than before. That is not to say that the night ended without drama. Our musical debut was merely cool to the kids, it was the adults who were horrified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before my parent knew the owner of Teen Town. After being emphatically denied an invitation to see us play, they ignored it and snuck into the show. They even conspired with Chris to setup a video camera in the sound room away from view. They were shocked from the opening number. They found Brian Johnson’s lyrics about exploits with a fast machine inappropriate. The rest of our set list didn’t meet any better approval. They were appalled! We were lucky they didn’t stop the show on the spot and whisk us home. I was able to feign ignorance. After all I didn’t have to learn the words to play the guitar. In fact I claimed that I was too concerned with my own parts to even think about the lyrics. Rodney was the singer and he didn’t get off as easy. Claiming to not understand the sexual references and innuendo was hard enough but there was no getting past the cursing. Looking back, we sure did get him in a lot of trouble. We all survived, even Rodney, but the video recording did not. It took years before I had the courage to ask to see the footage that would recall our moral betrayal. By that time my sisters infatuation with all things New Kids on the Block struck. Desperate for a VCR tape to record a concert on TV, our performance was overwritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The rest of the story
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly that was the highlight of my music career. Our little band played at Teen Town twice and for a talent show at school once. I never stopped playing the guitar. I was getting pretty good at it. However, the closer I came to graduating high school the more pressure I received to choose a real career.  I had decided long ago that I would play guitar for a rock band. I wanted to  play in front of thousands of screaming fans. Unfortunately, I was not stupid. It was easy to dream of becoming a rock star while sitting in the back of English class. The dream became more and more unrealistic the closer I came to being responsible for my own well being. I knew what the life of a musician was like. I had been told ever horror story on record. I was also not blind to the lives of working stiffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to resist. I moved to northern California and landed a job at a full service gas station. My spare time was spent meeting new people. My intention was to work days and play music by night. But I hated that job and I missed my family. It didn’t last three months before I returned home. By the time I got home I had determined to give college a try after all. My grandmother lived a few blocks from a community college in Oklahoma City where I could enroll. I had no idea what I would study. Something to do with computers I assumed, besides it would be only temporary. Something to fall back on in case my music career faltered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought of going back to school depressed me. I had just spent four years in high school and I was about to start all over. Getting a job and living with my grandmother was just too much. I knew it wouldn’t work within a week. One day as I drove through the city looking for a job, I passed by an Air Force recruiting office. With a high ASVAB score and no police record, I was a prime candidate for military service. The recruiter was happy to see me. I joined that day, settling for a job as a cryptologic linguist because it sounded something like being a spy. The truth is that I had no idea what to do with my life. Even small amounts of adversity had discouraged me. I took the easy way out, the military was a safe choice. Once I began I could not easily quit. I assumed that I wouldn’t go hungry and hey I might get to see the world. When my enlistment was over, military service would look good on a resume. My parents could be proud of me. Most important, I could get away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At seventeen years old, I had a dream. The older I got the more ridiculous that dream seemed until I finally abandoned it. I chose my career as if it were for sale in a mail order catalog. “This week only&amp;#8230;  a life of playing music with a less than slight chance of becoming rich and famous. All for the low low price of a minimum of five years as a starving musician. Side effects may include alcohol and drug dependencies. Buyer beware, no guarantees, all rights reserved, not valid in Alaska and Hawaii.” It’s no surprise that I chose something a bit more secure. Thank god I didn’t choose the life of a musician as I perceived it at the time. I’m much better off as a stereotypical white collar office worker. I didn’t understand that I could write out that job description anyway I chose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still rewrite it whenever I’m ready. In fact, having lived nearly forty years, I am in a much better position of knowing exactly what it should be. I can set the details any way I choose. If I want to play music I can.  “But you’re too old to go gallivanting about!”, I’ll leave that part out. “Night clubs and bars are no place for married men!”, I won&amp;#8217;t include them in my plan. “You can’t afford to quit your job!”, in that case I’ll keep it. “But you can’t possibly succeed otherwise.”  The way I see it, I can’t possibly fail. I get to decide what constitutes failure and I see no need to pre-define those parameters. I should have thought of this when I was seventeen. I would have excluded not only the starving musician part but also the unwanted dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, I have decided to work with a team to redefine what it means to be a musician on the Internet. I know too many talented people who have abandoned their dreams. Too many whose audience consists of four walls in a room of their house. And frankly I am not satisfied with the music that is fed to me.  I am not exactly sure where this project will lead but I promise to share what I learn every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disciple reunion at Trees</title>
      <link>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/04/disciple-reunion-at-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erik.craddock.org/2011/04/disciple-reunion-at-trees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not often that Linda and I have a night without the kids so having a full weekend to do what we pleased felt very foreign indeed. This all came about thanks to a late 80&amp;#8217;s metal band. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Christmas, instead of adding to the ever increasing pile of toys, trinkets and equipment in Drew&amp;#8217;s room, we decided to give him three months of Drum lessons. I scoured the internet looking for the best instructor I could find that wasn&amp;#8217;t too far away. Eventually with the aid of a music instruction head hunting company I found the perfect drum instructor. I think Drew was a bit disappointed at the time because there really wasn&amp;#8217;t anything for him to open. He basically received a card that informed him of the gift. However, it didn&amp;#8217;t take long before his opinion changed drastically. Drew is taking to drums like a fish to water with a lot of the credit going to his instructor Scott Rainey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the many impressive items on Scott&amp;#8217;s resume is that he was the drummer for a heavy metal band in the late 80&amp;#8217;s named Disciple. Back then his band was a pretty big deal in the Dallas / Fort Worth area where I live. I was also impressed to learn that they toured with the band Pantera of whom I was a pretty big fan.  One of the clubs that his band frequently played at was called the Basement. As it turns out Trees in Dallas decided to have a reunion show for a lot of the bands that used to play at the Basement and Scott&amp;#8217;s old band Disciple was invited. Scott in turn invited Linda and I to attend the Disciple Reunion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously a night club that caters to the desires of heavy metal music connoisseurs is probably not the greatest place for children. If we wanted to go, our first mission would have to be getting rid of our pesky kids. Linda met my parents half way between our house and theirs in Wichita Falls, Tx and made the exchange freeing ourselves a whole weekend to behave irresponsibly. I went wild. I took all the baby gates down and rebelliously only latched the bottom dead bolt which only a day prior could have resulted in the unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday night we took the hour long drive to Trees in Dallas and went inside not exactly sure what to expect. We arrived at about 8:30 PM before the crowd was very big which allowed us to find a good place to sit. The club is bigger than it looks from the outside. The bar was easily accessible and the stage was visible from almost everywhere in the building. There were two levels with the top being where Linda and I settled sitting comfortably enough on bar stools with a clear vision of the stage. A little further down from us was a door marked &amp;#8220;band members only&amp;#8221;, however, the rule didn&amp;#8217;t seem to be well enforced. All sorts of interesting people went through those doors, some of whom we later saw on stage and others not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the bands that we saw would have been called &amp;#8220;hair bands&amp;#8221; had age not confiscated their hair. A couple that still had hair might not have come by it naturally. Much to my amusement some of the singers could still hit those high notes. However many of them seemed to just be reliving the glory days and several were staggering around drunkenly before they ever made it on stage. It would be a crime not to mention the singer of Hill Billy Orchestra who was a huge man that required the use of a stool due to his size. Nevertheless, he was quite animated on his stool and managed to keep me in stitches the entire performance. At one point he pulled out a Cheech and Chong sized blunt and alternated between mock smoking and playing it like a guitar. Another notable performance was the beer bellied singer who strutted around without a shirt acting like a horribly misguided sex symbol. When he wasn&amp;#8217;t pelvis thrusting in the general direction of the audience he was falling into his guitar player who managed to anticipate his drunken blunders as if he had experienced this many times before. Even with some of the hilarious antics all the bands played well and a good time was had by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciple was slotted to play at 10:30 PM. The bands that played before them were mostly your classic pop metal hair bands of the 80&amp;#8217;s with upbeat tempos and party themed songs. One of the bands even played an acoustic set. Having heard a couple of Disciple songs in the past, I knew that anyone expecting more falsetto Judas Priest like screaming were in for a huge ass kicking.  Finally Disciple took the stage and the pummeling began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Lehmann looked pissed like he was just waiting for someone in the crowd to cross him. He is a big guy with a shaved head. The way he doubled gripped the microphone and screamed out the lyrics gave you the impression that you&amp;#8217;d be best served by listening and paying attention. Al Ward who has been a constant fixture to the Deep Ellum music scene for quite some time shredded the guitar like the professional that he is. The riffs he played were dark and relentless. In the past Disciple had been a three piece band with Dan playing the bass along with his singing duties. This time however, in order to allow him more freedom on stage Todd Heazux was asked to play along with the original lineup. He performed his duties with precision despite only having practiced with the band for a few weeks. Finally there was the reason we were there in the first place.  Scott Rainey&amp;#8217;s drums were a steady eruption of double bass madness. It&amp;#8217;s difficult to comprehend how it is even possible to move ones arms and legs as quickly and methodically as he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music of the preceding bands offered little warning for what happened when Disciple took the stage. Some of those bands seemed like a group of has beens trying to relive the glory days. Not Disciple, they seemed more like serious musicians determined to be heard and respected. I am personally extremely impressed and honestly quite shocked that this band didn&amp;#8217;t take over the world back when they were first touring. After hearing them live I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be surprised in the least if that injustice were not rectified soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>