<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It’s All A Cliche</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/02/its-all-a-cliche/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/02/its-all-a-cliche/</guid>
      <description>Today I’d like to share another song that Rodney Craddock and I have recorded. It is called It’s all a cliche. My dad, Larry Craddock, is once again playing lead guitar. This time, my mom, Samie Craddock,has also made a huge contribution. She wrote the lyrics. I received an email from her seemingly out of the blue last November. It included a poem that she had written one day while she was in a particularly cynical mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Otis Ray?</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/11/who-is-otis-ray/</guid>
      <description>Some things quite clearly belong in this world. They come to us in a variety of different packages. We have experienced them at some point with all of our senses. They are easy to identify. When you see them, even for the first time, it is familiar. The taste and smell is pleasant. You could swear that you’ve heard them before. It just feels right. That is how I perceive art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bad End to a Good Time</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/a-bad-end-to-a-good-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/a-bad-end-to-a-good-time/</guid>
      <description>Rodney Craddock and I have been recording music together almost constantly since I visited his place a few months ago. While I was there, we threw our first song together in pretty much one day. We wrote the song and recorded all of his parts while I was at his house. We turned on the video camera. We recorded as we played and Rodney used that footage to create a video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it possible to sell sound?</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</guid>
      <description>The concept of property can get complicated. We have plenty of laws regulating it. In fact, the idea of private property is at the heart of our way of living. It seems fair that if you work hard creating something, then you should own it. That isn’t always possible, and some things cannot be owned at all. Or at the very least, it would be silly to consider owning them, for example a cloud, rain or air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfecting Sound Forever – Summary</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/perfecting-sound-forever-summary/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Edison invented the phonograph in 1877 in an effort to accurately record sound. He aimed to create a device that could document what was heard much the same way a photograph documented what was seen. It didn’t take long until it became apparent that the primary draw of the phonograph was not to document sound but to be entertained by it.
By the early 1900s, the phonograph was beginning to show up in private homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of Music Appreciation</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>When I was young, the music that I was allowed to listen to was strictly limited by my parents. Any music purchases must first go through an approval process. The cover art was the first obstacle. My mother would look over the tape cover with a suspicious eye. Anything with pictures of demons, drugs, or violence was out. Anything that might otherwise suggest the devil’s handiwork would quickly get put back on the shelf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 3 year old Storm hit Montgomery, Tx</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/a-3-year-old-storm-hit-montgomery-tx/</guid>
      <description>The family and I made our way down to Montgomery, Texas a few weeks ago. We stayed with my cousin Rodney and his girlfriend Erin for nearly a week. Our goal was to convince them that they should never, ever for any reason have children. Not that there was any talk of kids. Ethan was only too eager to help prevent that conversation from ever happening, ever. Drew made a beeline to the back room where he holed away to play the XBox, rarely to be seen again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili, beer and music at the Lanier’s</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/05/chili-beer-and-music-at-the-laniers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/05/chili-beer-and-music-at-the-laniers/</guid>
      <description>I spent last Saturday night drinking beer, eating chili and writing music at the home of Nathan and Misti Lanier. Linda and I had been looking forward to a night with adults away from the kids for some time. Unfortunately Linda was inflicted with a sinus infection and ended up staying with her parents along with the kids.
I’m never sure what to expect from a songwriting session. They can go in a lot of different directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My History with Music</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/04/my-history-with-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/04/my-history-with-music/</guid>
      <description>My History with Music nearly ended twenty years ago when I decided to throw my lot in with the working folks. After high school I decided that college was a waste of not only my time but my parents money. I knew for a fact that I would shrug off class and spend all of my time in more lively pursuits. I figured I could do that without the pretense of school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disciple reunion at Trees</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/04/disciple-reunion-at-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2011/04/disciple-reunion-at-trees/</guid>
      <description>It’s not often that Linda and I have a night without the kids so having a full weekend to do what we pleased felt very foreign indeed. This all came about thanks to a late 80’s metal band. Let me explain.
For Christmas, instead of adding to the ever increasing pile of toys, trinkets and equipment in Drew’s room, we decided to give him three months of Drum lessons. I scoured the internet looking for the best instructor I could find that wasn’t too far away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
