<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to overcome burnout</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/07/23/how-to-overcome-burnout</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/07/23/how-to-overcome-burnout</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt like doing shit. It has been impossible to get motivateed to do anything of value. What normally excites me, now seems like a chore. I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to care. In short, I am burned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-causes-burnout&#34;&gt;What causes burnout?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupational_burnout&#34;&gt;Burnout&lt;/a&gt; is a form of depression caused by stress due to work. It is usually associated with working too much. A stereo typical scenario might involve an employee that spends too many straight hours working on a project. Because of this, he fails to maintain the proper work-life balance and gets worn out. He is unable to show passion for his work and the quality suffers. The traditional solution is to take more frequent vacations and learn to balance work and life more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this scenario is plausible, even typical, there are plenty of exceptions. There are people who dedicate their every waking moment to work without experiencing burnout. We celebrate them. There is a long list of celebrities from sports stars to CEOs that admit to spending as many as 13 hours a day working. How do they avoid burning out? What makes them different from the reset of us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the cause of burnout is not working too many hours. Rather, it is caused by not making meaningful progress in your work. It happens to me for these reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;my-goals-seem-unreachable&#34;&gt;My goals seem unreachable&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am constantly in the middle of some big project. I&amp;rsquo;ll get excited about something, start working on it, and eventually fizzle out. To fight against this tendency, I organize. I set goals and make plans to achieve them. I decide at the beginning of each week what I intend to accomplish. Unfortuneately, I usually end up biting off more than I can chew. In theory, I will get better at breaking big tasks into small tasks and prioritizing them. In practice, I sometimes get stuck. For whatever reason, I can&amp;rsquo;t accomplish the task. Maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t know how or where to even start. When weeks go by without much progress, I get discouraged. Doubt creeps in and the easiest thing to do is nothing at all. Netflix and Steam here I come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to over come this is through planning. First, don&amp;rsquo;t think about the big picture during the week. Don&amp;rsquo;t second guess yourself. Do your work even if you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it. Next, if you don&amp;rsquo;t finish a task on time, break it down into smaller tasks. Most of the time we get stuck because we aren&amp;rsquo;t sure what to do next. Finally, be honest with yourself during your weekly planning session. If several weeks have gone by and you still haven&amp;rsquo;t progessed, drop it. Quit, you aren&amp;rsquo;t that into it. You will feal much better and you can focus on something else that you obviously care about more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;i-can-t-control-something-i-care-about&#34;&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t control something I care about&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is much like not being able to reach a goal without the goal. When something bad happens to you or to someone you care about, it can feel like the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;not-eating-right-and-getting-enough-exercise&#34;&gt;Not eating right and getting enough exercise&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>