<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I consume the Internet</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/06/29/how-i-consume-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/06/29/how-i-consume-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am an information junkie. I go from one obsession to the next. The Internet deals me out a constant supply of articles, images, music and video on any and every subject I can imagine. It is very easy to get sucked in. If I&amp;rsquo;m not careful I will find myself reading about some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theapricity.com/forum/showthread.php?178939-8-Most-Bizarre-Religious-Rites&#34;&gt;obscure religious rite&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.nationalgeographic.com/2016/06/seahorse-reproduction-behavior-conservation/&#34;&gt;mating habits of deep sea creatures&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/u/55503/Electric-Monk&#34;&gt;Neuromancer fan fiction&lt;/a&gt;. Every subject is represented. There are niche groups living within niche groups. Unbelievably, there is just too much information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/04/how-i-replaced-google-reader-with-pinboard/&#34;&gt;dealing with this issue&lt;/a&gt; for a long time. We all deal with it to varying degrees. It is necessary to limit ourselves or we will be on the Internet all day. Some of us have to go to work and food is nice from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do we deal with it? We can&amp;rsquo;t just ignore it. Every year, more jobs revolve around data from the Internet. My job certainly does. I am a software developer, a field that is constantly changing. If I don&amp;rsquo;t keep myself informed, I will soon find my skills irrelevant. It&amp;rsquo;s not just my job that is effected. In fact, almost every aspect of my life is improved by consuming information on the Internet. What is the best music or movies out right now? What advances in technology have been made? How much are Bitcoins selling for? Will George R.R. Martin ever relase the next Song of Ice and Fire book? Pretty sure the answer is no, he&amp;rsquo;s just going to let HBO write it for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
### Past attempts at solving the problem
 Below are a few.

* **Google Reader**
    was my RSS reader of choice until it was shutdown in 2013. Each day, usually in the morning, I would scan the posts of each feed and star anything that looked interesting. This supplied me with an almost never ending list of posts to read. My favorite features was Reader&#39;s ability to view the contents of a post from within the application. It stripped out most of the formatting and the ads and left me with simple readable text.

    There were a few drawbacks. It wasn&#39;t always possible to view a website from within Reader. Video was not supported. Also it wasn&#39;t possible to star articles from outside of a feed subscribed to through Reader.
* **Pinboard / Twitter**
    was how I initially replaced Google Reader. Pinboard is an application that allows you to create bookmarks by tagging links on the Internet. The primary feature that convinced me to use pinboard was it&#39;s ability to interact with other applications. There were several plugins that worked with popular web application. One of them was a Google Chrome plugin that let me mark any article that I came across as something I wanted to read later. The primary way that I discovered new content was Twitter. I followed people who wrote about subjects that I was interested in and bookmarked them. I could then get a list of articles that I wanted to read on Pinboard.

    Pinboard&#39;s mobile application allowed me to view simplified versions of my bookmarks much like Google Reader. Unfortunately this feature wasn&#39;t implemented for the web application. I had to open each site in a new tab and remember to close it later. The other problem with this solution was Twitter. Even though everyone posted links to their Twitter stream, they also tweeted random thoughts and other texts that I had to sift through. I eventually looked for a new solution because this one was just too much of a pain in the ass.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am faced with a horrible realization. There isn&amp;rsquo;t enough time in the day to consume everything on the Interet that interests me. I must limit myself or at least be more efficient. To maximize my time, I have devised a system for managing all of the articles, videos and images that I want to view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-tools&#34;&gt;My Tools&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS Reader&lt;/strong&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goread.io/&#34;&gt;GoRead&lt;/a&gt; is an RSS reader that was created to replace all of the funcitonality of Google Reader, which was shutdown in 2013. Where most RSS readers that I have found try to be everything for everyone, GoRead does one thing good. It lets you subscribe to and view RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bookmark Browser Plugin&lt;/strong&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/save-to-pocket/niloccemoadcdkdjlinkgdfekeahmflj&#34;&gt;Save to Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is a browser extension for Chrome which adds a button next to the address bar used to tag links to read later with Pocket. The extension also adds a context menu item when you two finger tap a link using a Mac or right click using Windows. Another cool feature of the extension is the keyboard shortcut for saving a link. It is by default Command+Up+P for the Mac and Ctrl+Shift+S for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Later List&lt;/strong&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; allows you to tag links and save them for later use but I typically use the default list as a list of web pages on the Internet that I intend to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article Viewer&lt;/strong&gt; -
Pocket lets me view articles three different ways: &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com&#34;&gt;web application&lt;/a&gt;, mobile application: &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ideashower.readitlater.pro&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/read-it-later-pro/id309601447?mt=8&#34;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, native &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/pocket/id568494494?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12&#34;&gt;OSX application&lt;/a&gt;. Each gives me a list of links that I previously saved. When I click on a link, Pocket allows me to read using article view or web view. Article view cleans up the page so that it is mostly text. Web view displays the full website. If I am using the web application, web view open the link in a new tab. For both the native OSX and mobile applications, web view displays within the Pocket application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-daily-process&#34;&gt;My Daily Process&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; -
    At least once a day, using my RSS reader, I browse through new items by category. If the title looks interesting, I right click on the link and select &amp;ldquo;Save to Pocket&amp;rdquo;. On some occassions, I save a link to the read later list based entirely on the author. For example, I read everything Seth Godin writes. I also check sites like Reddit, Medium and Twitter a few times a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browsing&lt;/strong&gt; -
    Througout the day as I am browsing the Internet, I may come across something that looks interesting. I am able to save a bookmark using the Pocket bookmarking browser plugin. It keeps the popup window open long enough to allow me to tag the link if I care to. I can trigger saving the link to Pocket by either clicking on the extenion&amp;rsquo;s button next to the address bar or by the keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt; -
    Whenever I am in the mood to read, I can open up Pocket using either the web, mobile or native OSX application. If I am using either the mobile or native application, the article displays in a frame with a button bar that lets me either archive, trash, tag or set the link as a favorite. Once I&amp;rsquo;m done reading, I tag and archive the article if I think it has future value. Otherwise I trash the document. I have yet to use the favorite feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;missing-features&#34;&gt;Missing Features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As easy and convenient as this system is, there are still some features that are missing that would make life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS feeds for Tags&lt;/strong&gt; -
There should be a way to tag a link on the internet and then subscribe to an RSS feed based on the tag. I use my RSS reader as a discovery application. Now, when I tag a link it goes straight to my read later list. If I could subscribe to a tag feed I could add to this list without having to decide to actually read the article or not. I could decide later during my actually discovery process. This would allow me to tag links without putting much thought into if I cared to read it later. I could tag links based off of many different criteria such as subject, author, or who recommended the link. It would be nice to have the ability to quickly tag links that might remind me of why I was interested in the subject in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link priority&lt;/strong&gt; -
It would be nice if I could prioritize how interested I was in a link. There are times when a certain link makes it to the front of the list and I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to read it, but I do want to read it eventually. There should a way to push it to the back of the list or at least further down the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am constantly tweaking this system of consuming data on the Internet. New tools come out all of the time, hopefully someone will create a way of fixing the missing features I mentioned. If you have a better system, I would love to hear about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Good People Online</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/04/meet-good-people-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/04/meet-good-people-online/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I think that it’s possible to meet good people online without feeling like a creep and with very little risk. I think that the key to making friends online is by spending time with them offline. Conventional knowledge tells us that meeting people in person that we met on the Internet is a bad idea and potentially dangerous. I believe that I know how to solve that problem. Below are my ideas for using the Internet to safely meet people who are worth friendship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/03/how-we-meet-people/&#34;&gt;I have mentioned in the past&lt;/a&gt;, typically when we meet people, it is because we share an interest or a situation. This is the key. Any system that helps people meet will revolve around the events that they have in common. In order to manage the quality of the people we meet, we must manage the events where we meet them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trusted-host&#34;&gt;Trusted Host&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;To feel comfortable attending an event, we must trust that the other people attending are decent. How can you gain that trust when dealing with strangers? The best way is if there is a person that you both know and trust. Think about the initial conversations that you typically have with a stranger. They usually turn into efforts at finding things you have in common,  “Where are you from?”,  “Oh, really, do you know so and so?” Etc. If that doesn’t result in a match we move on to common interests by asking questions like “What do you do?”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;For this event management system to work, it is important that there is a host with a good reputation. The host is responsible for making sure that everything runs smoothly and that there are no assholes. The more a host is respected, the more likely people will be to risk their time attending.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vetting-system&#34;&gt;Vetting System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;In order to ensure that the right people attend, I propose a vetting system. Instead of sending out invitations, the host would share information about the event online. This would be either on social media or with a search engine that is dedicated to the type of event being held. People who are interested in attending would request an invitation. The host would be responsible for choosing the right people. The host could make that decision anyway they see fit. I suspect that a decision would be made based on the following criteria.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Personal friend of the host&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Past attendee with a good reputation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Reference from a trusted friend of the host&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Reference from a past attendee with good reputation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Acquaintance of the host&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Person with an interesting profile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;It might go without saying, but the event would be for a specific purpose. It might be to eat a certain type of food that the host makes. It could be to watch a sporting event on television. My favorite is a house party to listen to a local band. Again, the idea is to meet cool people who have similar interests as you. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reputation&#34;&gt;Reputation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;It should be possible for both the host and an attendee to build a reputation.  Everyone involved should be able to rate each other. Not only does it make it easier to get an invitation to another event, it also gives everyone an incentive to behave. If someone makes an ass of themselves at an event, they are less likely to get invited in the future. The person looks bad and it reflects poorly on the host that invited them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assumptions&#34;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;That is the basic idea for how to meet good people online in its raw form. I’ve made several assumptions that need to be tested. The biggest is, do people need help making friends? If so, are they worried about safety? Would a person be willing to request an invitation to a party? Would a host be interested in being choosy about who attends their event? Would attendees actually rate each other? Would an attendee agree to have their rating published for future hosts to see?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-application&#34;&gt;An Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The best way to test these assumptions is to actually build a web or mobile application and ask people to start using it. In lean startup language, a minimum viable product needs to be created. This application would allow a host to create and manage an event. A feature would exist to make it easy to publish the details to a social media site. Anyone interested in attending can see the host&amp;#8217;s rating / reputation. The person would click on the shared link to request an invitation. The host could optionally require that information such as a questionnaire be submitted to help with the vetting process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Each person that requests an invitation will be listed for approval by the host. The host will be able to review any past ratings that the person may have. Once they are approved, an email will be sent with the details of the event such as where it will be held. Once a person has been invited, they will be able to see the profiles of the other people who received an invitation. When the event is over each person will be able to leave comments and ratings for the host and everyone who attended.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The next step is to begin building the application. I will update this website as I make progress. If would like me to notify you as I post updates please send me your email address by filling out the form below. Please contact me if you want to help or if you have any suggestions or criticisms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Meet People</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/03/how-we-meet-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/03/how-we-meet-people/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-facebook-do-us-a-favor&#34;&gt;Did Facebook do us a favor?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been said that social media websites, like Facebook, are ruining social interactions. I have always been of the opinion that these websites make it easy to know enough about your friends so that you never need to speak to them again. Usually, when I see a friend we discuss what happened since we saw each other last. That is hardly necessary when you are kept informed in real time of their day to day experiences. On top of that, it’s not unusual to learn that you really don’t have much in common with your friends. Or that honestly, you don’t like them. There is something about an open forum that brings out the worst in people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe, social media websites just brought out in the open a problem that we’ve always had but never noticed. Maybe, those friends that we only interact with on Twitter aren’t really our friends. Maybe, that buddy with the radical political opinion just doesn’t have the nerve to bring it up in person. Would that make him any less of a tool? Maybe, Facebook did us a favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meeting-people-is-hard&#34;&gt;Meeting people is hard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I am a bit of a homebody. I don’t like to get out that much. Having to smile and politely greet people sounds like a nightmare. It is so rare that I find other human beings that I have something in common with. Although, that could very well be because of how little I get out. The one friend that I actually make an effort to hang out with might be more antisocial than me. I just don’t know how to meet people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I believe that it is healthy to socialize with other people. There are plenty of studies that all but prove that an active social life will make you live longer. The problem is that most people I meet are either shallow, temperamental or unreliable, or all of the above. I wonder how I seem to them? What I really need is a way to meet other people in person with similar interests that aren’t assholes. It would be nice if these people were also looking for friends.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-perfect-solutions&#34;&gt;No perfect solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;There are solutions to this problem but none of them completely work for me. There are lots of websites out there specifically designed to help you find that special somebody. I’m not interested in that. I already found my special somebody. I have been married to her for seventeen years. There are no services that I am aware of that help people look for just a normal friend. Probably because that sounds kind of pathetic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;When you meet a new person it is either because you have a common interest or situation. Depending on where you meet, there may also be certain behaviors that are appropriate. Generally speaking, the places that expect appropriate behaviors are safer than those with fewer expectations of proper etiquette. A lot of the time this means that you don’t really get to know a person as they are. Instead, you get a situationally appropriate version of them.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;places-we-meet-people&#34;&gt;Places we meet people&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Here are a few examples of safe places where people typically meet other people: work, church, school, &lt;a href=&#34;http://yonomitt.com/blog/2016/3/23/meeting-people-is-easy-but-hard&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conventions&lt;/a&gt;, or an event for their kids such as a baseball game etc. These are all locations where you should probably bring, at most, your rated PG personality. You are less likely to get into a fight at these places although you might watch out for some of those soccer moms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Other places to meet people might be: parties, bars, clubs or concerts for example. It is probably ok to let your hair down here but these are also some of the riskier locations. It is rare to get a DUI coming home from church, not so much from the bar. Remember, Uber is your friend. Also, don’t expect much stimulating conversation unless you are particularly fascinated with television, fashion, sports or Donald Trump. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meeting-people-online-is-creepy&#34;&gt;Meeting people online is creepy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;If you are looking for a lively debate, look no further than the Internet. You can find plenty of it online in forums or social media. The Internet has added all kinds of variety when it comes to meeting people. Of all the social networks, Twitter is the only one that I think you can reasonably meet new people. In my experience the others, notably Facebook, are just places where we keep track of the friends we meet in person. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The main problem with meeting people on the Internet is that you can never be sure who they are. The anonymous nature of the Internet is a honeypot for the worst sorts of sociopaths. Nowhere is this more true than in multiplayer games and online forums like reddit. You can never be sure who you are actually dealing with or what kind of sick game they may be playing. The Internet may be super convenient but it can also be a very creepy way of meeting people. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;There are services that combine both the risks of meeting online and meeting in person. Dating sites like eHarmony are probably the safest but as I mentioned before, I don’t want a date. It is also possible to find groups on Craig’s list or sites like meetup.com. The problem is that you don’t know what you are getting into until you get there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-can-we-do-about-it&#34;&gt;What can we do about it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;So what is the answer? Is it possible to meet real people, who aren’t putting on a show, without risking boredom, a DUI, or possibly your life?  Surely there must be some safe way to use the Internet to improve the way we meet people in person. I think that this is a problem that is worth solving. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;So to sum it up, I think there needs to be an online service. This service should make it safe and easy to meet other people, in person. It should not focus on romance and it should not be creepy. How hard could it be? Anyone else have any thoughts? Does this service already exist? Who wants to help me build it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan to Succeed</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the time, we set ourselves up for failure. We set goals in order to please someone else. We plan for things that we aren’t ready to tackle. We try to do too much. These are recipes for failure. If you are going to set goals, make sure that they are achievable. Spend some time figuring out what you need to do. Determine what success looks like and make plans. Otherwise you are likely to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting goals is the process of identifying the things that you want to do. Planning is the process of managing the things that you want to do. If you are anything like me, you have way more that you want to do than time to do it. If you are not careful, you’ll try to start working on everything and end up finishing nothing. Of course the answer is to plan. This is how I manage the things that I want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/how-to-use-goals/&#34;&gt;As I have mentioned before&lt;/a&gt;, I like to group my goals up into three different categories: long term, yearly and quarterly. Long term and yearly goals are really too far away for much planning. There is still too much time for everything to go to hell. However, a quarterly goal is really just a project. These are things that need to be done that are comprised of more than one action. Some projects are more strictly defined than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure that I am working towards my goals, I perform a review process at predefined times during the year. The review process is the secret sauce for creating a plan that stays relevant throughout the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekly Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Sunday I sit down and go through a review process. First, I go over what I accomplished the week before. I try to identify either why I was able or unable to finish what I had planned. I look at what I have left to do and decide whether I still want to do it. I also look over my “Waiting” list and decide if any other action needs to be taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I take a look at my goals for this quarter. I look at the projects and make sure that they are prioritized correctly. I take pains to avoid moving anything to or from the list of projects for this quarter. The Weekly review session is not the time to change quarterly goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that is done, I choose a project to work on. This should be the first item in the prioritized project list. Occassionaly that isn’t practical due to whatever is going on that week. Once I decide what projects to work on, I must break things up into actionable tasks. I store tasks in two different lists. I have a “To Do” list for everything I intend to do this week, and a “Doing” list for what I am doing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are more tasks for a project than can be finished in a week. In that case, I leave the extra tasks attached to the project in the Quarterly goals list. For those times when I finish more than I expect, these are the tasks that I usually do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I conduct a monthly review on either the first or last Sunday of every month. I choose the Sunday that is closer to the first day of the month. For example this month I will do my monthly review today since the first lands on a Tuesday. If the first was on a Friday, I would do my monthly review on the third day of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This review is a bit more elaborate version of my weekly review. The major difference is that I allow myself to add or remove a goal that I had set for this quarter. The added goal still needs to work towards accomplishing one of my yearly goals. The monthly review process is not the time to change yearly goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quarterly Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every three months, I have a quarterly review. As you will suspect, this review is much like the monthly review. I still do everything that I would do in a weekly review except that I allow myself to change yearly goals. I do not allow myself to change long term goals. The quarterly review process is not the time to change long term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that I allow myself to change goals at predefined times during the year is to allow for some flexibility. I personally need a bend but don’t break strategy for accomplishing goals. I have such a wide variety of interests that it doesn’t take much to derail me from everything that I have planned. On the other hand, sometimes things just don’t work out. It is ridiculous to continue working on something that obviously isn’t worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearly Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the yearly review, I reevaluate all of my goals. &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/12/2015-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;I think about the prior year&lt;/a&gt; in terms of what worked and what did not work so well. I put some thought into what I want to accomplish both now and in the future. &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/goals-and-plans-2016/&#34;&gt;Last year I spent about a week&lt;/a&gt; going through this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the time to change those long term goals. Sometimes after spending a significant amount of time working on something it becomes clear that it isn’t a good fit. It is difficult to give up on a goal that you have worked hard to accomplish. I always remind myself that setting goals and making plans is something that I do to make my life better. If at any time I feel like I have become a slave to the processes that I set up, then it is time to change. But only at the predefined intervals that I set beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of being a Parent</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was seventeen my father confessed, “Hey, I’ve never done this before. We are practicing on you.”. I think every parent on earth feels that way. We really have no idea what we are doing. Most of us are dealing with issues as they come by the seat of our pants. Even worse, the rules keep changing. And it doesn’t really matter how much experience or how many kids you have. The biggest mistake a parent can make is to expect what worked with one child to work on another. Being a parent is just hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up is the process of gradually taking more responsibility of your life. A child’s job is to fight for control of their lives until eventually they pull away. It’s like a game of tug of war with the kid at one end and the parent at the other. Whoever has more rope has more control but It’s a big rope. If, as a parent, you let go too soon your kid will fall backwards on their ass. That doesn’t stop most of them from trying. Too much control too soon is overwhelming. But parents can’t hold on forever. No one just magically becomes an adult at eighteen. The parent should give in slowly until eventually they feel comfortable letting go completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids rarely figure this out until they are grown. It has been difficult to explain to my oldest why I do what I do. I talk to him about the future. I try to make him understand that what he does now has a big effect on what he can expect later. To him the future happens in the next month or so. He still mostly lives his life as it happens. I am the roadblock that he has to get around. He knows that if he gets all A’s in school then he can play video games during the week. He knows that if he doesn’t do his chores that I am likely to get upset and punish him. He is starting to understand that he can get what he wants by giving me what I want. For my part, I try to only get in the way enough so that it is hard for him to do anything especially stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My youngest, on the other hand, lives a lot of his life in the clouds. He creates fantasy worlds in his head that he uses to test out situations that either scare or excite him. He is a bit more cautious and usually prefers to be alone. I encourage him to become the hero of those fantasy worlds. I try to teach him to be brave. We make an effort to get him involved in group activities so that he can get comfortable being around other kids. My wife and I have learned that we have to be careful about how hard we push him. Too much pressure and he shuts down. He retreats into of his imagination and we have to work hard to get him back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of being a parent is to teach children how to be adults. That responsibility trumps everything else while they are growing up.  Every kid is different. What works for one probably won’t work for another. One may try to jerk that rope out of your hands at every turn. Another may be content to let you lead them around forever. Either way can lead to trouble. Eventually our children must grow up to be adults that are capable of caring for themselves and their families. Hell, we may eventually need them to take care of us too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Teach Kids to Learn</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/04/how-to-teach-kids-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/04/how-to-teach-kids-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Kids naturally learn. It’s what they do. In the dictionary it should describe children as “Small humans who obtain knowledge at dizzying speeds with the express intent of driving their parents insane”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As parents, our concern is what they are learning from whom. Our hope is that they are being influenced by parents, teachers, and coaches etc. The truth is that they are primarily influenced by video games, YouTube videos and their friends, mostly their friends. It is possibly even better that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want them to learn skills that will be useful to them as they grow older. Reading, writing and arithmetic come to mind. The ability to use a computer and communicate clearly are invaluable skills as well. But it is hard to tell if they are learning anything. So, we turn to tests which suck the fun right out of everything. A test converts the tendency to learn into something to be avoided. Learning has become a dirty word that conjures up visions of being bored half to death while old people talk endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, testing is very hard to accomplish. How does one know that a kid has learned what they need to know? Our answer has been to standardize what we teach them. There has to be a definite right answer to determine wrong answers. It also allows us to gauge their progress against the progress of other students. Nevermind that different people have different talents. Nevermind that we NEED different people to have different skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School has become this place where we send our kids to learn how to memorize facts and follow instructions. Most of them take it to heart and spend their lives looking to be told what to do next. Some of them rebel and look for every opportunity to give the middle finger to authority often at their own expense. A small few learn to lead the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do some kids lead while others follow? Where do the leaders find the courage to do their own thing? The answer is confidence or even arrogance. At some point the kid took a chance and it paid off. This almost always meant that he learned to fail the right way. Or that she learned to treat a mistake like a setback instead of an excuse to quit. The trick was to find something they wanted so badly that they were willing to risk failure to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-should-we-do&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what should we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning is easy when it is needed for something awesome. Sometimes it just takes a little push. At our house, we are trying out an experiment. The idea is to always have some kind of creative project in the works. We define creative as something that the project owner considers art. We give each other daily updates as is possible. The updates consist of what you’ve done and what you intend to do next. It’s as simple as that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no size, type or time limits, as long as you are actively participating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No physical help. Questions are fine but the project should be completed alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can not buy the end result of your project. You can however buy ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need to buy a resource / ingredient, you must use your own money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s Next Updates should have a tangible result. No saying, I’m going to think about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you haven’t made any progress within a week, it means your project wasn’t exciting  enough. You should choose something new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a project is finished or abandoned, a new one must take it’s place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must love and care about your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to create an environment that encourages taking on risk. It is my hope that we learn that the more you put into something the more satisfaction you get from it’s completion. I hope we learn that failure is a necessary part of learning. I also hope that we learn to take pride in our work. Taking on bigger and more elaborate projects over time is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids do not spontaneously lose interest in learning. We train them to avoid it by trying to force them to prove how much they’ve learned. If we want to teach kids to learn we must encourage them to create art that they love. It will give them the courage they need to lead instead of abstain or follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Issues</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/05/communication-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/05/communication-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever known someone so well that you could complete their sentences? With some people there is hardly a need for verbal communication at all. Half the time, my wife knows what I’m feeling better than I do based solely on my posture and facial expressions. Our biggest communication issues come from the fact that she knows me too well. She likes to anticipate what I’m going to say. Often she will ignore what I actually say and instead answer the question I should have asked. I tend to get bent out of shape over it but the frustrating part is that she is usually right. We know each other so well that we have developed a kind of specialized pseudo language. It consists mostly of looks, movie quotes and partial or half spelled words etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different situations demand different types of communication.These days many alternative methods of communications are sprouting up. Cumbersome keyboards on cell phones and character limits on SMS messages cause proper English to be impractical for text messaging. Text based communications in multi-user video games are by necessity hurried. You will most likely be “ganked” by other players or slaughtered by magical creatures long before you can choose the proper verb conjugation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that there is a certain portion of the population that cry foul on communications by any other means than proper English. The older generation frowns at the younger’s slang. The slang of the older generations has become so common that it no longer sounds like slang. Many of the words have made their way into standard dictionaries. Languages are in a constant state of modernization. This is how they grow. English has changed immensely over time. It has its roots in a dialect of a germanic language from many centuries ago. It has changed so much that we couldn’t even begin to understand it’s original form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of language is communication. That should go without saying. It means that you should be able to both understand and be understood. Yet, it seems that most of our problems stem from misunderstandings. I have devised a theory that I believe explains how people successfully communicate. It also describes how we are able to improve our communication skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful communications should result in comprehension. To make that happen, there are three criteria that must be accounted for. They are Relationship, Topic Familiarity and Language Precision. Each of these are measured on a sliding scale. The levels of one criteria must be inversely proportional to that of the other two. As a criteria value decreases, one or both of the others must increase to properly convey the intended message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship)&lt;/strong&gt; The better you know someone the easier it is to communicate. The more comfortable you are around someone, the more aware you become of their idiosyncrasies. The closer you are to someone the more forgiving each of you will be towards mistakes. This person will be more likely to correctly intuit your meaning. The closer your relationship is to someone the less important it is to use precise language while discussing topics that you both know well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic Familiarity)&lt;/strong&gt; The complexity of a topic depends on the people communicating. The same topic can be extremely complicated for some and childs play to others. Topic experts usually have little need to discuss details. A laugh, sigh, facial expression or hand gesture might be all that is necessary. When I began my career in the Air Force, I was sent to boot camp. I lived in barracks with a bunch of boys that I didn’t know. We were given very specific instructions on how to conduct ourselves. Each of us were encouraged to become experts on how to behave while in boot camp. The military procedures quickly went from seeming foreign to second nature. Even though I barely knew the other Airmen, we each were able to perform our duties with very minimal verbal communication because we understood our roles so well. The more familiar a group is with a the topic, the less important it is for close relationships or precise language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language Precision)&lt;/strong&gt; A language is an agreed upon systematized group of words and grammatical conventions. It is a set of rules for converting concepts and ideas into either text or speech. People who know the rules can share ideas using text or speech. Even though these rules tend to change slightly over time, the conventions are universally agreed upon for each respective language. Language makes it possible to portray a specific idea and feel confidant that you can be understood. When speaking a language precisely, my words have a definite meaning no matter how well I know the subject or the listener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comprehension can be achieved by combining these three criteria in the correct proportions. The more of one of the criteria you use the less you need of the other two combined. Let’s say that each criteria is measured on a ten point scale with one being the very bottom and 10 being perfect. The Relationship criteria would begin with Indifference (0) and end with Mind-melded (10). Topic Familiarity would go from Ignorant (0) to Expert (10). And Language Precision would start at Vague (0) and stop at Professor (10). I should note that the highest and lowest numbers are practically impossible to achieve. For example a Relationship ten would essentially mean that you absolutely always knew what the other person was thinking. A zero would mean that you weren’t even aware they existed. Neither is valuable for anything other than setting a benchmark for a numerical value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how the numerical values work. A ten on any two criteria allows for a zero on the remaining one. Lowering one of the criteria would allow for the raising of another. So, if two people can read each others minds (10) and you both have absolutely nothing left to learn (10) on a topic, communications on that topic requires no language at all (0). Here is a more practical example. An informal (5) conversation about a familiar (5) topic with an acquaintance (5) could be considered idle chit chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve comprehension there must be no less than twenty points between the three criteria. Less than that does not achieve complete understanding. Each person involved in a conversation contributes to the total points assigned. A person&amp;#8217;s aptitude for each of the criteria must be taken into account. So for example, if one person in the conversation speaks English fluently (8) but the other person is very new to the language (2). Their combined possible Language precision can not be higher than the average (5). It works the same for the other two criteria. Until a group of people are able to find twenty point between the three criteria they will be unable to understand each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that each individual can increase their points with effort. One can always learn more about an interesting person, topic or skill on their own. However, It is more interesting when it is accomplished with a group. While communicating with another person excess points can be used to increase aptitude in another criteria. Here is a scenario where learning can occur. Let’s say we have two people who know each other well (8). They each are using proper English (8) to discuss a topic that one of them knows (8) but the other does not (2). Their combined Topic Familiarity would be an average of five (8 + 2 / 2). The criteria values would be Relationship (8), Topic Familiarity (5) and Language Precision (8). Combined that is a total of 21. The remaining Topic Familiarity point increases the value for future communications. The next time a similar conversation occurs the potential for learning increases even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion something similar to what I have described is the natural way in which people communicate and learn. I imagine that in reality it is quite impossible to quantify an accurate number to describe something like a relationship, understanding of a topic or how precise one is capable of speaking. However, in my mind, this does help one think about how to best communicate with another person. Talking in big fancy words to someone that I hardly know about a subject that one of us doesn’t understand is a lesson in futility. I can’t help but wonder how comprehensible this article will be for most of the people that I know. Hopefully someone that understands this topic better than I will care enough to set me straight where I have missed the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whining, Crying and Belly Aching</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/03/whining-crying-and-belly-aching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/03/whining-crying-and-belly-aching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is there anything worse than a whining, sniffling, belly aching kid? I think not. Sometimes, It seems like it’s all my kids do. We hear such long suffering complaints as “Vegetables are gross, WAH”, or “I don’t want to do my chores, WAH, WAH”. And my personal favorite, “Why me?, WAH, WAH, WAH”. It seems to go on and on forever. It’s enough to drive a person crazy. It’s no consolation but my kids are not alone. From what I’ve seen, incessant whining is a skill in which nearly every child excels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where and how do kids learn this constant complaining? Do they attend secret bitch and moan classes behind our backs? Obviously they get it somewhere. As Linda and I were discussing this very topic the other night it hit me like a ton of bricks. They learned it from me! The truth was so obvious. I was dumbstruck. Unbelievably, this had never occurred to me before. They are indeed learning in secret bitch and moan sessions and I am the maestro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I was aware of the problem, I paid much closer attention to the amount of complaining coming from the adults of the house. It actually exceeded the volume of complaints coming from the kids. It was typically unconscious responses to frustrating situations. “The traffic on the way to work sucks, WAH”. “The house is a mess, WAH, WAH”. “Our children whine too much, WAH, WAH, WAH”. So Linda and I began pointing out when the other was complaining. If the boys were learning it from us, they should unlearn it from us as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whine police worked well for about ten minutes. And then It seemed like I was being chastised for every other word I said. Are not some complaints necessary? How are we to ever solve problems if they are never identified? Obviously some rules were in order. To begin with we needed definitions. What is complaining? When does it cross over into whining territory? When is it ok to point out undesirable situations or events? First off, the only difference between whining and complaining was who did it. Children whine, adults complain. In fact we spend an inordinate amount of time complaining about them whining. Since they are learning it from us, we are actually making it worse when we point it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should we define the word complain? The dictionary definition is: To express dissatisfaction or annoyance about a state of affairs or an event. A problem is defined as: A matter or situation regarded as unwelcome or harmful and needing to be dealt with and overcome. How can one point out an annoyance or unwelcome situation without expressing dissatisfaction? Do we just ignore problems and hope they go away? Of course not. The answer lies in the back half of the definition of problem. A problem needs to be dealt with or overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are acceptable and unacceptable forms of complaining. If the intention of a complaint is to deal with or overcome a problem, then it is acceptable. Merely pointing out that a problem exists is not enough. You should always offer a solution along with the complaint. The offered solution should either be an action for the person who is hearing the complaint or a token solution designed to elicit help. Sometimes problems are not within our power to solve. This is especially true for children. Instead of whining that he doesn’t want to go to bed so early, Drew could suggest reading for another thirty minutes. Also there is no good reason to talk about a problem that you can solve without assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times when the person with the problem is not aware of any acceptable solution. In this case the only way for the problem to be solved is to ask for help. However, this is very difficult to accomplish. Describing the problem in your attempt to ask for help is indistinguishable from unacceptable complaining.  When the complainer is not receptive to possible solutions then it is unsanctioned complaining. Think about all the times people have come to you in the guise of requesting help but then proceed to shoot down every solution you offer. This is merely clandestine whining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why the best course of action is to offer a solution even if it is only a token one. It is actually quite difficult to even identify a problem without having some sort of idea of how things should be. If you know how things should be then its not that hard to come up with at least one thing to do which will move you in that direction. For example, if I am unhappy with the traffic during my morning commute there are several things I can try. I could take a different route. I can ask my boss to let me work from home. Or I can ask to work an earlier shift to avoid the traffic. I could take the bus. Depending on my situation some are possible and some aren’t. What I can be sure won’t work is complaining. I can only imagine how my boss would react if I merely pointed out over and over again that traffic sucked. Most likely the response would be “join the crowd, it is not pleasant for anyone”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other trap that is easy to fall into is tricking yourself into believing that your problem is insurmountable. This is especially frustrating when there is an obvious person to blame. There is almost always some kind of solution. The boss won’t listen to you? Well then quit. Find a different job. If you can not or are unwilling to try every solution that is offered than just keep your mouth shut. Do not shoot down each suggestion that is offered to you like some kind of skeet shooting exercise. There is no need to prove that your situation is impossible. This will only ensure that future problems will have one less ear willing to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with all of this in mind. I have come up with a few rules that I plan to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before outsourcing problem solving duties, I will attempt to correct issues on my own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the solution to a problem involves another person, I will clearly understand and be able to explain the role I hope for that person to fill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will try to avoid rule number 2 as much as possible. I will make it worth their while when it is necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of asking for help, I will ask for a critique of a solution that I propose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess in a way, everything I have written today is one big long winded complaint. Hopefully I have followed my own rules. I am very interested in hearing your critique of the solution I propose. Hopefully as a result, I will be a better example for my children. Hopefully the constant whining and crying will end. Because the truth is that the only thing worse than a whining, sniffling, belly aching kid is a complaining adult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ball and Chain of Experience</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/02/the-ball-and-chain-of-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/02/the-ball-and-chain-of-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Children are unburdened by the ball and chain of experience. They typically see the world for what it is and it isn’t nearly as complicated as we adults seem to think. For example, my youngest son is almost four years old, he has a mind like a trap. He has very concrete expectations for life. He wants to eat when he is hungry and drink when thirsty. Mostly, he wants to play. He is on a continual quest for anything new; new games, new friends and new words. Each offers him new opportunities to play. When there is somewhere to go he wants to tag along. His prime directive is to have fun. He faces down any act of fun repression with fierce opposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy looks at the world as his personal playground. The different pieces of equipment on the playground are all there solely for his enjoyment. He associates the places he goes with their purpose. More specifically, he associates them with his purpose for going there. When we go to the mall, it isn’t for shopping. We are there to ride the escalator. So of course the mall is the Escalator Store. Twice a week he attends a kiddy martial arts class. He has dubbed it the Fight Store because it’s where he goes to fight. There is also the Haircut store, the Jump store (gym), several Food stores and many more Stores both identified and yet to be discovered. If he had his way he’d play in every store or piece of the playground simultaneously all of the time. He has a hard time envisioning a world where he doesn’t get his way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Childhood at its core is an egocentric enterprise focused almost entirely in the now. With age the focus shifts slightly outward and is aimed more towards the very near future. As young adults we idealize our future lives and are eager to connect with new people. Eventually we become primarily concerned with maintaining our present state of affairs. The older we get the more interested we are in our own past and our children’s future. Have you ever noticed that history and genealogy are mostly adult hobbies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our personal legacy is like the halls of a museum. We create exhibits to honor certain events as we go about our lives. As we get older, it is tempting to build shrines to some of those old exhibits and worship them. For reasons I don’t understand the older exhibits feel more authentic. At some point, we more closely identify with what we’ve done than what we want to do. Until finally we become bored with our own museum entirely. Children don’t look back. That story is dull. The plot hasn’t been flushed out yet. All the good stuff is in front of them. They are much more interested in creating exhibits than looking at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are young the future is mysterious and exciting, anything is possible. Adults understand that those endless possibilities are not necessarily all good. In fact many of them are dangerous. The difference between a child’s outlook and that of an adult is what we call naivety. Adults have become adept at mitigating risk and liability. Adults have learned to fear while children believe with innocence. I’m starting to realize that children don’t really lose that innocence. Instead it is corrupted, mutated. For adults much of life still seems like a magic trick. We don’t really understand the world any better. We have, however, learned to fear what we don’t understand. It is fear that evolves into anxiety, anger and hate. The fear is what corrupts us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us do everything we can to avoid things that make us uncomfortable. We’ve learned to be cautious. We don’t easily take chances because we understand that there are real consequences to our actions. We tend to forget that our greatest triumphs were also our riskiest ventures. That’s just how it works. The greater the reward the harder it is to achieve. The likelihood of success is directly proportional to the difficulty of the task. The events that result in the most joy are the ones with the largest stakes. What about your life are you most proud of? Chances are, it is also the one in which you put your life on the line the most. This is how it should be. Computer and robots make decisions based on precise analytical calculations. Life should not be a series of events undertaken based on their statistical chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children are unburdened by the ball and chain of experience. They are looking forward. Their eyes are on the reward. Failure is not a concern. They run headlong into whatever flight of fancy that they are currently dreaming. Eventually this gets them in trouble. They learn that the cost of experience is typically paid in heartache and pain. As they grow older they get better at evaluating risk. They get better at avoiding situations that could get ugly. They become cautious, they become adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, it is childlike audacity that inspires us. It is the person that risks everything to create something out of nothing that we value the most. This is because it is rare. We see musicians, artists and actors and we are envious. It doesn’t even matter much the merit of the persons antics. If it is dangerous or takes courage we are intrigued. Honestly, the moron taking the risk need not even realize it as long as the viewer considers it risky. Anyone that has become caught up watching a reality tv show knows. We all understand at some level that taking the risk is often itself the reward. It makes us feel alive. It reminds us of the time in our lives before life kicked us in the teeth. It tempts us to throw caution to the wind and risk everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well, maybe not everything. But we can spare a little pride can’t we? My own in-brain statistical analysis suggests that for maximum effectiveness a little more risk is required. I probably shouldn’t change everything overnight but, you know, baby steps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it possible to sell sound?</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept of property can get complicated. We have plenty of laws regulating it. In fact, the idea of private property is at the heart of our way of living. It seems fair that if you work hard creating something, then you should own it. That isn&amp;#8217;t always possible, and some things cannot be owned at all. Or at the very least, it would be silly to consider owning them, for example a cloud, rain or air. What about sound? Does one own the sounds he makes? Can you sell sound? When you speak, you create sound. A few people actually put a lot of time, energy and thought into what they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you own sound waves? Can you forbid someone from repeating your words? Can you sell your spoken words? Can you demand compensation for those who have heard your words?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is mostly yes, if those sounds have been recorded. This logic kind of falls apart in a live setting. If you give a speech, you do not own the sounds you make. You can&amp;#8217;t forbid anyone from uttering the same words. You can not even charge anyone for hearing the sound. You can only restrict access to the location you speak from so that only authorized ears are in range to hear. In a sense you are restricted by physical property for what you can and can not charge. Instead of a sound being stored on a cassette, disk or thumb drive forever, it is stored in a geographic area or inside of a building for only a moment. Therefore you can not charge for those sounds. You can only charge for access to the sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also cannot make someone pay to hear sound in a public place. How silly would it be if you walked down a public street singing a song and demanded that everyone who heard pay? But what if it was a song you worked very hard to create? What if your performance was the best that had ever been heard? Doesn’t matter right? Now what if someone recorded your performance on the public street, can you charge them now? It is ridiculous to think that someone could charge for something that was knowingly released to the public. In this sense public is not a designation. It is a description. If something is reasonably accessible by all people, then it is public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never had to consider these issues before. We have never directly paid for sound. Instead, as I mentioned, we buy access or we purchase containers that sounds are stored in. Records, 8 tracks, tapes and CD’s are all physical items that are inherently scarce and therefore have a value. You are free to sell the item you own for whatever price you can get. The radio however is a different thing entirely. If a song is broadcasted publicly over a radio frequency then whoever is able to hear it should be able to do whatever they want with it. This would be no different than recording someone playing a song on a street corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is no different than the radio. The radio is no different than someone speaking in public. Only the scope of the broadcast is different. Some of these network are password protected. Some radio frequencies are encrypted. This does not make the networks or radio frequencies private. The raw Internet or Radio network is still accessible to anyone in range. It simply means that the tools necessary to make sense of them are protected. As an example think of this in terms of the person speaking in public. It would be as if he spoke in a another language to protect his words. He might offer a class in that language to grant access to the meaning but the words themselves are free to be consumed by anyone in range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is made up of private servers all over the world. On their own the data on these servers is private. However once it becomes part of a public network then that machine is accessible by any machine on that network. The data that is shared between machines is public. The Internet is not the machines themselves but instead it is all of the connected networks. Each individual server is privately owned and its files are private. They can and should be secured. However if a private file is released on a public network can we reasonably expect it to stay private? The accessible data on the network is public in the same way that the radio is public. The radio signal is useless without a receiver but it is nonetheless available to all in range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything becomes confused when we consider digital items. Digital items are pieces of data. The data itself is in demand, people want it. But here is the real question. What exactly is data? Can I pick a piece of data up in my hands? What does it look like? Data is an abstraction. It does not physically exist, it is only a concept, an idea. Data is like sound, it only has meaning when processed through the brain. You may be able to speak in an unfamiliar language but you can not prevent people from hearing the sounds unless they are out of range. I can understand paying for a device which makes it possible to access data, like a radio receiver. I can understand paying for the method of making sense of data. I can even understand the rate of payment being based on the amount of data I access. But if you broadcast data over a public network, then it has become public property. If I have a password, can decrypt the security, or understand the secret language then I should be able to use it as I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think that we are missing the point entirely. What exactly is the point of granting or denying access to all of this data? When it comes to music, do we want the container or the music it contains? In the days of physical media, the tape, CD, etc., offered a service. Without the physical item it was impossible to hear the music. With digital files, all the music in the world is instantly available but denied to the listener who doesn’t pay. As I said, data is a concept. It is impossible to make it partially available to the public. Once it is out there, the only way to secure access is to threaten violence, incarceration or fines. Would we punish someone for understanding words spoken in public because they didn’t learn the language from an authorized source?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it could be argued that the Internet is not a public forum since one has to pay to access it. I would disagree, you have to pay for a newspaper. You don’t pay for the news mind you, you pay for the actual paper. You pay to access information, not for the information itself. The government recognizes the newspaper as a public forum for public notices. If a band is authorized to play a song in a public location they can not charge admission. The preferred method of compensating the band would be a donation. This allows each person to judge the value and give the band the data they need to determine whether it was worth their while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using force or threats to demand payment for a public resource is extortion. It doesn’t matter that you made the resource public. The legality of your action doesn’t change the definition of extortion. The Internet is attractive because it is used by the public. Publishing your song or any other information on the Internet and then demanding payment is no different than singing in a public park and demanding payment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of Music Appreciation</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was young, the music that I was allowed to listen to was strictly limited by my parents. Any music purchases must first go through an approval process. The cover art was the first obstacle. My mother would look over the tape cover with a suspicious eye. Anything with pictures of demons, drugs,  or violence was out. Anything that might otherwise suggest the devil’s handiwork would quickly get put back on the shelf. The same held true for any slight suggestion of sexuality. It’s not hard to imagine how many titles were restricted for this rock n roll fan in the early 80’s. Next, the song titles were scrutinized. The same rules applied as with the cover art; no drugs, sex, demons or violence. It was harder for her to check the lyrics. That is until that damnable woman Tipper Gore convinced the record labels to put a big black label on the album that said “EXPLICIT LYRICS”. Those two words were the purchasing death nail of many albums I desired. On rare occasion, I was able to sneak something through that wasn’t entirely squeaky clean. Once I was finally permitted to purchase an album it became a treasured possession. By the time I was a teenager with a job, I bought whatever I wanted and learned to hide my treasures. When this became the norm, the approval process was turned on its head. I actively sought out many of those Explicit Lyrics labeled albums. My album collection became a representation of me and how I viewed myself, instead of the idealized version of me that my mother wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Music Appreciation as a hobby
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have changed alot since then. I can remember hanging out with my friends with the express intention of listening to an album. Listening to music was the thing we did together. We would dissect each album. I knew what equipment was used, how the guitars were tuned and the backstory of the lyrics usually. We liked to compare the musicians from this or that band. We knew the names of each album and all of the songs. To this day I remember the lyrics to most of the songs on those albums and can name the band, track, album and release year after hearing the first measure. I don’t think we were the exception to the rule. Nearly everyone listened to music that way. It doesn’t seem to happen any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the line music has become the soundtrack for whatever else we are doing. It gives us something to sing along with while we’re in the car. It plays softly while we are at work.  Music has degenerated into our last defense against boredom. It is no longer something we do but instead it is background noise that guards against silence. Silence makes people uncomfortable. They nearly always find something to say instead of allowing it. Music is a nice convenient way of drowning out the possibility of having those forced conversations. Have you ever been in the car with someone who turned the music up so loud that you had to scream to talk to them? My favorite trick is headphones. I listen to music or books all day while wearing headphones. People are hesitant to talk to you while you are wearing them. Nothing says, “Please don’t disturb” quite like a good pair of headphones. The over the ear variety are even more effective. Somehow music has gone from connecting me to other people to helping me avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It’s hard to hold a digital file
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did listening to music go from being the main event to a mere sideshow act? I think that there are several reasons. One of the big ones is that there is now nothing physical to cherish. There is nothing to touch. Every album feels the same to my fingers, exactly like my mobile phone. It is all ones and zeroes floating inside a mini computer. Before when I bought an album, I physically possessed it. It was mine and which ones I owned said something about me. I could only have so many with me at any one time. The albums I kept on hand defined me, especially while in my car. If I wanted to play music for a friend, I had to choose carefully what albums to bring. What I listened to was a representation of my musical tastes. My music collection was tangible proof of that. I can now keep as many albums as I want. There is no space limitation and no penalty for having even the worst music on my digital player.  I may never listen to an album ever again and still have it on hand &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; without even a slight inconvenience. This seems like a good thing at first, but in reality it has trivialized the process of owning music. Many of us don’t even bother owning it anymore, instead we subscribe to music services which allow us to listen to what we want, when we want. It is much easier to take it for granted when it is so quick and simple to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Singles discourage innovation
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This constant access to music has lead to the habit of listening to singles instead of albums. We  now only listen to the equivalent of mix tapes, a personal greatest hits collection. The only problem is that this music is usually curated for us. We listen to what a computer algorithm tells us we will like. At best our friends suggest songs that they liked which the computer suggested to them. Albums in the past were meant to be listened to straight through. The single was essentially a gift we received via the radio to help us decide if we wanted to hear the entire album. You didn’t know which was your favorite song on an album until you listened to them all. The single got you through the door, the album helped you decide if you would stay or ever return again. Some albums ended up in our car and some ended up at the used record store. But now people mostly want to listen to singles. This requires that every song is available for individual purchase. It means that every song has to stand on its own. Musicians are in the business of selling music. No matter how much artistic integrity they have, ultimately they need to pay the bills like the rest of us. How many songs are now scrapped that don’t have an obvious market? Can you imagine if all of the tracks on Pink Floyd’s The Wall had to stand on their own? Even though the cost of creating a fully realized song is much lower, the time commitment is still substantial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  There is too much music
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor is competition. The cost of doing business has reached the point where anyone can start a band, record music and market it to the world for very little money. Of course these things alone do not guarantee success. It does guarantee that anyone can throw in their hat and try. This is another thing that seems like a good thing but has a negative impact on how we listen to music. In the past, it was so expensive to record that a band needed someone to fund their recording sessions. Record labels would invest in bands who obviously filled a market. Even though this process probably stifled creativity in general, it ensured for the most part that the music would be decent. Of course this depends on your tastes but the point is that there was less out and out bad music. The gatekeepers are now falling to the wayside. More and more musicians are picking themselves instead of waiting to be chosen by a record label. This has caused an entirely new problem, there is too much music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many bands, it is almost impossible to be heard. You have to really stand out to find any kind of mass audience. Signing with a major record label is still the best way to ensure that you will find an audience but ironically record labels want to sign bands who already have an audience. The latest strategy is for a band to give their music away to remove any kind of reason for fans to pass them by. This has created a race to the bottom, turning singles into nothing more than advertisements. The strategy seems to be to gain enough of a following so that record labels will want to sign you. The result has been that fans are given the impression that they are doing the band a favor by listening to their music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The Music Industry is dead, long live the music industry
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the problems that I have pointed out are the direct result of technological changes that we consider innovations. How do we determine if a change was a positive one? In my opinion, to be deemed positive it has to improve the fans experience. The truth is that technology is almost always used to make things easier. Sometimes getting something easy just makes us lazy. I am not suggesting that we turn back time and go back to physical media. In order to succeed, bands will need to overcome these issues. In order to do this we must realize that the game has completely changed. I’ve read that the era of super bands like the Beatles is over and that the success of the future is only making a living. I don’t believe it. Mega successful bands will always exist as long as they connect listeners with music that moves them. The fan must respect and maybe even envy the musician. These people have the almost magical ability to manipulate our emotions with their creations. It’s hard to respect someone when you feel like you are doing them a favor by granting them your attention. It’s hard to cherish a possession that doesn’t actually exist. It’s even harder to pay for what is out there for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe that the problems I’ve mentioned are fixable. More than likely music will never again be primarily sold enmass in physical packages. I wouldn’t be surprised if musical compositions ceased to be sold at all. Music will become more accessible, not less. The idea of the personal music collection will be explained in history books next to the section on cassette tapes. People will continue to listen to mostly to curated music in the background.  The music industry as we know it has already died, we just don’t realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The successful band of the future will involve its audience in every way imaginable. The fans contribution to the project will cloud the line separating the band from its audience. By combining social networking, crowdsourcing and crowdfunding, musicians will join with their fans to produce music that is meant to be enjoyed by those who created it. This band will give their fans more than a souvenir, it will give them a voice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Kids Spend Too Much Time Inside?</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/08/do-kids-spend-too-much-time-inside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/08/do-kids-spend-too-much-time-inside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We ate dinner at seven o&amp;#8217;clock. We ate dinner together as a family, at the table, mom’s rules. My spot was at the end of the table directly in front of a wall heater, a prized location in the winter. I sat to the right of my brother Pete and across from mom. This was not some somber formal dining ritual. This was our daily family reunion after a busy day of school or play. Most of time, it was the first chance we had to really talk to each other all day. I don’t remember our house ever being quiet but then again I spent as little time in the house as I could. It was boring in the house. My room? That was the place they sent me when I was in trouble. I spent as much time as I could outside playing with the neighborhood kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was about eleven years old (my son Drew’s age), my room consisted of a bed and a dresser for my clothes. I don’t remember having much more than that, although I’m sure my mother would disagree. The truth is that I can’t remember my room very well at all. I don’t think I used it as much more than a place to sleep. I would just concede a bad memory except that I remember other details of my childhood vividly. I remember that we had an old broken Volkswagen bug at the back of the yard. The engine should have been in the trunk but it was gone. I almost got stuck in it one time. We boys usually used it as “the hill” in king of the hill. We had a tree in the backyard with the long rubbery stalks that were the source of endless entertainment and bruises. I was having trouble describing the tree so I thought I’d ask dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: hey dad what kind of tree was that in the back of 708 next to the pole?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larry Craddock: I don&amp;#8217;t know what those are called &amp;#8230; it had beans on it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larry Craddock: catalpa tree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: lol those things were beans? I thought it was a sword tree. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larry Craddock: 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another tree next to the house with a big branch that always threatened to brush up against the house. Dad always seemed to be trimming it. I would climb the tree and jump on to the top of the house. There were actually several routes to the top of the house, the most fun being the fancy metal poles that held up the roof on the covered porch. It was harder to get down but usually I just jumped. It’s amazing that I never broke a leg, it had to have been eight foot to the ground. I definitely remember the moped that we had at the side of the house. I’ll never forget the injury I received when a friend turned the pedal while my finger was in the chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we became members at the Regency pool, we had an above ground pool in the back yard. We had lots of fun trying to drown each other in that pool. We would have competitions for how long one could stay under water. I was the king, I could swim three full laps under water without coming up for air. At one point, dad built a tree fort around the bean/sword tree. I used to climb up into that fort and use it as a diving board into the pool. There was also a T shaped metal pole that was meant to support a clothesline that was utilized as a diving platform. The pole was right next to a chained link fence. The top of the fence came up over the support bar and functioned almost like a barb wired top. If one managed not to cut their feet up at the top of the fence, you could climb up on top of the pole. This in and of itself was tricky due to dripping wet feet newly covered with grass. If you managed to make it without slipping and busting your ass, you could manage some pretty awesome dives into the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no shortage of fun things to do at our house and it was not limited to only the back yard. We also used to play under the house. I can still remember the smell. It was musty with the slightest trace of decomposed carcass. The ground was almost like sand and boy was it dusty. I seem to remember there being chicken wire in front of each entrance, probably to keep animals out. One time a cat climbed under the house and died. Dad had one of us climb under there and drag it out. I think it was Nathan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t spend all of our time in the back yard. We were avid bike riders. I remember dad teaching me how perform maintenance on my bike. Maybe it was because I was rough on the bike  but I remember my chain slipping off all the time. I had to learn to put the chain back on. I even had to add a link to the chain once. Flat tires were frequent annoyances. Getting a new tire meant that there was no more room on the old tire for a patch. Worse was that after fixing a flat I had to push my bike to the filling station next to the highway through town to air up the tire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode our bikes all over town. Technically we were supposed to stay in the neighborhood but this rule was easier to give than to enforce. I’ve probably ridden my bike over every square foot of Anadarko, Oklahoma. Once we rode our bikes to Indian City which was a few miles outside of town. Our favorite thing to do was tricks, especially jumping. I was pretty convinced that I was Evel Knievel’s equal. You would think that there would be frequent wrecks and you would be correct. I’ve flipped over on my back attempting the world biggest wheelie. I’ve gone flying over the handlebars attempting a front wheelie. I’ve landed painfully on the frame of my bike so many times that it’s amazing that I have children. I probably have done irreparable damage to my brain from landing on my head without a helmet in bicycle accidents. Thankfully, I never broke a bone. I never needed much more than mom’s hand on my head and a declaration of “BE HEALED” to treat most of my childhood injuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another favorite pastime of my youth was playing football with the neighborhood boys. We took this very seriously. I was Walter Payton on offense and Brian Bosworth on defense. Helmets and pads were for sissies. I had never even heard of flag football and probably wouldn’t have understood the point of playing without tackling. We didn’t really play games, it was more like we played until everyone had to go home. If you weren’t bleeding a little by that point, you weren’t trying hard enough. There were no refs, everyone was responsible for identifying any penalties committed against them. Without the aid of instant replay, you would often have to resort to blows to get the correct call. Football almost always led to fights. Come to think of it lots of things led to fights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back I think we just enjoyed fighting. We fought all the time. Friends, enemies, strangers? It didn’t matter eventually there would be a fight. I don’t even remember being angry half the time. We just fought, if not with each other then we’d find someone. Getting into a proper fight took work sometimes. To facilitate the process we learned to insult each other. There was an art to spouting out insults. There was an appropriate insult for most every situation. There were insults of greeting, playful insults, comeback insults and the list goes on. There were certain insults that had to result in a fight if you have any self respect at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No insult was complete without a proper cuss word. My friends and I went to great lengths to cuss properly. It was necessary to have the proper inflection with just the right amount of emotion. If you weren’t careful a comeback insult could be misconstrued as a playful insult, vice versa, all because you pronounced your cuss word wrong. But we weren’t afraid to experiment by coupling different cuss words together. We even created our own unique insulting words and phrases. These worked best for insulting people to their faces without them being the wiser.  I can feel that grin that wells up inside your face threatening to reach your cheeks and give you away just thinking about it. These were my favorites, along with the ones where the victim wasn’t quite sure that they had indeed been insulted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say, I had quite the education that just would not have been possible if I had not spent so much time outside playing with other kids. So I pose the question. Do our kids spend too much time inside watching television and playing video games? How will our children test the limits of their physical well being from the safety of the house? How will they learn to effectively escape adult supervision while sitting in the house or being leashed to portable GPS devices? Are we really going to allow them to learn how to cuss by watching television or on the Internet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear your opinion on the subject. Were you an inside or outside kid? What were some of your experiences?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliophiles Anonymous</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/08/bibliophiles_anonymous/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/08/bibliophiles_anonymous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Erik and I am a bibliophile. I have a serious reading problem. I have read countless books, both fiction and nonfiction. I read blogs, news articles, wikipedia entries and comics. I read product reviews on shopping websites. I read the biographies of people I admire or want to emulate. I read about music and on other topics that I desire improved skills. I can easily lose a full day when I run across something new and interesting. I easily spend six hours on any given day reading. I tend to obsess on the same topic for months on end before moving on to a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read books about self improvement, physics, marketing and leadership. I’ve devoured books on every religion you’ve ever heard of and some you haven’t. I have studied the oil industry, the history of money and trade, and real estate sales strategies. I’ve read books about the history, language and culture of people who speak Arabic, Farsi, Chinese, Japanese, Greek, Italian, German, French, Spanish, Welsh and English to name a few. And that is only nonfiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend so much time reading nonfiction that it leaves me with no time for those wonderful escapes into other strange worlds. To make time for fiction, I have taken up listening to audiobooks while in the car or riding a bike at the gym increasing my reading time another two hours a day. I spend a large portion of my time consuming information. You would think that with all of this reading I probably know a lot about many topics. For the most part this isn’t true. I typically have a pretty good grasp of whatever is currently on the top of my obsession list. I usually only retain a general knowledge of past obsessions. I’ve simply read so much that there isn’t room in my head for it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to read for the sake of reading. It has literally become an addiction. I engage in the act of reading much like I smoked in the past. I know I overdo it but I enjoy the activity so much that I can’t seem to stop. I think a better example is overeating. Eating is a positive action until it isn’t. The mind, like the body, needs nourishment. We eat to supply fuel to our bodies so that we can perform physical activities. If you continue to supply fuel without using it, you get fat. Once you get past a certain point the extra fuel actually becomes a hindrance until eventually you have a hard time moving at all.  Knowledge is similar. It is the energy of the mind. Knowledge for its own sake is not only a waste of time but I believe that it will eventually consume you. I have spent so much time acquiring information that there is no time to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge difference between understanding something and knowing it. One could read until their face was blue about gears, levers, body inertia, momentum and friction and still not know how to ride a bike. It takes actually getting on and crashing a few times to learn and then you never forget. It’s the same for most things. I’ve read countless books on math and guides on how to write computer programs. I didn’t learn to actually code until I pressed the compile button and fixed the resulting errors a few million times. Once I learned, the experience changed me forever. The logic of cause and effect and object oriented thinking color everything I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I am not suggesting that reading is a waste of time. I am saying that being exposed to information without putting it to use is a waste. Reading isn’t even the most common method of acquiring information. Most people watch TV at an average rate of about 3 hours a day. I won’t comment on quality but no matter the source, I believe that all of this information has made our brains fat and lazy.  Learning how young singers deal with stress on American Idol is useless knowledge unless you intend to become a singer. Understanding the details of permission marketing is a waste of neurons with nothing to sell. Knowledge isn’t truly consumed until it is utilized. Up until that point it is merely taking up space in your brain. The more time we spend focusing on a specific skill, the less we have to think about it. The knowledge is transferred from our brain to what we call muscle memory. Of course it is much more complicated than this. There are all sorts of scientific explanations that I don’t even begin to understand. The irony is that I am actively suppressing the urge to spend the next month reading about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reading habit may be an extreme case but I think that most of us spend way more time consuming information than is healthy. We spend countless hours filling our brains with useless data. We have become a nation of the mentally fat and lazy. We applaud individuals who become experts at their craft while failing to recognize the dedication it took for them to achieve it. I have heard people say of a musician “I wish I had their talent”. The assumption being that the person was born with it. The truth is, they focused entirely on one skill for a long period of time until they mastered it. While I was reading about King Alfred uniting the early Britons with the English language, that person was playing scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep reading that we live in the Information age, that someday people will look back and proclaim our time to be the epoch of a new era. I hear that the Internet and freely available information will change the world forever. My worry is that we may drown in this ocean of information. I know that I am barely keeping my head above water. I think some kind of accountability system is in order. As I mentioned before, we could call it bibliophiles anonymous. We would help people only consume data that they intended to use. Part of our 12 step program would be mandatory time offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this world of instant access to information, it’s how we use it when we are offline that leads to true wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s about time for a mid life crisis</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/07/its-about-time-for-a-mid-life-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/07/its-about-time-for-a-mid-life-crisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m facing another one of those age milestones in a couple of weeks. I turn 39 next month. This will be the last year of my 30’s. The average lifespan of a male in the United States is about 75 years, but that increases a little bit nearly every year. So I am probably somewhere around halfway finished. I’m still young, relatively speaking. I’ve already experienced so much that I can’t remember it all. That is kind of exciting if I think about it. There is so much I can still do, and maybe I’ll forget about some of the dumb shit I’ve already done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been one to worry about age or getting old. I can’t say that I am too concerned about this birthday coming up either. But I’m starting to question the wisdom in that. Maybe I should worry some. There are plenty of things that I didn’t consider at all when I was younger that could have led to a more pleasant life now. It’s not a stretch to imagine that an older me might appreciate a little caution especially when it comes to my health. It seems that life’s lessons are almost always learned through retrospect measured on some kind of sliding scale. The more positive my reaction to something, the more confidence I gain in its “rightness”, vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it is a little more complicated than that. The feedback loop from experiment to result is not at all instantaneous. The results kind of creep up on you. It is easy to confuse instant gratification with a positive reaction. But there truly is such thing as too much of a good thing. It’s amazing how often self indulgence leads to heartache and pain. For example, overeating. I was amazed to learn that 72% of men in the U.S. over 20 years of age are overweight. Somewhere around 35% of all Americans are obese. There are all sorts of health issues associated with obesity.  I’m right there with them. I weigh about 20 pounds more than I should and losing 30 pounds wouldn’t hurt a bit. There are plenty of other examples of self indulgence leading to sorrow such as drug abuse but you understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that there is a certain point in everyone’s life where they are forced to consider the fact that they will someday die. The topic of their mortality becomes serious business and no longer makes their eyes glaze over. There is a sense of urgency to either correct a mistake, shore up their legacy or achieve some neglected aspiration. I associate it with your classic mid life crisis. Even the words mid life crisis are embarrassing. I instantly conjure up images of a sleazy balding man wearing shades while posing next to a Corvette or a Harley with a fake breasted bimbo in a bikini by his side. Who am I to judge, maybe that is just what the doctor ordered for some people. But please put me out of my misery if I ever become that guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, recognizing that your life is not all that you intended is not a bad thing, especially when it comes to your health. When we are young we feel invincible. So many of us abuse our bodies by eating too much, smoking, drinking alcohol to excess, or even drug abuse. I have been guilty of them all at one point or another, except drug abuse, unless you count cigarettes. Tack on working from dusk to dawn staring at a computer screen 16 hours a day for several years and it leads to potential ruin. Most of the time we are aware of our sins but feel like we have plenty of time to right the wrongs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what the long term effects of all of this abuse might be. I spent years abusing my body and still do to a lesser extent. I smoked Camels like a freight train for 15 years. I ate to excess with no concern for what I was stuffing in my face other than how it tasted. I washed it all down with either Mountain Dew or Miller Genuine Draft. I don’t think I drank a cup of water for years on end. It wasn’t until my late thirties that I finally came to my senses. Was it too late? How much irreparable damage have I done to myself? I find that lately I am much more aware of the ailments of older people. It is finally hitting home that the aches and pains that “old people” mutter about are someday going to be my aches and pains. It has not escaped my attention that some people suffer more than others in old age. I have many relatives that have serious ailments that are more than likely the result of hard living such as smoking, drinking, lack of sleep from late nights or over work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day while at the gym, there was an old man that had accidentally shit all over himself in the locker room. He was mortified with shame and frustration. I felt so bad for him. I couldn’t help but wonder if that would someday be me standing there with feces running down my leg as some young kid looked on with useless pitying eyes. An evil place in my mind wants to put all the blame on the old man. Surely he waited too long to drag himself to a gym. Surely there were all sorts of glaring signs that he ignored on his way to McDonalds for a double or triple cheeseburger. Surely nothing like that could ever happen to me. Then I remember how many triple cheeseburgers I have consumed in my life and how winded I get walking up stairs. But even scarier, maybe that is just a fact of life at a certain age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only have faith that it isn’t too late. Maybe if I concentrate on my health from now on, I can be one of those old men that doesn’t spend his last days confused and in pain while sitting in a rocker at some rest home. Life is meant to be experienced. It was not meant to be tolerated or suffered through. There are so many things that I wish I had figured out earlier. I have spent too much time working, too much time on my ass in front of a computer, too much of my life cultivating the wrong kinds of relationships. I’ve sought out people who were compatible to my goals. It might not have been as bad if those goals weren’t centered entirely on making money. In retrospect, I wish I had shaped my goals so that I could spend more time with the people I loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it takes this realization that we’re closer to the day we’re going to die than the day we were born for most of us. But if it takes a mid life crisis to jar us out of our self abusive lifestyles than I am all for them.  I think I’ll leave the Corvettes and bimbos to someone else but otherwise sign me up. In fact, I wish there was a way to bring them on sooner. Life isn’t nearly over at forty. With a little luck, there is still plenty of time to make all sorts of new mistakes that we won’t mind forgetting at eighty. That is if we are healthy enough to pull ourselves out of the rocker long enough to make them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Virtual Relationships Digitizing our Souls?</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/05/are-virtual-relationships-digitizing-our-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2012/05/are-virtual-relationships-digitizing-our-souls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The line of demarcation between our physical and internet lives is continually blurring. Many of our activities are obviously shifting to the latter, especially when it comes to communication and entertainment. Music, video, written text, and personal communication are already more prevalent on the web. Before you know it everything that you can’t get directly from the Internet will get dropped shipped to the home you never need to leave. I’ve even read about machines that can print three dimensional objects. Can you imagine ordering an end table from the Internet and then printing it from scratch directly in your home? It almost sounds like the Starship Enterprise teleporter, but I’m getting side tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I consider this, it makes me a little sad. It seems to me that we might be digitizing our souls along with music, videos and books.  But is it true? I can see traces of the lizard brain in that statement. After all, isn’t the Internet just a new medium for the same old stuff we’ve had forever? What makes me hesitate the most is when virtual connections replace physical ones. People are able to leave home and still stay in contact with friends and family. What is the cost? I don’t think there is currently a sufficient alternative to hugs and kisses. On the other hand, how many people do we now connect with daily that at best would have received an occasional letter in the past? In person is just better than a digital representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume that you have the following two choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have a remote relationship with as many people as you want. That means all of the social networks, any remote communications method including audio, video and messages. But you can’t breathe the same air with any of them. It means that you can’t physically touch any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can live in close proximity to five people that you love most in the world. However, you can have no relationship with any of the other people you’ve met in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>