<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>/categories/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to find good ideas</title>
      <link>/2021/02/good-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/02/good-ideas/</guid>
      <description>For several years, I wrote articles for this blog regularly. I never had a particular subject that I focused on. I never considered writing as something serious. I just wanted to be a better writer, and the best way to learn to write is to write.
What I actually learned is that I enjoy writing and dread it at the same time. I always got stuck on what to write. What do I have to say that is worth reading?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gluttonous Amount of Music</title>
      <link>/2019/01/gluttony-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/gluttony-music/</guid>
      <description>Music has become so ubiquitous that it has mostly lost it&amp;rsquo;s luster. Gone are the days when your music collection defined you as a person. Gone are the days when listening to music was an actual past time. Music is now a commodity. It is the noise that acts as the sound track for our lives. This is hardly even debatable at this point. I know that there are still insurgent music listeners out there, little pockets of resistance who probably sit around their record players soaking in the ambiance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I consume the Internet</title>
      <link>/2016/06/how-i-consume-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/how-i-consume-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>I am an information junkie. I go from one obsession to the next. The Internet deals me out a constant supply of articles, images, music and video on any and every subject I can imagine. It is very easy to get sucked in. If I&amp;rsquo;m not careful I will find myself reading about some obscure religious rite or the mating habits of deep sea creatures or Neuromancer fan fiction. Every subject is represented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Good People Online</title>
      <link>/2016/04/meet-good-people-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/meet-good-people-online/</guid>
      <description>I think that it’s possible to meet good people online without feeling like a creep and with very little risk. I think that the key to making friends online is by spending time with them offline. Conventional knowledge tells us that meeting people in person that we met on the Internet is a bad idea and potentially dangerous. I believe that I know how to solve that problem. Below are my ideas for using the Internet to safely meet people who are worth friendship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Meet People</title>
      <link>/2016/03/how-we-meet-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/how-we-meet-people/</guid>
      <description>Did Facebook do us a favor? It’s been said that social media websites, like Facebook, are ruining social interactions. I have always been of the opinion that these websites make it easy to know enough about your friends so that you never need to speak to them again. Usually, when I see a friend we discuss what happened since we saw each other last. That is hardly necessary when you are kept informed in real time of their day to day experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan to Succeed</title>
      <link>/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>Much of the time, we set ourselves up for failure. We set goals in order to please someone else. We plan for things that we aren’t ready to tackle. We try to do too much. These are recipes for failure. If you are going to set goals, make sure that they are achievable. Spend some time figuring out what you need to do. Determine what success looks like and make plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of being a Parent</title>
      <link>/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/11/the-purpose-of-being-a-parent/</guid>
      <description>When I was seventeen my father confessed, “Hey, I’ve never done this before. We are practicing on you.”. I think every parent on earth feels that way. We really have no idea what we are doing. Most of us are dealing with issues as they come by the seat of our pants. Even worse, the rules keep changing. And it doesn’t really matter how much experience or how many kids you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Teach Kids to Learn</title>
      <link>/2015/04/how-to-teach-kids-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/how-to-teach-kids-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Kids naturally learn. It’s what they do. In the dictionary it should describe children as “Small humans who obtain knowledge at dizzying speeds with the express intent of driving their parents insane”.
As parents, our concern is what they are learning from whom. Our hope is that they are being influenced by parents, teachers, and coaches etc. The truth is that they are primarily influenced by video games, YouTube videos and their friends, mostly their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Issues</title>
      <link>/2013/05/communication-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/communication-issues/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever known someone so well that you could complete their sentences? With some people there is hardly a need for verbal communication at all. Half the time, my wife knows what I’m feeling better than I do based solely on my posture and facial expressions. Our biggest communication issues come from the fact that she knows me too well. She likes to anticipate what I’m going to say. Often she will ignore what I actually say and instead answer the question I should have asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whining, Crying and Belly Aching</title>
      <link>/2013/03/whining-crying-and-belly-aching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/whining-crying-and-belly-aching/</guid>
      <description>Is there anything worse than a whining, sniffling, belly aching kid? I think not. Sometimes, It seems like it’s all my kids do. We hear such long suffering complaints as “Vegetables are gross, WAH”, or “I don’t want to do my chores, WAH, WAH”. And my personal favorite, “Why me?, WAH, WAH, WAH”. It seems to go on and on forever. It’s enough to drive a person crazy. It’s no consolation but my kids are not alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ball and Chain of Experience</title>
      <link>/2013/02/the-ball-and-chain-of-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/the-ball-and-chain-of-experience/</guid>
      <description>Children are unburdened by the ball and chain of experience. They typically see the world for what it is and it isn’t nearly as complicated as we adults seem to think. For example, my youngest son is almost four years old, he has a mind like a trap. He has very concrete expectations for life. He wants to eat when he is hungry and drink when thirsty. Mostly, he wants to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it possible to sell sound?</title>
      <link>/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/is-it-possible-to-sell-sound/</guid>
      <description>The concept of property can get complicated. We have plenty of laws regulating it. In fact, the idea of private property is at the heart of our way of living. It seems fair that if you work hard creating something, then you should own it. That isn’t always possible, and some things cannot be owned at all. Or at the very least, it would be silly to consider owning them, for example a cloud, rain or air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of Music Appreciation</title>
      <link>/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/the-decline-of-music-appreciation/</guid>
      <description>When I was young, the music that I was allowed to listen to was strictly limited by my parents. Any music purchases must first go through an approval process. The cover art was the first obstacle. My mother would look over the tape cover with a suspicious eye. Anything with pictures of demons, drugs, or violence was out. Anything that might otherwise suggest the devil’s handiwork would quickly get put back on the shelf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Kids Spend Too Much Time Inside?</title>
      <link>/2012/08/do-kids-spend-too-much-time-inside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/do-kids-spend-too-much-time-inside/</guid>
      <description>We ate dinner at seven o’clock. We ate dinner together as a family, at the table, mom’s rules. My spot was at the end of the table directly in front of a wall heater, a prized location in the winter. I sat to the right of my brother Pete and across from mom. This was not some somber formal dining ritual. This was our daily family reunion after a busy day of school or play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliophiles Anonymous</title>
      <link>/2012/08/bibliophiles_anonymous/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/bibliophiles_anonymous/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Erik and I am a bibliophile. I have a serious reading problem. I have read countless books, both fiction and nonfiction. I read blogs, news articles, wikipedia entries and comics. I read product reviews on shopping websites. I read the biographies of people I admire or want to emulate. I read about music and on other topics that I desire improved skills. I can easily lose a full day when I run across something new and interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s about time for a mid life crisis</title>
      <link>/2012/07/its-about-time-for-a-mid-life-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/its-about-time-for-a-mid-life-crisis/</guid>
      <description>I’m facing another one of those age milestones in a couple of weeks. I turn 39 next month. This will be the last year of my 30’s. The average lifespan of a male in the United States is about 75 years, but that increases a little bit nearly every year. So I am probably somewhere around halfway finished. I’m still young, relatively speaking. I’ve already experienced so much that I can’t remember it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Virtual Relationships Digitizing our Souls?</title>
      <link>/2012/05/are-virtual-relationships-digitizing-our-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/are-virtual-relationships-digitizing-our-souls/</guid>
      <description>The line of demarcation between our physical and internet lives is continually blurring. Many of our activities are obviously shifting to the latter, especially when it comes to communication and entertainment. Music, video, written text, and personal communication are already more prevalent on the web. Before you know it everything that you can’t get directly from the Internet will get dropped shipped to the home you never need to leave. I’ve even read about machines that can print three dimensional objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do people bother spending time with you?</title>
      <link>/2012/05/why-do-people-bother-spending-time-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/why-do-people-bother-spending-time-with-you/</guid>
      <description>While reading a blog post about passive income streams, I was presented with the following question: Why do people bother spending time with you? I had to stop and think about this for a little bit. The point of the question is to identify the value that you already bring people. I realize that I don’t really know why people spend time with me. If I think about it, not too many people actually do spend time with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socialized Digital Product Development</title>
      <link>/2012/05/socialized-digital-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/socialized-digital-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Digital products have a serious flaw, they are infinitely reproducible. Copies can be created in moments at no expense. These copies can be shared indiscriminately. Technology has simplified the process of creating music, books, video, software and just about any product that can be digitized. It is possible for nearly anyone to be an author, musician, director, composer, software developer to name a few. Everything you need to know is freely available on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Voices in My Head</title>
      <link>/2012/05/the-voices-in-my-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/the-voices-in-my-head/</guid>
      <description>Is it just me or does everyone hear a thousand chaotic voices muttering in their head all of the time? The voices in my head mostly judge my every move and offer up opinions on the people around me. The opinions vary as do their insistence on being heard. They speak of the feelings and suspicions they have for everyone in my life or in my near vicinity. Neither friends, family or strangers are off limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up in the air</title>
      <link>/2011/10/up-in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/up-in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>For as long as I’ve known Ron Philips, he has always been obsessed with airplanes. It was as if he belonged up in the air. His office was decorated with pictures of them. He had model airplanes on his desk. He played flight simulator games in his spare time. I wasn’t the least bit surprised when I learned that he had begun the process of becoming a pilot. You could see that look in his eyes when he would talk about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youthful Creativity</title>
      <link>/2011/08/youthful-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/youthful-creativity/</guid>
      <description>The earliest act of creativity that I can remember came in the form of a comic book. I was by no means a talented artist. The characters I created were the stereotypical products of an eight year old mind. For example my villain was big, bald and ugly. I dubbed him Butch Meaney. It’s a little disconcerting how much I now resemble my early ideal of a bad guy.
My parents, aunts and uncles have ribbed me for that character ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta book Reviews</title>
      <link>/2011/05/metabook-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/metabook-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Is there such a thing as a book review that sticks to the facts? I’m sick of reading opinionated reviews that focus on special circumstances. Satisfaction with what we read depends upon our motives. Our current situation and mood dictates our ability to enjoy anything that we do. Many book reviews do nothing more than recommend or discourage reading a particular title with very little reasoning. Half the time owners of bad reviews openly admit to not even finishing the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middle Class Rock Stars</title>
      <link>/2011/04/middle-class-rock-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/middle-class-rock-stars/</guid>
      <description>How many of you would make a donation to my personal bank account in exchange for my behaving in a manner that amused, entertained or was otherwise interesting? I could just behave erratically by doing or saying things inappropriate to my surroundings. We could even take the show on the road, I could travel around just being eccentric. Of course you would all need to pay for this. I, off course, would record each moment and make it available to subscribers for their vicarious living pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wow as it turns out I’m a terrorist</title>
      <link>/2009/05/wow-as-it-turns-out-im-a-terrorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/wow-as-it-turns-out-im-a-terrorist/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much spent my whole day trying to get subversion, ahnk, tortoisesvn and visual studio updated. I also began working on a new dialog to Adding Attachments that are not scanned. I’ve also decided that I need to create a user control that rolls up all the attachment functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel Vision, cold sweats and swing sets</title>
      <link>/2009/03/tunnel-vision-cold-sweats-and-swing-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/tunnel-vision-cold-sweats-and-swing-sets/</guid>
      <description>The drive to work this morning seemed to take forever. I felt like (and honestly still do) I was on the verge of going insane pretty much the entire day. I regretted going to work almost as soon as I got there. I promised dana yesterday that I would finish the search code by tomorrow so I set about getting it done. I finally fixed the dropdown list that for the tables in the sort area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
