<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to beat burnout</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2017/02/how-to-beat-burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2017/02/how-to-beat-burnout/</guid>
      <description>For the past few months, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt like writing. I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt like working on anything really. It has been impossible to motivate myself. The resistence has kicked my ass. I&amp;rsquo;ve been burned out. I actually started writing this post in July and put it down until now. Why did I allow this to happen? There are several reasons, none of them good.
What causes burnout? Burnout is a form of depression caused by stress due to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I consume the Internet</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/06/29/how-i-consume-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/06/29/how-i-consume-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>I am an information junkie. I go from one obsession to the next. The Internet deals me out a constant supply of articles, images, music and video on any and every subject I can imagine. It is very easy to get sucked in. If I&amp;rsquo;m not careful I will find myself reading about some obscure religious rite or the mating habits of deep sea creatures or Neuromancer fan fiction. Every subject is represented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan to Succeed</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>Much of the time, we set ourselves up for failure. We set goals in order to please someone else. We plan for things that we aren’t ready to tackle. We try to do too much. These are recipes for failure. If you are going to set goals, make sure that they are achievable. Spend some time figuring out what you need to do. Determine what success looks like and make plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Goals</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/25/how-to-use-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/25/how-to-use-goals/</guid>
      <description>Every year in January a horde of people line up at the gym for that magical workout that will change their lives forever. They make grandiose promises of losing 50 pounds, giving up sugar, or quitting smoking. Of course by the 2nd week of January the gym is a ghost town, candy bar sales are through the roof and that pack of cigarettes became two. Why is it so hard to do what we know needs to be done?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals and Plans for 2016</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/03/goals-and-plans-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/03/goals-and-plans-2016/</guid>
      <description>When it came time to review how things went in 2015, I had a hard time. I had nothing to work with because I did not set any goals and plans at the beginning of the year. The only valuable thing I was able to do was list out the areas where I did not do so well. This year will be different. I have set a number of goals and plans for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year in Review for 2015</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/12/30/2015-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/12/30/2015-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Year in Review summary In an effort to improve my life, I am publishing a year in review for 2015. Since I didn’t set any goals last year, it is a bit hard to grade my progress. So, before the year is over, I intend to set a few goals on what I want to improve next year. But first, I think it would help to summarize how i think things went in 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Things Done – GTD</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Lists are how we track what we need to do but this alone is not enough. Despite an abundance of technology available to help us keep track of tasks, many of us still keep these lists in our heads. We do this for a variety of reasons. They all have a common root. We don’t trust our system. We don’t actually believe that the list is the full list. We know that things have either been forgotten to be put on the list or were not important enough to track.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>