<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goals on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/tags/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goals on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erikvancraddock.com/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Goals</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/how-to-use-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/how-to-use-goals/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Every year in January a horde of people line up at the gym for that magical workout that will change their lives forever. They make grandiose promises of losing 50 pounds, giving up sugar, or quitting smoking. Of course by the 2nd week of January the gym is a ghost town, candy bar sales are through the roof and that pack of cigarettes became two. Why is it so hard to do what we know needs to be done? It’s not like it’s someone else’s problem that we are being asked to care about. In fact, typically people are much better at doing the work that is important to someone else, such as their boss.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The problem is a lack of planning. If you don’t plan your life, someone will plan it for you, more than likely your boss. Without a plan, all you can do is fumble around in the dark dealing with issues as they occur. It is virtually impossible to accomplish anything substantial without a certain amount of organization. But to keep track of what you need to do, you must know what you need to do. You must have a goal. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-goals-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;A goal is a desired result. It’s a mission. It is a dream. When you look to the future and imagine how things could be, that is a goal. It doesn’t matter if that is for tomorrow, later this year or sometime before you die. Goals are how we plan for the future. To me, it makes sense to list goals into three different groups: Long Term, Yearly and Quarterly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term Goals&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;are used for direction. They serve as a compass for everything we plan to do. These are the list of outcomes that we hope to achieve someday. They don’t have to be specific but they should be measurable. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;There needs to be some solid definition, so that you know when you are done. For example, if the goal is to be healthy, how will you know when you are successful? Your definition for healthy will change over time. Mine changes every morning right before it is time to head to the gym. That is when I feel so healthy that the gym seems unnecessary. Don’t set “healthy” as your goal. It is better to set a certain weight, or some other attribute like six pack abs. Then, there will be no question as to whether you met the goal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;A long term goal should be hard but achievable. It should act as a guide for all of your yearly and quarterly goals. It should not be a stepping stone to something bigger. The bigger goal itself is your long term goal. I break mine up into five different categories: Health, Family, Professional, Personal and Financial.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearly Goals&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;are the major achievements that you want to accomplish this year. Each of them should bring you closer to fulfilling a long term goal. Bonus points for the yearly goal that counts towards multiple long term goals. If you find yourself planning something that is unrelated to a long term goal, you know there is a problem. Where is the disconnect? Did you not fully identify your long term goals? Does it make sense to do this work?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Be careful not to bite off more than you can chew. It is better to keep your load manageable, especially at first. It is much easier to give up, if you fall hopelessly behind. That is less likely to happen if you start off small. In another post, I will describe the mechanism I use for changing goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;On the other hand, don’t be so easy on yourself that there is no challenge. Achieving all of your goals in the first months of the year defeats the purpose. There will always be pressing things to do. If you don’t have any goals you will have no viable way of prioritizing what you do. You will essentially be back to dealing with issues as they occur. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quarterly Goals&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;are the ones that are in the crosshairs. These are goals in which we can identify specifics. If a long term goal is a dream and a yearly goal is a mission then a quarterly goal is a project. You should have a pretty clear idea of how you will accomplish a quarterly goal. It is no longer a dream. It is now simply work that needs to be done.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;For example, if your long term goal is to major in a specific study in college, you may decide to take certain classes your first year. But each semester you actually enroll in those classes. You then know exactly when to attend class and which books are required. This isn’t some pie in the sky fantasy. You have committed to taking these classes and there are consequences if you do not. To a freshman attending the first class of the semester, the idea of a degree may seem unreal or even impossible. But of course it isn’t, graduation will come one semester at a time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-in-conclusion-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;There is no shortage of techniques for keeping track of what you need to do. I use a process that is based off the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/25/how-to-get-things-done/&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done by David Allen&lt;/a&gt;. All of the planning in the world is a waste of time if you don’t have a clear idea of what you want to accomplish. It is easy to let your agenda be set by the people around you. It is easy to spend all of your time putting out fires. It might be better to let some things burn. Who knows, maybe a new hero is just waiting for the chance to champion that cause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The most insidious villain in my life is me. I constantly have new ideas that I let derail what I am currently working on. Writing down long term, yearly and quarterly goals reminds me of why I am doing what I am doing. I feel like I am fulfilling a purpose when I force myself to keep my projects based on my current goals. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Setting goals is not a one and done ordeal. Life is not static and neither are your goals. However, there is a balance. You shouldn’t change goals on a whim but they also shouldn’t be so set in stone that they no longer align with who you are. This is where a planning system comes in play. &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/02/plan-to-succeed/&#34;&gt;My next post will be the nuts and bolts of how to plan projects and manage goals.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals and Plans for 2016</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/goals-and-plans-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/goals-and-plans-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;When it came time to &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/12/30/2015-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;review how things went in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, I had a hard time. I had nothing to work with because I did not set any goals and plans at the beginning of the year. The only valuable thing I was able to do was list out the areas where I did not do so well. This year will be different. &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2016/01/24/how-to-use-goals/&#34;&gt;I have set a number of goals&lt;/a&gt; and plans for myself.  At the end of the year, I will be able to compare my goals and plans with what I actually achieved.  This time next year, I should be able to look back and see how I did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, I jotted down a few of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2015/12/30/2015-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;mistakes I made last year&lt;/a&gt;. I believe that I can avoid most of these by looking ahead and planning. One of the problems I had was allowing myself to get over extended. I started too many different major projects without completing them. I am going to remedy this by committing to fewer projects this coming year. I will also not allow myself to abandon a project so easily. I will only let myself change a goal once a quarter and only if there is a compelling reason. If I do decide to back out, I will write about it here. This will allow someone to call bullshit if it is not for a good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of what I do involves my family. When it came time to set goals and plans, there was no way to do it alone. Linda and I spent about two days writing down both long term goals and goals for the upcoming year. Some of them are personal but many can only be achieved together. We broke them up into a few different categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;As I get older and my body starts failing on me, I have become more interested in my health. I haven’t always taken care of myself properly. I have done much better in the last few years. In March, it will be 7 years since I quit smoking. That was a bad habit that had me trapped for nearly 20 years. I currently find myself in as good of shape as I’ve been since high school, but I’m still overweight by at least 15 pounds. At 5’11, I should weigh no more than 175 pounds and I am currently at 190.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-gym-and-keto-diet-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Gym and Keto Diet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I don’t want to only lose weight. I also want to gain muscle and feel good. I want to be generally healthy.  My sister and mother have been “encouraging” me to try the Keto diet. For the most part it has helped me lose weight. This time last year I weighed closer to 215. For those of you unfamiliar with the Keto diet, in a nutshell, it is a high fat, low carb, medium protein diet. My mother can explain it better than me. You can read her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ketogranny.diet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keto Granny blog to learn more&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-food-and-supplement-tracking-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Food and Supplement Tracking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Now, I did have a run in with gout that nearly killed me. No exaggeration, I was willing to have my foot amputated at one point. I can’t really blame the Keto diet for this for two reasons. First, I had just returned from a trip to Universal Studios where I probably walked more in a single day than I did for the whole year. Second, I wasn’t tracking what I ate very well. We all suspect that too much protein may have at least played a part. Unfortunately the keto diet is NOT high fat, high carb, high protein. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-style-text-decoration-underline-span-style-font-weight-400-this-year-i-plan-to-do-the-following-for-my-health-span-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;This year I plan to do the following for my health:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Continue the Keto Diet&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Track what I eat daily&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Weight training every weekday&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-family-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Family&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-vacation-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Vacation &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;For the last few years I have made an effort to take the family somewhere where we can have a good time and relax. I would prefer to go places where I can experience a different culture. I’m not a big fan of tourist attractions, especially amusement parks. We did go to Universal Studio this year as part of a company get together. It was fun but I ended up walking more than I should have.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we are planning on taking at least two trips, one as a family and the other with just Linda and I. The company I work for is headquartered near Ft Lauderdale, Florida. Our plan is to stay there for about a month after the boys get out of school. I will be working but we should have plenty of time to see things after hours, especially the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linda has an Aunt that lives in France. She has been after us to come visit for years. We keep saying that we will but due to one thing or another, we’ve never done it. This year we plan to change that. We hope to travel to Europe for a few weeks and visit Paris while we are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-children-goal-evaluations-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Children Goal Evaluations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Setting goals and plans for my future is great but it isn’t enough. I have two boys to think about as well. When it comes to them, it’s easy to focus only on finances and saving for college etc, but I think it is also important to teach them to set their own goals and plans. With that in mind, I spent a few hours with them, mainly the oldest, talking about goals and plans. We set goals for the year and listed a few things to try to do this month to hit those goals and plans. My plan is to sit down with them once a month to see how things are going.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-style-text-decoration-underline-span-style-font-weight-400-this-year-i-plan-to-do-the-following-for-my-family-span-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;This year I plan to do the following for my family:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Spend a month in Florida&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Take Linda to France&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Have monthly goal evaluations with the boys&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-professional-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Professional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-writing-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I don’t typically write about topics that have mass appeal. I don’t spend a lot of time marketing or doing any of the things that it takes to gain a large group of readers. However, every once in awhile I write something that attracts more visits than I am used to. It is hard not to get discouraged when that kind of web traffic isn’t consistent. When I get discouraged, I tend to stop writing. I have to remind myself of the reasons I write here in the first place. I want to be a better writer and I want to record my thoughts for one future reader, myself. The main reason I publish these posts is to be held accountable to any potential readers, who, in my mind, call my bluff every time I write a single line of bullshit. I lost sight of that for the better part of two years. This year, I intend to write at least 300 words every day. Most of it will probably end up on this blog.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-coding-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Coding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The technology that I use to do my job as a software developer is in constant flux. It seems like every other day there is a new programming language or javascript framework that I need to learn. In the last 6 months at work, I have written code involving the following technologies:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;C#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Sql Server&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;KnockoutJs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Jasmine&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Specflow&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Nunit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;NodeJs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;AngularJs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Mocha&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Karma&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;SinonJs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;GoLang&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;MongoDb&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, the only ones that I had used in the past for production quality code was C#, Sql Server and Nunit. However, I had used several of them for code that I wrote at home for fun. If I waited to learn a technology when I needed it for work, I would be lost most of the time and probably out of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to learn new technologies, I need projects to implement them with. I have a ton of different ideas for projects, but, as I have pointed out, I tend to start them and never finish. This year I am going to work on a specific largish project that I can create using emerging technology. That project will be an event management web application which I will write more about later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-family-business-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Family Business&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;We have decided for various reasons that we want to start a family business. The primary purpose of this business is to give both Linda and Drew a way of gaining practical experience. My job provides enough money to support us and it offers us great benefits like health insurance, life insurance and a retirement plan. However, if anything happened to me it would be difficult for Linda to continue our current standard of living. Also Drew intends to go to college when he graduates from high school, but the job market is competitive. Having practical work experience will give him an advantage. We have a few ideas of different businesses we might start, but we want to make sure it is a good fit for all of us. It needs to be something that we all can play a big part in. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-style-text-decoration-underline-span-style-font-weight-400-this-year-i-plan-to-do-the-following-professionally-span-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;This year I plan to do the following professionally:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Write at least 300 words a day&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Create an event planning application&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Start a family business&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-personal-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Personal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;I have a few different hobbies that help me avoid getting burned out. I have been playing the guitar since I was a boy and I like to play a video game every once in awhile. I think this has been good for me and I don’t plan to change anything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This biggest problem that I have personally is that I don’t spend a lot of time cultivating friendships. I have two good friends that I visit every once in awhile. We have made a few acquaintances since we have moved to Mustang, but no one that, for example, we would invite over to dinner. We plan to stay here for quite awhile so it makes sense for us to work on this. A friend or two with something in common with us would be great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I want to improve is my fluency in Spanish. I do speak Spanish a bit but I could definitely be better. Linda and I have talked about taking a class but I am not ready to commit to that this year. In the meantime, I will continue to have small conversations in Spanish with friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-style-text-decoration-underline-span-style-font-weight-400-this-year-i-plan-to-do-the-following-personally-span-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;This year I plan to do the following personally:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Work on my social life&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Improve my Spanish &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-font-weight-400-financial-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Financial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The older I get, the more I realize that money is something that I may need after a time when I’m no longer able to earn it at my current rate. This leads to all sorts of other realizations. Saving money has become more of a priority. It also means that I probably should only spend as necessary. It turns out that isn’t so easy. It is hard to know what you need when that decision is made in real time. We have not done a very good job of managing our money. So one of our biggest priorities this year is creating a budget. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to figure out more precisely what we spend our money on.  To accomplish this we need to categorize the way in which we currently spend. I suspect that once we figure out how much we spend on fast food and entertainment that we will be astonished. Once we understand our spending better, then we can create a budget. This will help us manage our money better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a good budget will make it easier to save money for retirement, but it will help in other ways as well. An issue we run into is having the funds to take care of unexpected expenses. These usually come in the form of home repairs, trouble with vehicles or sickness of some sort. It would also help to pay for not so unexpected expenses like replacing old appliances, furniture or vehicles. What we really need is some sort of maintenance plan. If we replaced expensive items on a regular basis then we may not ever need to repair something that we should have replaced but couldn’t afford to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-style-text-decoration-underline-span-style-font-weight-400-this-year-i-plan-to-do-the-following-for-my-finances-span-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;This year I plan to do the following for my finances:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Create and follow a budget&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Create and follow a maintenance plan&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;In the past when I have set goals and plans, I tried to challenge myself. I would essentially set myself up for failure. I have not done that this year. I should be able to accomplish these goals easily as long as I stay focused. I recognize that life tends to happen in unexpected ways. I also am aware of my own tendency to get bored with something and move on to something else. With this in mind, I have devised a procedure for allowing change to these goals. I will write about it in more detail later but essentially, I am only allowed to modify these goals once a quarter. Also, if I do modify a goal I must explain myself. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited about the upcoming year. I am hopeful that we can avoid some of the bad stuff that happened in 2015. I feel like I have a clear idea of what I want to do in the next year. Now I just need to get busy doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Things Done – GTD</title>
      <link>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikvancraddock.com/2013/07/an-overview-of-getting-things-done-lists/&#34;&gt;Lists are how we track what we need to do&lt;/a&gt; but this alone is not enough. Despite an abundance of technology available to help us keep track of tasks, many of us still keep these lists in our heads. We do this for a variety of reasons. They all have a common root. We don’t trust our system. We don’t actually believe that the list is the full list. We know that things have either been forgotten to be put on the list or were not important enough to track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we can’t trust our system, we do what comes natural. We attempt to remember. We deal with issues as they come. The squeaky wheel gets the grease. That is until there is another louder squeak. This inevitably leads to stress and poor performance. The true genius of GTD are the procedures that help us manage lists. The integrity of our lists are what make the system trustworthy. To achieve this GTD is broken up into five different categories, Collect, Process, Organize, Review and Do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Collect
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It is essential that every thought, idea, request or demand that you have or receive be collected in a place that can be reviewed later. It is not necessary that you act on these items immediately but don’t be in a situation where you are forced to remember them. Always have a notepad and pen, a mobile computer or a voice recorder with you at all times. If you fail to collect tasks as they come you will lose faith in your system. If you are relying on your memory anyway, you will stop bothering with the system.  All of your tasks and notes should be deposited into a central Inbox so that you can process them at a later time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Process
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Most of us have way more to do than we could ever keep track of in our brains. It doesn’t really help to have a huge lists of tasks stored elsewhere either. At some point we need to organize the tasks into sections so that they are easier to manage. Traditionally this is done only when we are at our wits end. We throw up our hands and say “I’ve got to get organized.” We then stack the papers that are strewn about into neat piles and throw away anything not immediately identifiable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With GTD this is a daily process. The instinct is to leave anything that we’re not ready to deal with in the inbox whether its an email or a physical piece of paper. Before you know it your inbox is unmanageable and the scenario above is triggered. With GTD this is how tasks get into our lists. Each task begins its life in the inbox. At least once a day, the inbox is emptied by either transferring its contents to a list, the trash or to be archived as reference material.  We accomplish this one task at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each task in the inbox item is put through a series of questions. It is very important to process one item at a time. An item should never be returned to the inbox. Don’t pick and choose which ones to process. Take them as they come. Processing starts with a question. Is the item actionable? Can something be done about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  No
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  If the answer is no, then there is one of three choices.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    If it is trash, throw it away.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    If the required action can not be taken until some time in the future, then add it to your calendar.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    Some things are purely valuable as information. This information might be handy in the future but there is no immediate action that needs to be taken. We file these away in a bookmark, reference folder or archive the email.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Yes
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  If there is action to be taken, then determine if it is a single task or a project. Add projects to your projects lists.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to determine the next action. What is the next thing to do to further or finish the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the next action will take less than 2 minutes then just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise it needs to be added to a list. Are you the best person to perform this task? If so add the task to your Next Actions list. Otherwise, delegate the task to the person that is. Add the task to your waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Organize
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Keeping everything in its proper place establishes an order that gives us faith in the system. Lists are the proper places for a task. New unprocessed items belong in the Inbox. The name to identify multistep tasks are stored in the Project list. Tasks that are ready to be worked on are stored in the Next Actions list. Unfinished tasks that have been delegated are kept in the Waiting list. Projects or tasks that you may want to do in the future are stored in the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tasks don’t neatly fit into any of these lists. Some tasks can not be accomplished until some other condition is met first. It might be that a project can not be started until some other project is completed. On the other hand some tasks can not begin until a certain date or time. For these types of projects we have two different tools to ensure that when the time comes we are ready. These tools are the tickler file and the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickler file is essentially a reminder to deal with a task. You will be reminded of this task either during your weekly review or by checking your calendar. Here is an example. If you are a musician and you might think of a clever new trick you want to use in your next video. Since you are currently focusing on recording the song, it is not the appropriate time to act on it. You are not exactly sure when you will begin working on the video. The answer is to make a note of the idea and add it to the tickler file for the music video project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another method of ensuring that nothing falls through the cracks is your calendar. Anything that needs to be done on a specific date or at a specific time should be entered onto your calendar. It is recommend to use an online calendar with a good reminder system. Some tasks can not be completed until a certain date. For example, the tickets for the concert that you want to attend may not go on sale until a date in the future. Add a reminder to your calendar to purchase tickets on the correct date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review
&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  One of the most import aspects of the GTD system is also the most overlooked. Spending the time to refresh your memory on everything you have is the best way to ensure that none of it slips between the cracks. A review of everything in your system should be accomplished at least once a week. Some things will never be addressed until you have a review. Your tickler file and Maybe / Someday lists in particular are dependant on the review process. If you fail to review your system at least once a week, you will find that you stop using the parts of the system which require it. Your weekly review should consist of five different tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Next Action List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Look over each task. How long has the task been in the Next Actions List? Do you actually intend to do it? Be honest. Sometimes we have good intentions but when push comes to shove, it just isn’t going to happen. If you are not going to do it, then trash it. Things change. Has something happened since you added the task to your next actions list that prevents or discourages you from doing this work. Maybe now is no longer the right time. If you intend to work on the project but not right now, move it to the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common reason for a task lingering on the Next Actions List is confusion over what the task actually is. Typically this happens when your task is actually a project. Ask yourself what the next action actually is and update the task accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Project List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The review process is the time to evaluate the status of each of your projects. How many tasks are left to be completed? How far along in the process are you? It is not until after the review process that you can be confident that a project is completed. As with the Next Action List review, this is the time to ask yourself the hard questions. If no progress has been made on a project since your last review, it may be time to either trash it or move it to the Maybe / Someday list.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Maybe / Someday List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Of all of our lists, the Maybe / Someday list is the most dependant on the review process. This is where we store the ideas that we don’t want to forget about. Many of the projects that we are working on now will have some kind of impact on our future projects. While reading our Someday list, it may become obvious that a current project could be tweaked to include a listed idea. Update your project list or next actions as necessary and remove it from the Maybe / Someday list.  It is also possible that one of our current projects may nullify the need of a listed project. In this case remove it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we have ideas that seem brilliant as we are having them. We may decide to put them on the back burner. Later on, we wonder what in the world we were thinking. We no longer have any interest in the project. These should obviously be deleted. On the other hand, when one project is completed it is time to begin another. Our Maybe / Someday list is the obvious place to look for more work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another benefit to the review process. During this period, you will almost surely have new ideas. One project will remind you of another project that you want to undertake at some point. Occasionally, an idea from one project combines with an idea from another. When this happens a new idea is born, one that you may have never thought of otherwise. Although, you must be careful not to let your list get too big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer your list of ideas, the less likely you will be to review them. When a project has spent too long in your Maybe / Someday list, it could be time to remove it. This is obviously a judgement call. At a certain point you need to be honest with yourself. If five years have gone by and you still haven’t planted that garden in the backyard, you might need to consider that you may never do it. The finality of removing an idea from your Maybe / Someday list can be hard. It will clear up time and effort for projects that you will actually work on. This is true even if it is only during the review cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Review the Waiting List
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Almost certainly at some point, you will find yourself waiting for someone to finish a task before you can move on or complete a project. You may have a varying amount of influence over that person. You may have direct authority over some people. You may be able to directly set their priorities. You may have no authority at all over others. Your options will range from a kind word of encouragement all the way to dropping the project. At the very least, you’re waiting list is a good place to keep yourself reminded of who is holding up progress.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Calendar / Tickler File
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  You’re calendar and tickler files are like your own personal crystal ball. You can get a pretty good idea of what your future holds by looking at what you have planned. The amount of progress that  you’ve made since your last review will help you determine what you can expect. It may be necessary to change an appointment or modify a deadline.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tickler file is essentially a reminder with no specific date, time or task association. Without the review process a tickler file is useless. It might make sense to check the tickler file every day to keep this information as a constant reminder. The tickler file must be checked at least once a week to retain its value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-8217-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s Next&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparation is a waste of time unless it is followed by the actual work. In a future article I will write about [using goals][1]. I will also offer some tips on actually doing the tasks that have been planned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>