<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goals on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</title>
    <link>/tags/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goals on ERIK.VAN.CRADDOCK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Goals</title>
      <link>/2016/01/how-to-use-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/how-to-use-goals/</guid>
      <description>Every year in January a horde of people line up at the gym for that magical workout that will change their lives forever. They make grandiose promises of losing 50 pounds, giving up sugar, or quitting smoking. Of course by the 2nd week of January the gym is a ghost town, candy bar sales are through the roof and that pack of cigarettes became two. Why is it so hard to do what we know needs to be done?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals and Plans for 2016</title>
      <link>/2016/01/goals-and-plans-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/goals-and-plans-2016/</guid>
      <description>When it came time to review how things went in 2015, I had a hard time. I had nothing to work with because I did not set any goals and plans at the beginning of the year. The only valuable thing I was able to do was list out the areas where I did not do so well. This year will be different. I have set a number of goals and plans for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Get Things Done – GTD</title>
      <link>/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/how-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Lists are how we track what we need to do but this alone is not enough. Despite an abundance of technology available to help us keep track of tasks, many of us still keep these lists in our heads. We do this for a variety of reasons. They all have a common root. We don’t trust our system. We don’t actually believe that the list is the full list. We know that things have either been forgotten to be put on the list or were not important enough to track.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
